<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>✍️ Rob&#039;s Notes</title>
      <link>https://robinsonraju.blog</link>
      <description>Last 10 notes on ✍️ Rob&#039;s Notes</description>
      <generator>Quartz -- quartz.jzhao.xyz</generator>
      <item>
    <title>The Acharnians by Aristophanes</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.blog/Book-Notes/Plays/Aristophanes---The-Acharnians</link>
    <guid>https://robinsonraju.blog/Book-Notes/Plays/Aristophanes---The-Acharnians</guid>
    <description> Play by Aristophanes It is in GB Volume 5. Newsletter post: People in the play: Dicaeopolis, Crier, Amphitheus, Ambassadors, Pseudo-Artabas, Theorus, Wife of Dicaeopolis, Daughter of Dicaeopolis, Cephisophon (servant of Euripides), Euripides, Lamachus, A Megarian, Two Young Girls (daughters of the Megarian), An Informer, A Boeotian, Nicarchus, Servant of Lamachus, A Farmer, A Groomsman, Messenger, Chorus of Acharnian Charcoal Burners The Acharnians - Readwise Highlights Metadata Author: Aristophanes Full Title: The Acharnians Category: articles URL: readwise.io/reader/document_raw_content/259210663 Highlights I pass the time complaining, yawning, stretching, I fidget, write, twitch hairs out, do my sums, Gaze fondly country-wards, longing for Peace, Loathing the town, sick for my village-home, (View Highlight) Am.</description>
    <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>2025-01-22 - Kao - No, I Don&#039;t Want to Hop on a Call</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-22---Kao---No,-I-Don't-Want-to-Hop-on-a-Call</link>
    <guid>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-22---Kao---No,-I-Don't-Want-to-Hop-on-a-Call</guid>
    <description>No, I Don’t Want to Hop on a Call - Readwise Highlights Metadata Author: Wes Kao Full Title: No, I Don’t Want to Hop on a Call Category: articles Summary: Wes Kao’s newsletter emphasizes ...</description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 15:37:26 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>2025-01-20 - Walters - What&#039;s Wrong With Retribution</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-20---Walters---What's-Wrong-With-Retribution</link>
    <guid>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-20---Walters---What's-Wrong-With-Retribution</guid>
    <description>What’s Wrong With Retribution? - Readwise Highlights Metadata Author: Holy Spirit Moments, with Fr. Kerry Walters Full Title: What’s Wrong With Retribution? Category: articles Summary: Retribution, often seen as revenge, is never morally justified and goes against Christian values.</description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 15:37:26 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>2025-01-21 - Smith - Your Memecoin Is Your Slush Fund</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-21---Smith---Your-Memecoin-Is-Your-Slush-Fund</link>
    <guid>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-21---Smith---Your-Memecoin-Is-Your-Slush-Fund</guid>
    <description>Your Memecoin Is Your Slush Fund - Readwise Highlights Metadata Author: Noah Smith Full Title: Your Memecoin Is Your Slush Fund Category: articles Summary: Donald Trump and Melania ...</description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 15:37:26 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>2025-01-21 - Zaides - 6 Secrets for Never Being Blocked Again</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-21---Zaides---6-Secrets-for-Never-Being-Blocked-Again</link>
    <guid>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-21---Zaides---6-Secrets-for-Never-Being-Blocked-Again</guid>
    <description>6 Secrets for Never Being Blocked Again - Readwise Highlights Metadata Author: Anton Zaides Full Title: 6 Secrets for Never Being Blocked Again Category: articles Summary: The article ...</description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 15:37:26 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>2025-01-21 - Anderberg - My Year With Dickens Bleak House</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-21---Anderberg---My-Year-With-Dickens-Bleak-House</link>
    <guid>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-21---Anderberg---My-Year-With-Dickens-Bleak-House</guid>
    <description>My Year With Dickens: Bleak House - Readwise Highlights Metadata Author: Jeremy Anderberg Full Title: My Year With Dickens: Bleak House Category: articles Summary: Jeremy Anderberg ...</description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 15:37:26 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>2025-01-08 - Jarow - How Meditation Deconstructs Your Mind</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-08---Jarow---How-Meditation-Deconstructs-Your-Mind</link>
    <guid>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-08---Jarow---How-Meditation-Deconstructs-Your-Mind</guid>
    <description>How Meditation Deconstructs Your Mind - Readwise Highlights Metadata Author: Oshan Jarow Full Title: How Meditation Deconstructs Your Mind Category: articles Summary: Meditation ...</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 19:45:38 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>2025-01-15 - Walters - Swearing on a Penis</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-15---Walters---Swearing-on-a-Penis</link>
    <guid>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-15---Walters---Swearing-on-a-Penis</guid>
    <description>Swearing on a Penis - Readwise Highlights Metadata Author: Kerry Walters Full Title: Swearing on a Penis Category: articles Summary: In ancient Hebrew culture, swearing an oath ...</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 19:45:38 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>2025-01-20 - Palihapitiya - What I Read This Week…</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-20---Palihapitiya---What-I-Read-This-Week%E2%80%A6</link>
    <guid>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-20---Palihapitiya---What-I-Read-This-Week%E2%80%A6</guid>
    <description>What I Read This Week… - Readwise Highlights Metadata Author: Chamath Palihapitiya Full Title: What I Read This Week… Category: articles Summary: President Trump is set to be inaugurated ...</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 19:45:38 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>2025-01-12 - Palihapitiya - What I Read This Week…</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-12---Palihapitiya---What-I-Read-This-Week%E2%80%A6</link>
    <guid>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-12---Palihapitiya---What-I-Read-This-Week%E2%80%A6</guid>
    <description>What I Read This Week… - Readwise Highlights Metadata Author: Chamath Palihapitiya Full Title: What I Read This Week… Category: articles Summary: The Federal Reserve is losing credibility ...</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 19:45:38 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>