<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>✍️ Rob&#039;s Notes</title>
      <link>https://robinsonraju.blog</link>
      <description>Last 10 notes on ✍️ Rob&#039;s Notes</description>
      <generator>Quartz -- quartz.jzhao.xyz</generator>
      <item>
    <title>2025-01-25 - Smith - Yes, Reshoring American Industry Is Possible</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-25---Smith---Yes,-Reshoring-American-Industry-Is-Possible</link>
    <guid>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-25---Smith---Yes,-Reshoring-American-Industry-Is-Possible</guid>
    <description>Yes, Reshoring American Industry Is Possible - Readwise Highlights Metadata Author: Noah Smith Full Title: Yes, Reshoring American Industry Is Possible Category: articles Summary: ...</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 22:22:21 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>2025-01-25 - Walters - Resisting Tyranny</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-25---Walters---Resisting-Tyranny</link>
    <guid>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-25---Walters---Resisting-Tyranny</guid>
    <description>Resisting Tyranny - Readwise Highlights Metadata Author: Kerry Walters Full Title: Resisting Tyranny Category: articles Summary: Kerry Walters reflects on how small acts of decency ...</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 22:22:21 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>2025-01-24 - Anderberg - What to Read Next 1968&#039;s Sci-Fi &amp; Fantasy Classics</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-24---Anderberg---What-to-Read-Next-1968's-Sci-Fi--and--Fantasy-Classics</link>
    <guid>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-24---Anderberg---What-to-Read-Next-1968's-Sci-Fi--and--Fantasy-Classics</guid>
    <description>What to Read Next: 1968’s Sci-Fi &amp; Fantasy Classics - Readwise Highlights Metadata Author: Jeremy Anderberg Full Title: What to Read Next: 1968’s Sci-Fi &amp; Fantasy Classics ...</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 06:41:05 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>The Knights by Aristophanes</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.blog/Book-Notes/Plays/Aristophanes---The-Knights</link>
    <guid>https://robinsonraju.blog/Book-Notes/Plays/Aristophanes---The-Knights</guid>
    <description> Play by Aristophanes It is in GB Volume 5. Newsletter post: www.readgreatbooks.info/p/great-books-ep-96-aristophanes-the People in the play: Demosthenes, Nicias, Sausage-Seller, Paphlagon, Demus, Chorus of Knights The Knights - Readwise Highlights Metadata Author: Aristophanes Full Title: The Knights Category: articles URL: readwise.io/reader/document_raw_content/263736038 Highlights ‘tis when men drink, they thrive, Grow wealthy, speed their business, win their suits, Make themselves happy, benefit their friends.</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>The Acharnians by Aristophanes</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.blog/Book-Notes/Plays/Aristophanes---The-Acharnians</link>
    <guid>https://robinsonraju.blog/Book-Notes/Plays/Aristophanes---The-Acharnians</guid>
    <description> Play by Aristophanes It is in GB Volume 5. Newsletter post: www.readgreatbooks.info/p/great-books-ep-95-aristophanes-the People in the play: Dicaeopolis, Crier, Amphitheus, Ambassadors, Pseudo-Artabas, Theorus, Wife of Dicaeopolis, Daughter of Dicaeopolis, Cephisophon (servant of Euripides), Euripides, Lamachus, A Megarian, Two Young Girls (daughters of the Megarian), An Informer, A Boeotian, Nicarchus, Servant of Lamachus, A Farmer, A Groomsman, Messenger, Chorus of Acharnian Charcoal Burners The Acharnians - Readwise Highlights Metadata Author: Aristophanes Full Title: The Acharnians Category: articles URL: readwise.io/reader/document_raw_content/259210663 Highlights I pass the time complaining, yawning, stretching, I fidget, write, twitch hairs out, do my sums, Gaze fondly country-wards, longing for Peace, Loathing the town, sick for my village-home, (View Highlight) Am.</description>
    <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>2025-01-23 - Walters - Announcing an Upcoming Series</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-23---Walters---Announcing-an-Upcoming-Series</link>
    <guid>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-23---Walters---Announcing-an-Upcoming-Series</guid>
    <description>Announcing an Upcoming Series - Readwise Highlights Metadata Author: Kerry Walters Full Title: Announcing an Upcoming Series Category: articles Summary: Jacob the Wayfarer URL: ...</description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:56:08 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>2025-01-22 - Kao - No, I Don&#039;t Want to Hop on a Call</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-22---Kao---No,-I-Don't-Want-to-Hop-on-a-Call</link>
    <guid>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-22---Kao---No,-I-Don't-Want-to-Hop-on-a-Call</guid>
    <description>No, I Don’t Want to Hop on a Call - Readwise Highlights Metadata Author: Wes Kao Full Title: No, I Don’t Want to Hop on a Call Category: articles Summary: Wes Kao’s newsletter emphasizes ...</description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 15:37:26 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>2025-01-20 - Walters - What&#039;s Wrong With Retribution</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-20---Walters---What's-Wrong-With-Retribution</link>
    <guid>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-20---Walters---What's-Wrong-With-Retribution</guid>
    <description>What’s Wrong With Retribution? - Readwise Highlights Metadata Author: Holy Spirit Moments, with Fr. Kerry Walters Full Title: What’s Wrong With Retribution? Category: articles Summary: Retribution, often seen as revenge, is never morally justified and goes against Christian values.</description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 15:37:26 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>2025-01-21 - Smith - Your Memecoin Is Your Slush Fund</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-21---Smith---Your-Memecoin-Is-Your-Slush-Fund</link>
    <guid>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-21---Smith---Your-Memecoin-Is-Your-Slush-Fund</guid>
    <description>Your Memecoin Is Your Slush Fund - Readwise Highlights Metadata Author: Noah Smith Full Title: Your Memecoin Is Your Slush Fund Category: articles Summary: Donald Trump and Melania ...</description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 15:37:26 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>2025-01-21 - Zaides - 6 Secrets for Never Being Blocked Again</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-21---Zaides---6-Secrets-for-Never-Being-Blocked-Again</link>
    <guid>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-21---Zaides---6-Secrets-for-Never-Being-Blocked-Again</guid>
    <description>6 Secrets for Never Being Blocked Again - Readwise Highlights Metadata Author: Anton Zaides Full Title: 6 Secrets for Never Being Blocked Again Category: articles Summary: The article ...</description>
    <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 15:37:26 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>