<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>✍️ Rob&#039;s Notes</title>
      <link>https://robinsonraju.blog</link>
      <description>Last 10 notes on ✍️ Rob&#039;s Notes</description>
      <generator>Quartz -- quartz.jzhao.xyz</generator>
      <item>
    <title>Kpaxs - Jeff Bezos&#039; Heuristic for Hiring</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Tweets/Kpaxs---Jeff-Bezos'-Heuristic-for-Hiring</link>
    <guid>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Tweets/Kpaxs---Jeff-Bezos'-Heuristic-for-Hiring</guid>
    <description>Jeff Bezos’ Heuristic for Hiring: Metadata Author: Kpaxs Full Title: Jeff Bezos’ Heuristic for Hiring: Category: tweets Summary: Jeff Bezos’ heuristic for hiring: URL: twitter.com/Kpaxs/status/1822278182189306163/photo/1 Highlights Jeff Bezos’ heuristic for hiring: (View Highlight) .</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 03:48:43 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Drew - I Just Finished Re-Reading Mastery by Robert Greene</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Tweets/Drew---I-Just-Finished-Re-Reading-Mastery-by-Robert-Greene</link>
    <guid>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Tweets/Drew---I-Just-Finished-Re-Reading-Mastery-by-Robert-Greene</guid>
    <description>I Just Finished Re-Reading Mastery by Robert Greene Metadata Author: Kieran Drew Full Title: I Just Finished Re-Reading Mastery by Robert Greene Category: tweets Summary: The author just finished re-reading Mastery by Robert Greene, praising it as one of the best books they’ve read.</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 03:48:43 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>2025-02-03 - Yochheim - This Is Barbara O&#039;Neill</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Tweets/2025-02-03---Yochheim---This-Is-Barbara-O'Neill</link>
    <guid>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Tweets/2025-02-03---Yochheim---This-Is-Barbara-O'Neill</guid>
    <description>This Is Barbara O’Neill - Readwise Highlights Metadata Author: Joey Yochheim Full Title: This Is Barbara O’Neill Category: tweets Summary: Barbara O’Neill is a holistic health expert who believes cancer is preventable through lifestyle changes.</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 03:48:43 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>2025-01-09 - Smith - 3 Years Ago, I Wrote a List of Generation-Defining Stats...</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Tweets/2025-01-09---Smith---3-Years-Ago,-I-Wrote-a-List-of-Generation-Defining-Stats...</link>
    <guid>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Tweets/2025-01-09---Smith---3-Years-Ago,-I-Wrote-a-List-of-Generation-Defining-Stats...</guid>
    <description>3 Years Ago, I Wrote a List of Generation-Defining Stats… - Readwise Highlights Metadata Author: Steph Smith Full Title: 3 Years Ago, I Wrote a List of Generation-Defining Stats… Category: tweets Summary: Three years ago, Steph Smith shared important stats about trends like fertility decline and tec...</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 03:48:43 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>2024-12-15 - Ferriss - 11 of My Favorite @Paulg Essays</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Tweets/2024-12-15---Ferriss---11-of-My-Favorite-@Paulg-Essays</link>
    <guid>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Tweets/2024-12-15---Ferriss---11-of-My-Favorite-@Paulg-Essays</guid>
    <description>11 of My Favorite @Paulg Essays: - Readwise Highlights Metadata Author: Tim Ferriss Full Title: 11 of My Favorite @Paulg Essays: Category: tweets Summary: Tim Ferriss shares 11 of his favorite essays by Paul Graham, highlighting their relevance and insights.</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 03:48:43 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>2024-12-09 - Karpathy - Of ~200 Books I&#039;ve Read, the Few That Stayed With...</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Tweets/2024-12-09---Karpathy---Of-~200-Books-I've-Read,-the-Few-That-Stayed-With...</link>
    <guid>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Tweets/2024-12-09---Karpathy---Of-~200-Books-I've-Read,-the-Few-That-Stayed-With...</guid>
    <description>Of ~200 Books I’ve Read, the Few That Stayed With… - Readwise Highlights Metadata Author: Andrej Karpathy Full Title: Of ~200 Books I’ve Read, the Few That Stayed With… Category: tweets Summary: Andrej Karpathy shares a list of memorable books he has read, highlighting their impactful themes and ide...</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 03:48:43 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Parrish - Morgan Housel Get Rich, Stay Rich</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Podcasts/Parrish---Morgan-Housel-Get-Rich,-Stay-Rich</link>
    <guid>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Podcasts/Parrish---Morgan-Housel-Get-Rich,-Stay-Rich</guid>
    <description>Morgan Housel: Get Rich, Stay Rich Metadata Author: The Knowledge Project with Shane Parrish Full Title: Morgan Housel: Get Rich, Stay Rich Category: podcasts URL: share.snipd.com/episode/5b454dc5-0f98-4726-810f-cbf1ef827d6f Highlights FOMO Avoid FOMO (fear of missing out) to build wealth.</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 03:48:43 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Google - EP197 SIEM (Decoupled or Not), and Security Data Lakes A Google SecOps Perspective</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Podcasts/Google---EP197-SIEM-(Decoupled-or-Not),-and-Security-Data-Lakes-A-Google-SecOps-Perspective</link>
    <guid>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Podcasts/Google---EP197-SIEM-(Decoupled-or-Not),-and-Security-Data-Lakes-A-Google-SecOps-Perspective</guid>
    <description>EP197 SIEM (Decoupled or Not), and Security Data Lakes: A Google SecOps Perspective Metadata Author: Cloud Security Podcast by Google Full Title: EP197 SIEM (Decoupled or Not), and Security Data Lakes: A Google SecOps Perspective Category: podcasts URL: share.snipd.com/episode/af74660d-1e0f-4861-a2f...</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 03:48:43 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Wright - Software Engineering at Google</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Books/Wright---Software-Engineering-at-Google</link>
    <guid>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Books/Wright---Software-Engineering-at-Google</guid>
    <description>Software Engineering at Google - Readwise Highlights Metadata Author: Titus Winters, Tom Manshreck, and Hyrum Wright Full Title: Software Engineering at Google Category: books Highlights The great thing about tech is that there is never only one way to do something.</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 03:48:43 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Wise - The Well-Trained Mind</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Books/Wise---The-Well-Trained-Mind</link>
    <guid>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Books/Wise---The-Well-Trained-Mind</guid>
    <description>The Well-Trained Mind Metadata Author: Susan Wise Bauer, Jessie Wise Full Title: The Well-Trained Mind Category: books Highlights The Well-Trained Mind is a parent’s guide to a do-it-yourself, academically rigorous, comprehensive education—a classical education.</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 03:48:43 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>