<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>✍️ Rob&#039;s Notes</title>
      <link>https://robinsonraju.blog</link>
      <description>Last 10 notes on ✍️ Rob&#039;s Notes</description>
      <generator>Quartz -- quartz.jzhao.xyz</generator>
      <item>
    <title>The Acharnians by Aristophanes</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.blog/Book-Notes/Plays/Aristophanes---The-Acharnians</link>
    <guid>https://robinsonraju.blog/Book-Notes/Plays/Aristophanes---The-Acharnians</guid>
    <description> Play by Aristophanes It is in GB Volume 5. Newsletter post: People in the play: Dicaeopolis, Crier, Amphitheus, Ambassadors, Pseudo-Artabas, Theorus, Wife of Dicaeopolis, Daughter of Dicaeopolis, Cephisophon (servant of Euripides), Euripides, Lamachus, A Megarian, Two Young Girls (daughters of the Megarian), An Informer, A Boeotian, Nicarchus, Servant of Lamachus, A Farmer, A Groomsman, Messenger, Chorus of Acharnian Charcoal Burners The Acharnians - Readwise Highlights Metadata Author: Aristophanes Full Title: The Acharnians Category: articles URL: readwise.io/reader/document_raw_content/259210663 Highlights I pass the time complaining, yawning, stretching, I fidget, write, twitch hairs out, do my sums, Gaze fondly country-wards, longing for Peace, Loathing the town, sick for my village-home, (View Highlight) Am.</description>
    <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>2025-01-18 - Smith - Why I&#039;m Long-Term Bullish on the Middle East</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-18---Smith---Why-I'm-Long-Term-Bullish-on-the-Middle-East</link>
    <guid>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-18---Smith---Why-I'm-Long-Term-Bullish-on-the-Middle-East</guid>
    <description>Why I’m Long-Term Bullish on the Middle East - Readwise Highlights Metadata Author: Noah Smith Full Title: Why I’m Long-Term Bullish on the Middle East Category: articles Summary: ...</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 15:44:54 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>2025-01-16 - Issa - The Art of Being Reflections on a Christmas Break With Family</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-16---Issa---The-Art-of-Being-Reflections-on-a-Christmas-Break-With-Family</link>
    <guid>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-16---Issa---The-Art-of-Being-Reflections-on-a-Christmas-Break-With-Family</guid>
    <description>The Art of Being: Reflections on a Christmas Break With Family - Readwise Highlights Metadata Author: Mo Issa Full Title: The Art of Being: Reflections on a Christmas Break With Family ...</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 15:44:54 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>2025-01-15 - Kao - How I Give High-Quality Feedback Quickly</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-15---Kao---How-I-Give-High-Quality-Feedback-Quickly</link>
    <guid>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-15---Kao---How-I-Give-High-Quality-Feedback-Quickly</guid>
    <description>How I Give High-Quality Feedback Quickly - Readwise Highlights Metadata Author: Wes Kao Full Title: How I Give High-Quality Feedback Quickly Category: articles Summary: Wes Kao ...</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 15:44:54 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>2025-01-15 - Smith - TikTok Is Just the Beginning</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-15---Smith---TikTok-Is-Just-the-Beginning</link>
    <guid>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-15---Smith---TikTok-Is-Just-the-Beginning</guid>
    <description>TikTok Is Just the Beginning - Readwise Highlights Metadata Author: Noah Smith Full Title: TikTok Is Just the Beginning Category: articles Summary: Congress passed a bill requiring ...</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 15:44:54 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>2025-01-14 - Anderberg - Discussion What Are Your Favorite Science Fiction  Fantasy Novels</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-14---Anderberg---Discussion-What-Are-Your-Favorite-Science-Fiction--Fantasy-Novels</link>
    <guid>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-14---Anderberg---Discussion-What-Are-Your-Favorite-Science-Fiction--Fantasy-Novels</guid>
    <description>Discussion: What Are Your Favorite Science Fiction / Fantasy Novels? - Readwise Highlights Metadata Author: Jeremy Anderberg Full Title: Discussion: What Are Your Favorite Science ...</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 15:44:54 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>2025-01-14 - Zaides - Being an Engineering Manager at Meta</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-14---Zaides---Being-an-Engineering-Manager-at-Meta</link>
    <guid>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-14---Zaides---Being-an-Engineering-Manager-at-Meta</guid>
    <description>Being an Engineering Manager at Meta - Readwise Highlights Metadata Author: Anton Zaides Full Title: Being an Engineering Manager at Meta Category: articles Summary: Gilad Naor ...</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 15:44:54 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>2025-01-12 - Qureshi - Principles</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-12---Qureshi---Principles</link>
    <guid>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-12---Qureshi---Principles</guid>
    <description>Principles - Readwise Highlights Metadata Author: Nabeel S. Qureshi Full Title: Principles Category: articles Summary: Nabeel S. Qureshi shares valuable life lessons in his open-sourced document, emphasizing that important insights often sound like clichés.</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 14:22:29 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>2025-01-06 - Altman - Reflections</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-06---Altman---Reflections</link>
    <guid>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-06---Altman---Reflections</guid>
    <description>Reflections - Readwise Highlights Metadata Author: Sam Altman Full Title: Reflections Category: articles Summary: Sam Altman reflects on the journey of OpenAI and the launch of ...</description>
    <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:45:26 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>2025-01-13 - Smith - Should Economists Read Marx</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-13---Smith---Should-Economists-Read-Marx</link>
    <guid>https://robinsonraju.blog/Readwise/Articles/2025-01-13---Smith---Should-Economists-Read-Marx</guid>
    <description>Should Economists Read Marx? - Readwise Highlights Metadata Author: Noah Smith Full Title: Should Economists Read Marx? Category: articles Summary: The debate revolves around ...</description>
    <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:45:26 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>