<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rob&#39;s Notes</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.info/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Rob&#39;s Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2020 Robinson Raju</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://robinsonraju.info/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>LinkedIn profiles, how to use them, how to market yourself, how to network</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/management/2014-10-19-linked-in-profiles-how-to-market-self/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2014 22:02:12 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/management/2014-10-19-linked-in-profiles-how-to-market-self/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/management/2014-10-19-linked-in-profiles-how-to-market-self/ -&lt;p&gt;In this post, we take a segway from discussions around Agile methodology and focus on something that is very important for everyone’s career – to have an online professional profile, something that someone can look at and find out about your career, capabilities and achievements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many sites where one can host a professional profile but LinkedIn is the most popular business oriented social networking service. With a huge database of over 120 million people, all of whom you can search and most of whom you can message within minutes, LinkedIn is far ahead in features and reach than other networking services. Employers and recruiters actively look at LinkedIn profiles either to find potential candidates that suit the role that they are looking for or to find out more about the person that they are interviewing. So it is very pertinent to look a little in-depth at what the site provides and how effectively it could be used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-does-linkedin-provide&#34;&gt;What does LinkedIn provide?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LinkedIn’s remarkable value is making our second and third degree networks visible, as well as the connecting paths, thereby revealing the networks of people we know. Thus it helps in finding the right people using our connections. Here is a short summary of what LinkedIn provides:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provides an ability to find and identify the right people through 2nd and 3rd degree networks and connecting paths.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gives a platform to discover information that can help in a conversation, meeting or network event by reading the other person’s LinkedIn Profile beforehand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Helps in maintaining relationships with your network via personal messages, sharing ideas in Discussions and helping people out in Answers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Helps in getting Recommendations which are visible to anyone, but in particular to the people who are important in your job or for your goals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provides a platform to receive introductions and referrals to the people who matter to you via the introduction tool or a regular email.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Helps in discovering the relationships between people by looking at mutual connections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raises your visibility, reputation, personal brand, and company brand via your LinkedIn Profile, your contributions in Answers and Discussions and on the web via search engines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Helps in “word of mouth publicity” by receiving Recommendations, or from people recommending you in Discussions or mentioning you as the expert in Answers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The platform sends notifications via Network Updates when someone changes jobs. This might be a good reminder to reconnect with them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Helps in picking up trends in the marketplace via Discussions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assists in finding professional organizations to join, both online and offline, via Groups, and via people’s Profiles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;linkedin-profile&#34;&gt;LinkedIn profile:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your LinkedIn profile is the page that people go to when they want to find out information about you. It means that many times, it is the first professional impression you make on someone. You need to make your profile relevant and highlight specific portions so that it increases your visibility, supports your personal branding and reputation.A good Profile increases your visibility on LinkedIn and also on the web. Google and other search engines index the information from your Public Profile on LinkedIn. Since LinkedIn has a high Page Ranking in Google the Profiles will also appear high in search results. If someone is not looking for you, but looking for a person with skills that you are expert at; a great LinkedIn profile will channel them to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-market-yourself-by-creating-a-great-linkedin-profile&#34;&gt;How to market yourself by creating a great LinkedIn profile&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are 5 portions of your profile that you need to focus on to create an attractive LinkedIn profile:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your “Teaser”: Picture, Name, Professional Headline, Location and Industry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Short Overview: Current &amp;amp; Past experience, Education, Recommendations, Connections, Websites, Twitter, and Public Profile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Core: Summary and Specialties.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Specifics: Experience, Education, and Sections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Details: Additional Information, Personal Information, and Contact Settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Teaser&lt;/strong&gt;: Make sure that you provide a professional picture. Since there is not much space for photo, just focus on have a good photo of your face with the upper torso. Make sure that you provide a name that people can recognize you with. Do not give nicknames. Give a professional headline that tells something about your area of expertise. By default it is the current job title, but it is better to change it. Provide a location that indicates where you are working out of. Also provide the industry where you have your expertise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Short Overview&lt;/strong&gt;: It is important to use “Current &amp;amp; Past Experience” section to help being found by former colleagues or by people searching for skills and roles that you have performed. Education is an important section where you could get found by people searching for alumni from specific schools or to connect with your former class or school mates. Recommendation is another powerful feature that you could use. Make it a habit to ask for recommendations, and provide recommendations for other people. Make it a point to have connections who know you or can recommend your skills. If you cannot have one of your connections give you introduction to another, it is not of much use. There is also a section that asks you about your websites and you can list up to 3 websites. Instead of the standard “Company website” or “Personal website”, choose “Other”and then write some compelling text. If you have a Twitter account, list it so that people can follow you. At this moment this feature exists on LinkedIn also. But if you are actively posting on Twitter, it makes sense to post Twitter link. Lastly, you must take care to see that you have a public profile URL that is not the standard undecipherable alpha-numeric string but a URL with your name it in. This is good for SEO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. The Core&lt;/strong&gt;: “Summary” is the place where you convey a lot of information about you in a very small area. It should not be too long or too short. The recommendation from Jon Vermeiren’s book “How to really use LinkedIn” is to use three blocks of text: information about the organization, some professional information about yourself, and some personal information. “Specialties” is the place to share the skills and knowledge you have accumulated in all your past jobs. This is the place to explain your expertise. You can put your certifications, knowledge of tools and programming languages, jargons, acronyms that are relevant to your industry here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. The Specifics&lt;/strong&gt;: The “Summary and Specialties” section has limited room. The Specifics section is where you describe in as much detail, your experience and education – including courses, projects, certifications, patents, organizations, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. The Details&lt;/strong&gt;: In this section you provide additional information related to your interests, groups that you belong to, honors and awards, personal information to reach you, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above steps need to be followed through on a periodic basis to ensure that the information does not get stale. Keeping your LinkedIn profile up to date is the best strategy to market yourself and present your best to the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-expand-your-network&#34;&gt;How to expand your network:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In their book &lt;strong&gt;“How to really use LinkedIn”&lt;/strong&gt;, Vermeiren &amp;amp; Verdonck give 4 phases to building a foundation of your LinkedIn network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phase 1: Upload your email contacts and connect with the ones already on LinkedIn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phase 2: Find current and former colleagues and classmates and connect with them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phase 3: Discover people you may know and connect with the ones you actually know.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phase 4: Promote your LinkedIn Profile with a LinkedIn Email Signature and LinkedIn Profile Badge for your website and blog.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have done these, you have a solid foundation on which you can build your network. It is said that there are just 6 degrees of separation between everyone in the world and since LinkedIn gives you 3 degrees of connections, you can leverage it to reach any contact that you have in mind. The next logical step is to join Groups that are relevant to your area or work or expertise. Groups are a place to help others and be helped by them, to apply the Golden Triangle of Networking and to raise your Know, Like, and Trust factor. Once you participate in some groups and gain trust and establish your brand as someone who can answer questions on specific topics, you can start groups or become Group manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of other strategies to network and improve your sphere of influence. As you use LinkedIn more, you would be able to effectively find more of your ‘target audience’ by doing specific searches, setting up alerts, browsing the connections of people in your network, browsing through LinkedIn recommendations of who to connect to, which groups to join, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] Vermeiren, J., &amp;amp; Verdonck, B. (2011). How to really use LinkedIn, second edition (2nd ed.). Stamford, Conn.: Hannacroix Creek Books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2] Elad, J. (2011). LinkedIn for dummies (2nd ed.). Hoboken, N.J.: Wiley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[3] Brown, K. (2014). Mastering LinkedIn (1st ed.). Bookboon.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[4] Kievman, N. (2007). LinkedIn Quick Start Guide (1st ed.). LinkedStrategies.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/management/2014-10-19-linked-in-profiles-how-to-market-self/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Agile tasks lists, what does “done” mean in Agile?</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/management/2014-10-07-agile-task-list-what-does-done-mean/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 21:10:13 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/management/2014-10-07-agile-task-list-what-does-done-mean/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/management/2014-10-07-agile-task-list-what-does-done-mean/ -&lt;p&gt;This is the fourth post in this series of “Introduction to Agile methodology”. The topic of this blog is “Agile task lists, what does “done” mean in Agile?”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teams change their methodology to agile with the lofty goal of getting great results but often fail. A primary reason for failure is the ambiguity around the definition of “done”. When what needs to be done in a User story is not clearly defined, what gets done does not fully meet end user requirements or even if it meets, might create technical debt. During the sprint planning, when the team discusses about the user story, everyone needs to make sure that the tasks required to complete the User Story is fully understood. If not, the scope would be inaccurate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One way of listing down a task for the User Story is to go over a &lt;strong&gt;“done thinking grid“&lt;/strong&gt;. A sample one is below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Column 1&lt;/strong&gt;: Make sure that the &lt;strong&gt;User Stories&lt;/strong&gt; for a sprint are &lt;strong&gt;clear&lt;/strong&gt; and understood by the team. Also make sure that the acceptance criteria are validated by the product owner. Make sure that the &lt;strong&gt;tasks&lt;/strong&gt; for the Stories have been &lt;strong&gt;identified&lt;/strong&gt;. Estimation will not be accurate if the tasks were not clearly understood by the team. Communicate &lt;strong&gt;build and package changes&lt;/strong&gt; to the build master if you have one. Make sure that there is enough time for the &lt;strong&gt;product owner to sign off&lt;/strong&gt; the User Stories after the User Acceptance Test. Also ensure that the features &lt;strong&gt;not done&lt;/strong&gt; during the sprint are &lt;strong&gt;added back to the product backlog&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Column 2&lt;/strong&gt;: Make sure that development, staging and production &lt;strong&gt;environment is ready&lt;/strong&gt; with all tools and artifacts needed to complete the tasks at hand. Continuous integration, automation, test data, etc., need to be in place. Also, the &lt;strong&gt;Design&lt;/strong&gt; needs to be complete. Lack of design may mean that the steps in the tasks have not been thought through. This situation is risky since it could result in scope creep or not being able to deliver on time. **Unit tests, documentation and pre-&lt;strong&gt;release builds need to be ready&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Column 3&lt;/strong&gt;: Make sure that all the coding for features in the task list are done. “&lt;strong&gt;Code complete&lt;/strong&gt;” implies that coding is done, &lt;strong&gt;unit testing&lt;/strong&gt; is done, &lt;strong&gt;code re-factoring&lt;/strong&gt; is done, &lt;strong&gt;bug fixes&lt;/strong&gt; are done and the code is &lt;strong&gt;checked in&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Column 4&lt;/strong&gt;: Make sure that &lt;strong&gt;automated code reviews&lt;/strong&gt;, for e.g review by a tool like P.M.D for Java coding conventions are done. Every code that is written needs to be &lt;strong&gt;peer reviewed&lt;/strong&gt; and approved. Check if &lt;strong&gt;code coverage&lt;/strong&gt; metrics have been maintained. If the new code didn’t add tests, coverage might decrease. Check if the project metrics like burn-down chart are updated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Column 5&lt;/strong&gt;: Ensure that the product is fully tested before being released to production. Check if &lt;strong&gt;functional testing&lt;/strong&gt; is completed. All kinds of automated and manual testing as per test cases need to be completed. Also make sure that &lt;strong&gt;Regression testing&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Load and Performance&lt;/strong&gt; testing and &lt;strong&gt;User Acceptance&lt;/strong&gt; testing are done. After this mark the tasks as closed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;: Having one definition or checklist of “definition of done” is not practical since every project and organization is unique. Most teams go wrong with the “definition of done” in the initial stages of Agile. If the team is committed to learning from each sprint by earnestly doing Sprint retrospective, then gradually, they would get it right. Getting to a state of the ideal “definition of done” is key to delivering ship-able products that satisfy customer expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] Gupta, M. (2008, September 3). Definition of Done: A Reference. Retrieved November 4, 2014, from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scrumalliance.org/community/articles/2008/september/definition-of-done-a-reference&#34;&gt;https://www.scrumalliance.org/community/articles/2008/september/definition-of-done-a-reference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2] Schwaber, K. (2004). Appendix A. In Agile project management with Scrum. Redmond, Wash.: Microsoft Press.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/management/2014-10-07-agile-task-list-what-does-done-mean/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>The Agile Sprint Retrospective</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/management/2014-09-21-agile-sprint-retrospective/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 21:24:13 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/management/2014-09-21-agile-sprint-retrospective/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/management/2014-09-21-agile-sprint-retrospective/ -&lt;h1 id=&#34;agile-sprint-retrospective&#34;&gt;Agile Sprint Retrospective&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the third post in this series of “Introduction to Agile methodology”. The topic of this blog is “Agile Sprint Retrospective”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overview:&lt;/strong&gt;  Agile Sprint Retrospective is a meeting that happens after a Sprint to evaluate how the last one went. The Team, the Scrum Master and the Product Owner attends this meeting in Scrum. The objective of the meeting is to reflect on the current process and determine what steps could be taken to make corrections and adapt to future sprints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Figure 1   Sprint Meetings – Sprint Retrospective highlighted&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meeting starts with all the team members answering 2 questions –&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;What went well during the last Sprint?
What could be improved in the next Sprint?
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Scrum, the Scrum Master writes down the answers in summary form. Then everyone prioritizes in which order it wants to talk about improvements. Actionable items could be added to the next Sprint during the Sprint Grooming session as “Non-functional Requirements”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advantages&lt;/strong&gt; of this meeting are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It often exposes Organizational impediments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everyone gets clarity on what could be improved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Actionable steps can be taken towards better execution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many &lt;strong&gt;impediments&lt;/strong&gt; to having a good retrospective. Few of them are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lack of a proper environment where the members could speak their minds would mean that people could avoid bringing up uncomfortable issues. It is advisable for managers (who do performance evaluation) to be not present in the meeting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lack of co-operation from everyone might make the retrospective life-less and stale with no constructive inputs to improve in the next iterations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Geographic distribution is another impediment. If everyone in the meeting is not face to face, the communication might cease to be fully transparent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scrum Masters employ a variety of techniques to get honest and transparent feedback from the team. Below are a few:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go around the table and ask 2 questions mentioned above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Silent writing: In this, the team is asked to write down feedback about the current process and submit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Satisfaction Histograms: Here the team given a survey of questions and asked to rate each on a satisfaction scale of 1 to 5.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, the retrospective is a very good mechanism to keep the team agile and improve continuously. Scrum Master aims to get answers and compiles them into an actionable list. These are either put into the next sprint’s backlog or into the product backlog to be tackled later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] Schwaber, K. (2004). Appendix A. In Agile project management with Scrum. Redmond, Wash.: Microsoft Press.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2] Agile Methodology. (2014, July 1). Retrieved September 10, 2014, from &lt;a href=&#34;http://agilemethodology.org&#34;&gt;http://agilemethodology.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/management/2014-09-21-agile-sprint-retrospective/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>The Agile Team and the backlog</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/management/2014-09-16-agile-and-backlog/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 19:34:23 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/management/2014-09-16-agile-and-backlog/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/management/2014-09-16-agile-and-backlog/ -&lt;p&gt;This blog continues on the last week’s blog about introducing Agile to newcomers to the practice. The focus this week is on 2 things – The agile team and the artifacts that they work on, namely “backlogs”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;agile-team&#34;&gt;Agile Team&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agile team is a self contained team that can by itself complete a user story in the backlog. Let’s take the example of “Scrum” which is a popular Agile framework. In scrum, there could be dependencies with external teams. But it is up to the Scrum Master to resolve these dependencies. Otherwise, the team would flag such User Stories as having ‘impediments’ and move on to the next one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Typically a Scrum team consists of the following roles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scrum Master&lt;/strong&gt; – Person who is in charge of the sprints&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Product Owner&lt;/strong&gt; – Person who represents the stakeholders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Team&lt;/strong&gt; – Consists of different people who collectively have skills to complete tasks in the backlog.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below is a short summary of responsibilities for each role.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;scrum-master&#34;&gt;Scrum Master:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manages 1 sprint at a time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facilitates Sprint Planning, Review &amp;amp; Retrospective&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finds and works to remove roadblocks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Helps to motivate the team and keep them excited&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Protects team from outside distractions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facilitates communication between roles for every aspect of the project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Responsible for keeping release/project information consolidated, organized and up to date&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drives the cross-functional team at all levels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Responsible for throughput&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drives the execution of sprint items&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;product-owner&#34;&gt;Product Owner:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Responsible for market, business case, and competitive analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Responsible for long and short term product vision&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Responsible for ROI and Net Profit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prioritizes features for releases based upon expected ROI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writes Acceptance Criteria&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writes user stories&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Makes tradeoff decisions between scope and schedule&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;team&#34;&gt;Team:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Responsible for implementation of the backlog items as per the acceptance criteria&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The team could contain people with specialized skills
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Architect to define the design and ensure that best practices are followed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Developers to develop and unit test the features&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quality engineers to test the features and ensure that they have been done as per the acceptance criteria&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User Experience Designers to take care of the human interaction perspective&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;..etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;backlog&#34;&gt;Backlog&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The product backlog in Scrum is a list of features that are desired for a product at that point in time. Features are short descriptions of the functionality that is needed and these are prioritized. They could contain new features, bugs, technical debt..etc. Typically a team picks few features from the top of the list during ‘Sprint Grooming’ sessions. During ‘Sprint Planning’, the product owner shows up with the prioritized list and the team take these, estimates and locks the features that could be accomplished in a sprint (called ‘Sprint backlog’).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] – Sanders, A. (2008, August 12). Agile Team Members : Roles and Responsibilities. Retrieved September 16, 2014, from &lt;a href=&#34;http://aaron.sanders.name/agile-team-members-roles-and-responsibilities/&#34;&gt;http://aaron.sanders.name/agile-team-members-roles-and-responsibilities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2] – Cohn, M. (n.d.). Topics in Scrum. Retrieved September 18, 2014, from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mountaingoatsoftware.com/agile/scrum/product-backlog&#34;&gt;http://www.mountaingoatsoftware.com/agile/scrum/product-backlog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/management/2014-09-16-agile-and-backlog/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>What is agile and what are user stories</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/management/2014-09-09-what-is-agile/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2014 22:54:56 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/management/2014-09-09-what-is-agile/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/management/2014-09-09-what-is-agile/ -&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the earlier days of the software industry, the process of developing software products mirrored engineering practices of the day. Like a bridge construction needed elaborate planning, design and construction, a software product went through a “waterfall” model of requirement definition, design, development, testing and release, with each phase occurring one after another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the cookie cutter approach failed for big software products which ended up creating products and systems that user didn’t have in mind or didn’t want anymore or became obsolete because the technology had changed. This is where Agile methodology comes into light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-agile&#34;&gt;What is Agile?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agile software development is a group of software development methods in which requirements and solutions evolve through collaboration between self-organizing, cross-functional teams. It promotes adaptive planning, evolutionary development, early delivery, continuous improvement and encourages rapid and flexible response to change. It is a conceptual framework that focuses on frequently delivering small increments of working software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;short-history&#34;&gt;Short History&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A small group of people got together in 2001 to discuss their feelings that the traditional approach to managing software development projects was failing far too often, and there had to be a better way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They came up with the agile manifesto[1], which describes 4 important values that are as relevant today as they were then.  It says,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;agile-manifesto&#34;&gt;Agile Manifesto&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We value:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Individuals and interactions&lt;/strong&gt; over processes and tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Working software&lt;/strong&gt; over comprehensive documentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Customer collaboration&lt;/strong&gt; over contract negotiation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Responding to change&lt;/strong&gt; over following a plan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though incremental practices have been in existence since late 1950’s[2], the ‘Agile Manifesto’ ushered in a new era of focus on lightweight-iterative development. The Agile Manifesto is based on twelve principles[3] :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;agile-principles&#34;&gt;Agile Principles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customer satisfaction by rapid delivery of useful software&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Welcome changing requirements, even late in development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working software is delivered frequently (weeks rather than months)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Close, daily cooperation between business people and developers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Projects are built around motivated individuals, who should be trusted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Face-to-face conversation is the best form of communication (co-location)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working software is the principal measure of progress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sustainable development, able to maintain a constant pace&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continuous attention to technical excellence and good design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simplicity—the art of maximizing the amount of work not done—is essential&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-organizing teams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regular adaptation to changing circumstances&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agile development provides opportunities to assess the direction of the project and to evaluate the end product at very early stages. This is achieved through regular cadences of work, known as Sprints or iterations, at the end of which teams must present a potentially shippable product increment. At the beginning of every sprint, the team does a “Sprint Planning” session where it pulls requirements from the top of a “backlog”, estimates the effort and determines if they can be accomplished during the sprint or not. The requirements are in the form of “User Stories” which is a high level definition of a feature being built for an end user. We’ll talk about User Stories in detail in the next section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;user-stories&#34;&gt;User Stories&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A user story is a short, simple statement of a requirement from the perspective of the end user of a system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It typically follows this structure :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a “type of user”, I want “some goal” so that “some reason”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A user story is a very high-level definition of a requirement, containing just enough information so that the developers can produce a reasonable estimate of the effort to implement it. User stories are often written on index cards or sticky notes, stored in a shoe box, and arranged on walls or tables to facilitate planning and discussion. As such, they strongly shift the focus from writing about features to discussing them. In fact, these discussions are more important than whatever text is written.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Typically, if an index card is used, a user story might contain the following – User story summary (in the format mentioned above), priority and estimate on one side of the card and acceptance criteria on the other side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the user stories of a release are sorted in the order of priority in the “Release backlog”. Stories from the top of the pile are taken and a “Sprint backlog” is created for every sprint during the “Sprint Planning” meeting. At the end of every sprint, the team presents a potentially shippable product increment which is demoed during the “Sprint Review” at the end of the sprint. Details about the workflow of an Agile Sprint and related meetings would be the subject of another blog post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;epics&#34;&gt;Epics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epics are large user stories, typically ones which are too big to implement in a single iteration and therefore they need to be dis-aggregated into smaller user stories at some point. Epics are typically lower priority user stories because once the epic works its way towards the top of the work item stack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;User Stories in the backlog&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We looked at how agile methodologies took shape, what agile is, a high level overview of the development life-cycle using agile and also looked in depth into one of key artifacts of agile – “User Stories” .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;references-&#34;&gt;References :&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[1] Beck, Kent; et al. (2001). “Manifesto for Agile Software Development”. Agile Alliance. Retrieved 14 June 2010.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[2] Gerald M. Weinberg, as quoted in Larman, Craig; Basili, Victor R. (June 2003). “Iterative and Incremental Development: A Brief History”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[3] Beck, Kent; et al. (2001). “Principles behind the Agile Manifesto”. Agile Alliance. Archived from the original on 14 June 2010. Retrieved 6 June 2010.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[4] Ambler, S. (n.d.). User Stories: An Agile Introduction. Retrieved September 10, 2014, from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.agilemodeling.com/artifacts/userStory.htm&#34;&gt;http://www.agilemodeling.com/artifacts/userStory.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scott, A., &amp;amp; Holitza, M. (2012). Agile for Dummies. John Wiley &amp;amp; Sons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Agile Methodology. (2014, July 1). Retrieved September 10, 2014, from &lt;a href=&#34;http://agilemethodology.org&#34;&gt;http://agilemethodology.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/management/2014-09-09-what-is-agile/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Introduction to Data Mining by Pang-Ning Tan, Michael Steinbach, Vipin Kumar</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/books/2014-02-16-datamining-tsk/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2014 18:17:11 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/books/2014-02-16-datamining-tsk/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/books/2014-02-16-datamining-tsk/ -&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Introduction to Data Mining&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; by Pang-Ning Tan, Michael Steinbach and Vipin Kumar has been recommended to me as a great book to learn about Data Mining. Read the first chapter and it felt very inspiring as though it was beckoning me to keep at it and read more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thought I will capture notes as I read. The way I usually capture notes is to make a list of all the headings, go over them once I finish a chapter or at a later time. Brain just needs a key to fetch information. The headings serve as good keys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best thing about the book is that sample chapters and lecture notes (ppt) are available on the publisher&amp;rsquo;s website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Main Page&lt;/strong&gt; : &lt;a href=&#34;http://www-users.cs.umn.edu/~kumar/dmbook/index.php&#34;&gt;http://www-users.cs.umn.edu/~kumar/dmbook/index.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Power Point slides&lt;/strong&gt; : &lt;a href=&#34;http://www-users.cs.umn.edu/~kumar/dmbook/index.php#item4&#34;&gt;http://www-users.cs.umn.edu/~kumar/dmbook/index.php#item4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sample Chapters&lt;/strong&gt; : &lt;a href=&#34;http://www-users.cs.umn.edu/~kumar/dmbook/index.php#item2&#34;&gt;http://www-users.cs.umn.edu/~kumar/dmbook/index.php#item2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-1---introduction&#34;&gt;Chapter 1 - Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Mining&lt;/strong&gt; : Non-trivial extraction of implicit, previously unknown and potentially useful information from data. Exploration &amp;amp; analysis, by automatic or semi-automatic means, of large quantities of data in order to discover meaningful patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 Introduction
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fields - business, medicine, science &amp;amp; engineering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.1 What is Data Mining
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Different from Information Retrieval&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integral part of KDD(Knowledge discovery in databases)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.2 Motivating Challenges
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scalability, High Dimensionality, Heterogenous and complex data, Data Ownership and distribution, Non-traditional analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.3 The Origins of Data Mining
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Relates to fields of Statistics, AI, Machine Learning &amp;amp; Pattern Recognition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built on Database technology, Parallel Computing, Distributed computing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.4 Data Mining Tasks
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Predictive tasks, Descriptive tasks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Predictive modeling - classification (discrete target variables), regression ( continuous target variables)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Association analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cluster analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anomaly detection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1.5 Scope and Organizations of the Book&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ref : Introduction to Data Mining - Chapter 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www-users.cs.umn.edu/~kumar/dmbook/dmslides/chap1_intro.pdf&#34;&gt;http://www-users.cs.umn.edu/~kumar/dmbook/dmslides/chap1_intro.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-2---data&#34;&gt;Chapter 2 - Data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data is a collection of objects and their attributes. An attribute is a property or characteristic of an object. A collection of attributes describe an object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 Data
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.1. Types of data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2.1.1. attributes &amp;amp; measurement
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;operations used to describe attributes - distinctness, order, addition, multiplication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 types of attributes - nominal, ordinal, interval, ratio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nominal and Ordinal are Categorical (Qualitative)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interval and Ratio are Numeric (Quantitative)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nominal (ids, zip codes) -&amp;gt; distinctness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ordinal (rankings, grades) -&amp;gt; distinctness + order&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interval (dates, temp in C) -&amp;gt; distinctness + order + addition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ratio (temp in K, length, time) -&amp;gt; distinctness + order + addition + multiplication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;attribute categorization by values -&amp;gt; discrete, continuous&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2.1.2. Types of data sets
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Characteristics of data sets -&amp;gt; dimensionality, sparsity, resolution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Types -&amp;gt; record, graph, ordered
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Record data : a. record data, b. transaction data, c. data matrix, d. document-term matrix&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graph based data : a. data with relationship among objects (www), b. data with objects that are graphs (molecular structure)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ordered data : a. sequential data (timestamps), b. sequence data (genetic code), c. time series data, d. spatial data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.2. Data Quality&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2.2.1. Measurement and data quality issues
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Noise &amp;amp; artifacts -&amp;gt; precision (std deviation), bias (mean-actual), accuracy (closeness to true value)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Outliers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Missing values -&amp;gt; how to solve : eliminate data objects, eliminate missing value attributes, ignore missing value during analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inconsistent values&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Duplicate data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2.2.2. Issues related to applications
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;timeliness, relevance, knowledge about the data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.3. Data Preprocessing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2.3.1. Aggregation
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Purpose : data reduction (smaller dataset means lesser memory), change of scale, more &amp;lsquo;stable&amp;rsquo; data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2.3.2. Sampling
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Processing all records is very expensive. but sampling needs to be representative&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sampling approaches :
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple random sampling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sampling without replacement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sampling with replacement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stratified sampling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Progressive sampling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2.3.3. Dimensionality reduction
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Curse of dimensionality (COD)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Purpose : avoid COD, reduce processing time, better visualization, reduce noise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Techniques : PCA (Principal Components Analysis), SVD (Singular Value Decomposition)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2.3.4. Feature subset reduction
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove redundant features, irrelevant features&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Techniques : brute force, embedded, filter, wrapper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2.3.5. Feature Creation
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create new attributes from existing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Methods : feature extraction, mapping data to new space (Fourier transformation, wavelet trans&amp;rsquo;n), feature construction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2.3.6. Discretization &amp;amp; Binarization
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;discretization, binarization, discretization of continuous attributes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unsupervised discretization (no class labels) : equal width, equal frequency -&amp;gt; K-means&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supervised discretization (using class labels) : entropy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2.3.7. Variable Transformation
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple functions, normalization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.4. Measures of Similarity &amp;amp; Dissimilarity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.4.1. Basics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;definitions - similarity, dissimilarity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;transformations -&amp;gt; e.g s&amp;rsquo; = (s - min_s) / (max_s - min_s)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.4.2. S &amp;amp; D b/w simple attributes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;nominal : d = 0 or 1 if x = y or x != y ; s = 1 or 0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ordinal :
$d = |x - y| / (n-1) ; s = 1 - d$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;interval or ratio :
$ d = |x - y| ; s = -d, s = 1/(1+d) $&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.4.3. Dissimilarities b/w data objects&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Distances
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Euclidean distance :
$f(x) = \sqrt{\sum_{k=1}^n (x_k - y_k)^2}$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minkowski distance (Generalization) :
$f(x) = (\sum_{k=1}^n (x_k - y_k)^r) ^ {1/r} $
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hamming distance (city blocks) : r = 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Euclidean distance : r = 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supremum distance : r =
$ \infty $&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Common properties : a. Positivity, b. Symmetry, c. Triangle inequality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;lsquo;metric&amp;rsquo; satisfies all common properties&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.4.4 Similarities b/w data objects&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;typical properties&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;s(x, y) = 1 only if x = y [max similarity]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.4.5 Examples of proximity measures&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Similarity co-efficients
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple Matching :
$ SMC =  (f_11 + f_00) / (f_01 + f_10 + f_11 + f_00) $&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jaccard :
$ JC =  f_11 / (f_01 + f_10 + f_11 + f_00) $&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cosine :
$ cos(x, y) = $ x.y / ||x||.||y|| $
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;x.y is the vector dot product =
$ \sum_{k=1}^n (x_k y_k) $&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;x.y is the vector dot product =
$ \sum_{k=1}^n (x_k y_k) $&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;||x|| =
$ \sqrt{x.x}$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extended Jaccard :
$ EJ =  x.y / (||x||^2 + ||y||^2 - x.y) $&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Correlation : $ P_k $ -&amp;gt; Pearson&amp;rsquo;s Correlation
*
$ P_k (x, y) = covariance (x, y) / SD(x) . SD(y) $&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;$ covariance(x, y) = 1 / (n-1)  \sum_{k=1}^n(x_k - \bar{x}) (y_k - \bar{x}) $&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;$ = 1/n \sum_{k=1}^n(x_k)$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;$ \bar{x} = $ mean of x $ = 1/n \sum_{k=1}^n(x_k)$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;$ \bar{y} = $ mean of y&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;$ SD(x) = Standard deviation = \sqrt{1 / (n-1)  \sum_{k=1}^n(x_k - \bar{x})^2 } $&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bregman divergence
*
$ D(x, y) = \phi{(x)} - \phi{(y)} - \langle \nabla \phi{(y)}, (x - y) \rangle $
*
$ D(x, y) = \phi{(x)} - \phi{(y)} - \langle \nabla \phi{(y)}, (x - y) \rangle $&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.4.6 Issues in Proximity calculation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a. different scales, b. different attributes, c. different weights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Standardization
*
$ mahalanobis(x, y) = (x - y) \sum_{}^{-1}(x-y)^T $&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Combining Similarities
*
$ Similarity(x, y) = \sum_{k=1}^n w_k \delta_k s_k(x, y)  / \sum_{k=1}^n \delta_k $&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.4.7 Selecting the right proximity measure&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type of proximity should fit type of data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use Euclidean distance for dense continuous data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Usually expressed as differences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sparse data -&amp;gt; ignore 0-0 matches -&amp;gt; use Jaccard, cosine, Extended Jaccard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time series -&amp;gt; use Euclidean distance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time series with different magnitudes -&amp;gt; use Correlation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was a pretty long chapter. Lots learnt !
Best thing that I learnt outside the chapter was &amp;lsquo;how to write mathematical equations in a blog&amp;rsquo;! Used a Javascript library named MathJax which renders LaTeX notation at runtime into HTML.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ref&lt;/strong&gt; : &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.mathjax.org/en/latest/start.html&#34;&gt;http://docs.mathjax.org/en/latest/start.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Putting this snippet in &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; section worked&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;script src=&amp;quot;http://cdn.mathjax.org/mathjax/latest/MathJax.js&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
    MathJax.Hub.Config({
        extensions: [&amp;quot;tex2jax.js&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;TeX/AMSmath.js&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;TeX/AMSsymbols.js&amp;quot;],
        jax: [&amp;quot;input/TeX&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;output/HTML-CSS&amp;quot;],
        tex2jax: {
            inlineMath: [ [&#39;$&#39;,&#39;$&#39;], [&amp;quot;\\(&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;\\)&amp;quot;] ],
            displayMath: [ [&#39;$$&#39;,&#39;$$&#39;], [&amp;quot;\\[&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;\\]&amp;quot;] ],
            processEscapes: true,
        },
        &amp;quot;HTML-CSS&amp;quot;: { availableFonts: [&amp;quot;TeX&amp;quot;] }
    });
&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ref&lt;/strong&gt; : &lt;a href=&#34;http://narnia.cs.ttu.edu/drupal/node/129&#34;&gt;http://narnia.cs.ttu.edu/drupal/node/129&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References for this chapter :&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Text : Introduction to Data Mining - Chapter 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ppt : &lt;a href=&#34;http://www-users.cs.umn.edu/~kumar/dmbook/dmslides/chap2_data.pdf&#34;&gt;http://www-users.cs.umn.edu/~kumar/dmbook/dmslides/chap2_data.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-3---exploring-data&#34;&gt;Chapter 3 - Exploring Data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data exploration is a preliminary exploration of the data to better understand its characteristics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 Exploring Data
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3.1 The Iris Data Set&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3.2 Summary Statistics
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3.2.1 Frequencies and the Mode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3.2.2 Percentiles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3.2.3 Measures of Location : Mean and Median&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3.2.4 Measure of Spread : Range and Variance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3.2.5 Multivariate Summary Statistics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3.2.6 Other ways to Summarize the Data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3.3 Visualization
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3.3.1 Motivations for Visualization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3.3.2 General Concepts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3.3.3 Techniques&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3.3.4 Visualizing Higher dimensional data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3.3.5 Do&amp;rsquo;s and Don&amp;rsquo;ts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3.4 OLAP and Multidimensional Analysis
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Representing Iris data as a multidimensional array&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multidimensional data : The General Case&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analyzing multidimensional data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Final comments on multidimensional data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;April 2014&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-4---classification&#34;&gt;Chapter 4 - Classification&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Classification is the task of assigning objects to one of several pre-defined categories. E.g - detecting spam email messages based upon the message header and content, categorizing cells as malignant or benign based upon the results of MRI scans, and classifying galaxies based upon their shapes ..etc&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 Classification
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.1 Preliminaries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.2 General Approach to solving a classification problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.3 Decision Tree Induction
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.3.1 How a Decision Tree works&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.3.2 How to build a Decision Tree&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.3.3 Methods for expressing attribute test conditions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.3.4 Measure for selecting the Best Split&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.3.5 Algorithm for Decision Tree induction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.3.6 An Example : Web Robot Detection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.3.7 Characteristics of Decision Tree Induction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.4 Model Overfitting
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.4.1 Overfitting due to presence of noise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.4.2 Overfitting due to lack of representative samples&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.4.3 Overfitting and the multiple comparison procedure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.4.4 Estimation of Generalization Errors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.4.5 Handling overfitting in Decision Tree Induction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.5 Evaluating the performance of a Classifier
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.5.1 Holdout method&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.5.2 Random subsampling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.5.3 Cross Validation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.5.4 Bootstrap&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4.6 Methods for Comparing Classifiers
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Estimating a confidence interval for accuracy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comparing the performance of two models&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comparing the performance of two classifiers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;May 2014&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-8---cluster-analysis&#34;&gt;Chapter 8 - Cluster Analysis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cluster analysis could be defined as &amp;ldquo;Finding groups of objects such that the objects in a group will be similar (or related) to one another and different from (or unrelated to) the objects in other groups.&amp;rdquo;
In short, cluster analysis divides the data into groups(clusters) that are meaningful, useful or both.
There are many applications of cluster analysis to practical problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clustering for Understanding&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Biology - creating taxonomy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Information Retrieval - grouping search results from the web&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Climate - finding patterns in the atmosphere&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Psychology and medicine - identify illness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Business - segment customers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clustering for Utility&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Summarization - apply costly algorithms to cluster prototypes instead of the entire dataset.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compression - prototypes are used when data objects are similar and loss is acceptable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Efficiently finding nearest neighbors - use prototypes to reduce number of pairwise distance computations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8.1 Overview&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8.1.1 What is Cluster Analysis
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Defined above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Groups data objects based only on information found in the data that describes the objects and their relationships.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notion of a cluster is ambiguous&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Classification is &amp;ldquo;Supervised Classification&amp;rdquo; and Cluster analysis is &amp;ldquo;Unsupervised Classification&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Segmentation&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Partitioning&amp;rdquo; are also sometimes synonymous with Clustering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is not Cluster Analysis
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supervised Classification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple segmentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Results of a query&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graph partitioning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8.1.2 Different types of Clusterings
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hierarchical vs Partitional
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hierarchical (nested) - leaves are singletons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Partitional (unnested) - non overlapping subsets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exclusive vs Overlapping vs Fuzzy
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exclusive - assign each object to a single cluster&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overlapping - objects can simultaneously belong to more than one cluster&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fuzzy - every object belongs to every cluster with a membership weight between 0(absolutely doesn&amp;rsquo;t belong) and 1(abs belongs)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;caveat : it doesn&amp;rsquo;t address true multi-class situations since the weights need to add up to 1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete vs Partial
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete - assigns every object to a cluster&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Partial - doesn&amp;rsquo;t assign every object to a cluster&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heterogeneous vs Homogeneous&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8.1.3 Different types of Clusters
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Well Separated - any point in a cluster is closer (more similar) to every other point in the cluster than to any point not in the cluster. Can have any shape.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prototype based (center based) -  an object in a cluster is closer (more similar) to the “center” of a cluster, than to the center of any other cluster.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for data with continuous attributes, center is often the centroid. when centroid is not meaningful (data with categorical attributes), centre is often the medoid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tends to be globular.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graph based - group of objects that are connected to one another but have no connection to objects outside the group. (Connected Components)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contiguity-based - 2 objects are connected only if they are within a specified distance of each other. Useful when clusters are irregular or intertwined.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clique - another example of graph based cluster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Density based - a cluster is a dense region of objects that is surrounded by a region of low density. Used when clusters are irregular or intertwined and when noise and outliers are present.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shared property (conceptual clustering) - Finds clusters that share some common property or represent a particular concept.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Objective function - Finds clusters that minimize or maximize an objective function.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Characteristics of Input data
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type of proximity/density measure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sparseness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attribute Type&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type of data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dimensionality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Noise and Outliers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Type of Distribution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clustering Algorithms
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;K-means - prototype based, partitional clustering technique - finds k clusters represented by their centroids.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hierarchical Clustering - leaves are singletons, top down or bottom up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DBSCAN - density based, partial that produces a partitional clustering. number of clusters is automatically determined by the algorithm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8.2 K-means&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Partitional clustering technique in which each cluster is associated with a centroid and each point is assigned to a cluster with the closest centroid. Number of clusters K, must be given as input.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8.2.1 The basic K-means algorithm
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Initial centroids are often chosen randomly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The centroid is generally the mean of the points in the cluster&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Closeness is measured by Euclidean distance, cosine similarity, correlation ..etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most of the convergence happens the first few iterations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complexity is O(I * K * m * n)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assigning points to the closest centroid - Manhattan(L1) distance can be used for Euclidean data, Jaccard measure for document data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Centroids and Objective function - e.g for objective function : minimize the squared distance of each point to its closest centroid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data in Euclidean space - Objective function used is SSE(Sum of Squared Error) also known as &amp;lsquo;scatter&amp;rsquo;.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;where dist is the standard Euclidean (L2) distance b/w objects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Centroid that minimizes the SSE of a cluster is the mean&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Given 2 different sets of clusters, we prefer one with lower SSE.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Document data
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;represented as a DTM(document term matrix)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;objective is to maximize similarity of the objects in the cluster to cluster centroid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The analogous quantity to SSE is &amp;lsquo;total cohesion&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The General case
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are many choices for the proximity function, centroid and objective function that can be used in basic k-means algorithm and that are guaranteed to converge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bregman divergence includes squared Euclidean distance, the Mahalanobis distance and cosine similarity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choosing initial centroids
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eg. 1 - Poor initial centroids : Randomly selected initial centroids may provide sub-optimal clustering with a higher SSE.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eg. 2 - Limits of random initialization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If there are K &amp;lsquo;real&amp;rsquo; clusters, chance of selecting one centroid from each is very small.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Solutions to Initial centroids problem
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perform multiple runs
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One way to minimize the effect or a poor random initial choice of centroids is to perform multiple runs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But this also need not give optimal clustering. If a centroid falls between a pair of clusters, it will be stuck there by making one cluster out of 2.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use hierarchical clustering on a sample
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One effective approach to counter the limitations of random poor initial centroids is to take a sample of points and cluster them using hierarchical clustering technique and use those centroids as initial centroids.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But this is practical only if sample is relatively small and k is small compared to sample size.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Iterative approach
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select first point at random (or take centroid of all points)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for each successive initial centroid, select a point that is farthest from the previously selected centroids.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the downside is that this could select outliers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select more than K centroids&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Post processing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bisecting K-means&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time and Space complexity
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Storage required : O((m + K)n) , m = number of points, n = number of attributes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time required : O(I * K * m * n) , I = number of iterations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8.2.2 K-means: Additional issues
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Handling empty clusters
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic K-means algo can yield empty clusters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose a replacement otherwise SSE will be large&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Approach 1 : Choose a replacement point that is farthest from any current centroid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Approach 2 : Choose a replacement point from the centroid that has highest SSE. This would split the cluster and reduce overall SSE.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Outliers
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If there are outliers, centroids may not be as representative as they ought to be and SSE would be higher as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One approach is to discover outliers and eliminate them beforehand. But there could be situations where outliers are important (compression, financial data)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Another approach is to identify outliers during pre-processing. Identify points with high contributions to SSE.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also we could eliminate small clusters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reducing the SSE with post processing
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One way to reduce SSE is to increase number of clusters (larger K). 2 strategies that decrease SSE by increasing K are -
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Split a cluster - Choose a cluster with largest SSE or largest standard deviation for an attribute.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduce a new centroid - One approach is to choose a point farthest from any cluster center. Another is to choose a point at random.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 strategies that decrease K and try to minimize the SSE increase are -
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disperse a cluster - removing a centroid and assigning the points to other clusters.  Disperse a cluster that doesn&amp;rsquo;t contribute much to the total SSE.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Merge 2 clusters - Clusters with closest centroids are usually chosen. Strategy is same as that used in hierarchical clustering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commonly used approach is to alternate cluster splitting and merging phases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updating centroids incrementally
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the basic K-means algorithm, centroids are updated after all points are assigned to a centroid. An alternative is to update the centroids after each assignment (incremental approach). Each assignment updates 0 or 2 centroids.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pros
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Guarantees that empty clusters are not produced.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Relative weights may be adjusted. Better accuracy and faster convergence are possible if weights are used.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cons:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is more expensive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduces an order dependency (clusters produced depends on the order in which points are processed) . Although this can be overcome by randomizing the order.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8.2.3 Bisecting K-means
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A straightforward extension of the basic K-means algorithm that is based on a simple idea: to obtain K clusters, split the set of all points into two clusters, select one of these clusters to split, and so on, until K clusters have been produced.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are different ways to choose which cluster to split, say using size or SSE.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Usually the the clusters are refined by using the resulting centroids as initial centroids for basic k-means algorithm. This is useful since during bisecting k-means we&amp;rsquo;re using k-means algorithm &amp;lsquo;locally&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bisecting K-means is less susceptible to initialization problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also we can use bisecting k-means for hierarchical clustering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8.2.4 K-means and different types of clusters
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;K-means has difficulty in detecting natural clusters when clusters have non-spherical shapes or widely different sizes or densities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This could be overcome if the user is willing to increase K and have more clusters. So a cluster might have many sub clusters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8.2.5 Strengths and weaknesses
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strengths : Used for wide variety of data types, Very efficient&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weaknesses : Cannot handle non-globular clusters, not good with data that has outliers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8.2.6 K-means as an optimization problem
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gradient descent - involves picking an initial solution and then repeating the fol- lowing two steps: compute the change to the solution that best optimizes the objective function and then update the solution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Derivation of K-means as an algorithm to minimize the SSE (sum of squared errors): Proof that the best centroid for minimizing the SSE of a cluster is the mean of the points in the cluster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Derivation of K-means for SAE (sum of absolute errors) : Ck is the median of the cluster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8.3 Agglomerative Hierarchical Clustering&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 approaches of hierarchical clustering -
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Agglomerative - Start with the points as individual clusters and, at each step, merge the closest pair of clusters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Divisive - Start with one, all-inclusive cluster and, at each step, split a cluster until only singleton clusters of individual points remain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Often displayed graphically using a tree-like diagram called dendogram, which displays sub-cluster relationships and also the order in which the clusters were merged.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t have to assume any particular number of clusters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;May correspond to meaningful taxonomies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8.3.1 Basic Agglomerative Hierarchical Clustering Algorithm
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Key operation is the computation of proximity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Defining proximity b/w clusters
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cluster proximity is typically defined with a particular type of cluster in mind. For example, many agglomerative hierarchical clustering techniques, such as MIN, MAX, and Group Average, come from a graph-based view of clusters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time and Space complexity
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proximity matrix requires the storage of 1/m^2 proximities. The space needed to keep track of the clusters is proportional to the number of clusters. Hence, the total space complexity is O(m^2).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are m steps and at each step the size, m^2, proximity matrix must be updated and searched. So time complexity is O(m^3). It can be reduced to O(m^2 log m) by keeping the data in a sorted list or heap&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8.3.2 Specific Techniques of similarity measures
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MIN (single link)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Similarity of two clusters is based on the two most similar (closest) points in the different clusters. Determined by one pair of points, i.e., by one link in the proximity graph.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strength : Can handle non-eliptical shapes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weakness : Sensitive to noise and outliers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MAX (complete link)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Similarity of two clusters is based on the two least similar (most distant) points in the different clusters. Determined by all pairs of points in the two clusters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strength : Less susceptible to noise and outliers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weakness : Tends to break large clusters, Biased towards globular clusters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Group Average
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proximity of two clusters is the average of pairwise proximity between points in the two clusters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compromise between Single and Complete Link&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strength : Less susceptible to noise and outliers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weakness : Biased towards globular clusters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ward&amp;rsquo;s method
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Similarity of two clusters is based on the increase in squared error when two clusters are merged.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Similar to group average if distance between points is distance squared.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hierarchical analogue of K-means – Can be used to initialize K-means.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strength : Less susceptible to noise and outliers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weakness : Biased towards globular clusters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Distance between centroids : Similarity of two clusters is based on the distance between the centroids in the different clusters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8.3.3 The Lance-Williams formula for Cluster Proximity
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A general formula for expressing hierarchical clustering proximity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any of the cluster proximities that we have discussed above can be viewed as a choice of different parameters in the Lance-Williams formula&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8.3.4 Key Issues in Hierarchical clustering
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lack of a global objective function : It is greedy technique in which optimization is done locally at that specific moment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to handle different cluster sizes : In order to take care of the relative sizes of the clusters that are merged, we could take weights into account.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UPGMA - Unweighted Pair Group Method using Arithmetic averages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WPGMA - Weighted Pair Group Method using Arithmetic averages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Merging decisions are final: Once the decision is made, it cannot be undone at a later time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8.3.5 Strengths and Weaknesses : Already discussed above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8.4 DBSCAN&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Density-based clustering locates regions of high density that are separated from one another by regions of low density. DBSCAN is a simple and effective density-based clustering algorithm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8.4.1 Traditional Density: Center-based approach
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the center-based approach, density is estimated for a particular point in the data set by counting the number of points within a specified radius, Eps, of that point. This includes the point itself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Classification of Points According to Center-Based Density
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Core point: A point is a core point if it has more than a specified number of points (MinPts) within Eps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Border point: A border point has fewer than MinPts within Eps, but is in the neighborhood of a core point.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Noise point: A noise point is any point that is neither a core point nor a border point.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8.4.2 The DBSCAN algorithm
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time and Space complexity
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The basic time complexity of the DBSCAN algorithm is O(m × time to find points in the Eps-neighborhood), where m is the number of points. In the worst case, this complexity is O(m^2). If a different data structure is used, it could be as low as O(m logm).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The space requirement is O(m).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Selection of DBSCAN Parameters
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The big question for DBSCAN is &amp;ldquo;how to determine the parameters Eps and MinPts ?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The basic approach is to look at the behavior of the distance from a point to its kth nearest neighbor(k-dist).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Usually points within cluster will have small k-dist and noise points will have large k-dist. So if we compute the k-dist for all the data points for some k, sort them in increasing order, and then plot the sorted values, we expect to see a sharp change at the value of k-dist that corresponds to a suitable value of Eps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clusters of Varying Density
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DBSCAN can have trouble with density if the density of clusters varies widely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the Eps threshold is low and if the densities vary, the denser clusters will be picked up and the dilute ones might be categorized as noise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8.4.3 Strengths and Weaknesses
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strengths
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resistant to Noise&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can handle clusters of different shapes and sizes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weaknesses
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doesn&amp;rsquo;t work well for clusters with varying densities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doesn&amp;rsquo;t work well for High-dimensional data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8.5 Cluster Evaluation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For supervised classification we have a variety of measures to evaluate how good our model is – Accuracy, precision, recall&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For cluster analysis, the analogous question is &amp;ldquo;how to evaluate &amp;lsquo;the goodness&amp;rsquo; of the resulting clusters?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The difficulty - Many times clustering is done as part of exploratory data analysis. So validation may not be needed. Also, different clustering algorithms might need different evaluation techniques - SSE might be suited for K-means but not for DBSCAN.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8.5.1 Overview
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aspects of Cluster Validation
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Determining the clustering tendency of a set of data, (distinguishing whether non-random structure actually exists in the data).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Determining the correct number of clusters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluating how well the results of a cluster analysis fit the data without reference to external information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comparing the results of a cluster analysis to externally known results, such as externally provided class labels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comparing two sets of clusters to determine which is better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Items 1, 2, and 3 do not make use of any external information - they are unsupervised techniques - while item 4 requires external information. Item 5 can be performed in either a supervised or an unsupervised manner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The evaluation measures (indices), that are applied to judge various aspects of cluster validity are traditionally classified into the following three types -
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unsupervised (Internal indices) -
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Measures the goodness of a clustering structure without referring to external information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;e.g SSE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Further divided into 2 classes - measures of cluster cohesion, cluster separation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supervised (External indices)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Measures the extent to which the clustering structure discovered by a clustering algorithm matches some external structure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;e.g Entropy (measures how well cluster labels match externally supplied class labels)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Relative
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compares different clusterings or clusters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;e.g Two K-means clusterings can be compared using either the SSE or entropy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8.5.2 Unsupervised Cluster Evaluation Using Cohesion and Separation
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cluster validity for a set of K clusters is a weighted sum of the validity of individual clusters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The validity function can be cohesion, separation or some combination of these. The weights will vary depending on the validity measure. For cohesion, higher values are better, for separation, lower values are better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graph-Based View of Cohesion and Separation
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cohesion of a cluster = sum of the weights of the links in the proximity graph that connect points within the cluster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Separation between two clusters = sum of the weights of the links from points in one cluster to points in the other cluster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The proximity function can be a similarity, a dissimilarity, or a simple function of these quantities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prototype-Based View of Cohesion and Separation
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cohesion of a cluster = sum of the proximities with respect to the prototype (centroid or medoid) of the cluster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Separation between two clusters = proximity of the two cluster prototypes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are two measures for separation because, the separation of cluster prototypes from an overall prototype is sometimes directly related to the separation of cluster prototypes from one another&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overall Measures of Cohesion and Separation
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The previous measures (cohesion &amp;amp; separation) can be combined into an overall measure of cluster validity by using a weighted sum.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Relationship between Prototype-Based Cohesion and Graph-Based Cohesion
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For some proximity measures, the measures of cohesion and separation are equivalent for Graph-based and prototype-based approaches even though they seem distinct.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For instance, for the SSE and points in Euclidean space, it can be shown that the average pairwise distance between the points in a cluster is equivalent to the SSE of the cluster&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two Approaches to Prototype-Based Separation
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When proximity is measured by Euclidean distance, the traditional measure of separation between clusters is the between group sum of squares (SSB), which is the sum of the squared distance of a cluster centroid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The higher the total SSB of a clustering, the more separated the clusters are from one another.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Relationship between Cohesion and Separation
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In some cases there is a strong relationship b/w cohesion and separation. It is possible to show that the sum of the total SSE and the total SSB is a constant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total sum of Squares (TSS) = sum of squares of the distance of each point to the overall mean of the data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TSS = SSE + SSB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The importance of this result is that minimizing SSE (cohesion) is equivalent to maximizing SSB (separation).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluating Individual Clusters and Objects
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many of the measures that we studied above can be used to evaluate individual clusters and objects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We could rank individual clusters according to their specific value of cluster validity (cohesion or separation) and make some observations -&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since higher value of cohesion may be better than lower, we could decide to split a cluster with lower value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If separation between clusters is low, we could decide to merge the clusters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Objects that contribute more to the cohesion and separation are probably near the interior of the cluster and others are probably near the edge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Silhouette Coefficient
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to compute Silhouette coefficient
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the i th object, calculate its average distance to all other objects in its cluster. Call this value ai.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the i th object and any cluster not containing the object, calculate the object&amp;rsquo;s average distance to all the objects in the given cluster. Find the minimum such value with respect to all clusters; call this value bi.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Silhouette coefficient, si = (bi − ai)/ max(ai, bi).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The value of the silhouette coefficient can vary between −1 and 1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When
$a_i = 0, s_i = 1$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8.5.3 Unsupervised Cluster Evaluation Using the Proximity Matrix
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Measuring Cluster Validity via Correlation
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Input -&amp;gt; Similarity matrix for a data set and the cluster labels from a cluster analysis of the data set.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Output -&amp;gt; Evaluate “goodness” of the clustering by looking at the correlation between the similarity matrix and the cluster labels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While computing the correlation, since the matrices are symmetric, only the correlation between n (n - 1) / 2 entries needs to be calculated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;High correlation indicates that points that belong to the same cluster are close to each other.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Judging a Clustering Visually by Its Similarity Matrix
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If we sort the rows and columns of the similarity matrix so that all objects belonging to the same class are together, then an ideal similarity matrix has a block diagonal structure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Well-separated clusters show a very strong, block- diagonal pattern in the reordered similarity matrix.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computation of the proximity matrix takes O(m ^ 2) time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8.5.4 Unsupervised Evaluation of Hierarchical Clustering
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previous approaches are for paritional clusterings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cophenetic correlation is a popular evaluation measure for hierarchical clusterings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cophenetic distance between two objects = Proximity at which an agglomerative hierarchical clustering technique puts the objects in the same cluster for the first time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The CoPhenetic Correlation Coefficient (CPCC) is the correlation between the entries of the cophenic distance matrix and the original dissimilarity matrix and is a standard measure of how well a hierarchical clustering (of a particular type) fits the data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8.5.5 Determining the Correct Number of Clusters
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plot SSE and Silhouette co-efficient for different values of k.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose k where there is a distinct knee in the SSE and a distinct peak in the silhouette coefficient&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8.5.6 Clustering Tendency
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clustering algorithms produce clusters for any input data. But can the data even be clustered ?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One approach is to evaluate the resulting clusters and only claim that a data set has clusters if at least some of the clusters are of &amp;lsquo;good&amp;rsquo; quality. To make sure that the poor quality is not due to wrong choice of algorithm, we could use multiple algorithms and again evaluate the quality of the resulting clusters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Another approach is to try to evaluate whether a data set has clusters without clustering. Most common approach, especially for data in Euclidean space, has been to use statistical tests for spatial randomness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8.5.7 Supervised Measures of Cluster Validity
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If we have external information about data, say in the form of class labels for the data objects, we could measure the degree of correspondence between the cluster labels and the class labels.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We could have different approaches to measure the extent to which two objects that are in the same class are in the same cluster.  There are 2 main approaches - classification oriented and similarity oriented.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Classification-Oriented Measures of Cluster Validity
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uses measures from classification, such as entropy, purity, and the F-measure. These measures evaluate the extent to which a cluster contains objects of a single class.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Entropy : The degree to which each cluster consists of objects of a single class&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Purity: Another measure of the extent to which a cluster contains objects of&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a single class.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Precision : The fraction of a cluster that consists of objects of a specified class.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recall : The extent to which a cluster contains all objects of a specified class.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;F-measure : A combination of both precision and recall that measures the extent to which a cluster contains only objects of a particular class and all objects of that class.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Similarity-Oriented Measures of Cluster Validity
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can view this approach to cluster validity as involving the comparison of two matrices:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(1) the ideal cluster similarity matrix discussed previously, which has a 1 if two objects are in the same cluster and 0 otherwise, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(2) an ideal class similarity matrix defined with respect to class labels, which has 1 if objects are in the same class and 0 otherwise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rand statistic and Jaccard coefficient are two of the most frequently used cluster validity measures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cluster Validity for Hierarchical Clusterings
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supervised evaluation of a hierarchical clustering is more difficult for a variety of reasons, including the fact that a preexisting hierarchical structure often does not exist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To evaluate a hierarchical clustering, we compute,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for each class, the F-measure for each cluster in the cluster hierarchy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For each class, we take the maximum F- measure attained for any cluster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, we calculate an overall F-measure for the hierarchical clustering by computing the weighted average of all per-class F-measures, where the weights are based on the class sizes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8.5.8 Assessing the Significance of Cluster Validity Measures
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do we interpret the significance of the number given by a cluster evaluation technique ?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Need to be aware of the basic definitions of evaluation measures used, like - a purity of 0 is bad, while a purity of 1 is good, an entropy of 0 is good, as is an SSE of 0.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If we don&amp;rsquo;t have an absolute standard, a common approach is to interpret the value of our validity measure in statistical terms. e.g - plotting a histogram of SSE for random data sets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow ! That was a really long chapter and took 1 full day to read through! Thanks to Tan, Steinbach and Kumar for an excellent narrative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really cannot forget this quote -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Just as people can find patterns in clouds, data mining algorithms can find clusters in random data. While it is entertaining to find patterns in clouds, it is pointless and perhaps embarrassing to find clusters in noise.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ref&lt;/strong&gt; :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Power Point slides : &lt;a href=&#34;http://www-users.cs.umn.edu/~kumar/dmbook/index.php#item4&#34;&gt;http://www-users.cs.umn.edu/~kumar/dmbook/index.php#item4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sample Chapters : &lt;a href=&#34;http://www-users.cs.umn.edu/~kumar/dmbook/index.php#item2&#34;&gt;http://www-users.cs.umn.edu/~kumar/dmbook/index.php#item2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/books/2014-02-16-datamining-tsk/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>The Spinning Melody and the Gateway</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2014-01-20-the-spinning-melody-and-gateway/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2014 16:35:56 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2014-01-20-the-spinning-melody-and-gateway/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2014-01-20-the-spinning-melody-and-gateway/ -&lt;p&gt;Reading &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Proof of Heaven&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; by Dr. Eben Alexander is almost like experiencing the NDE that he went through, to really be at the hospital with him where his loved ones were holding his hand 24/7 while he was in a coma, to be with him while he went through the underground, the gateway and the core back and forth experiencing the bright light and the melodious songs and the angelic being, to be able to hear with the whole being without anyone talking, to be able to see without physical eyes, to not have a concept of time, to feel a divine presence and be overjoyed to the fullest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t feeling well over this long weekend. Couldn&amp;rsquo;t go out because I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to spread the flu around. Couldn&amp;rsquo;t watch TV or browse the net since eyes were hurting. Couldn&amp;rsquo;t sleep because, I&amp;rsquo;d start coughing the moment I was in bed. So though of reading a book that I&amp;rsquo;d wanted to read for a couple of months. A had finished reading and told me the gist, but I wanted to read it too. So made some hot water, poured it into the flask and came upstairs to my room. Poured some hot water into a cup, opened a sachet of Emergen-C and eased myself on the beanbag with the book in one hand and cup in another. I was almost completely immersed into the book for almost two days. Slept a couple of times in the middle, refilled the cup with hot water almost mechanically, went down to have food ..etc but my mind was in the book and I completely forgot about everything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting up after finishing the book was like going into a theatre and coming out. In fact he explains that going from &amp;lsquo;the realm of the Earthworm&amp;rsquo;s eye-view&amp;rsquo; to the gateway is like coming out to the welcoming warmth of a sunny summer afternoon after being in a dark theatre for couple of hours - that experience multiplied 1000 times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is much more to write but this is one of those books where a person has to either read and engage in conversation with another who has read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some chapters had very good quotes at the beginning. I felt that the chapter headings were also good. It kind of gave an anticipation to what we might find in the chapter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A man should look for what is, and not for what he thinks should be.&amp;rdquo; — ALBERT EINSTEIN&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The true value of a human being is determined primarily by the measure and the sense in which he has attained liberation from the self.&amp;rdquo; — ALBERT EINSTEIN&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We must believe in free will. We have no choice.&amp;rdquo; — ISAAC B. SINGER&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There are two ways to be fooled. One is to believe what isn’t true; the other is to refuse to believe what is true.&amp;rdquo; — SØREN KIERKEGAARD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;And the drawing near of Death, which alike levels all, alike impresses all with a last revelation, which only an author from the dead could adequately tell.&amp;rdquo; — HERMAN MELVILLE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I maintain that the human mystery is incredibly demeaned by scientific reductionism, with its claim in promissory materialism to account eventually for all of the spiritual world in terms of patterns of neuronal activity. This belief must be classed as a superstition . . . . we have to recognize that we are spiritual beings with souls existing in a spiritual world as well as material beings with bodies and brains existing in a material world.&amp;rdquo; — SIR JOHN C. ECCLES
&amp;ldquo;There are only two ways to live your life. One is as though nothing is a miracle. The other is as if everything is.&amp;rdquo; — ALBERT EINSTEIN&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you would be a real seeker after truth, it is necessary that at least once in your life you doubt, as far as possible, all things.&amp;rdquo; — RENÉ DESCARTES&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I must be willing to give up what I am in order to become what I will be.&amp;rdquo; — ALBERT EINSTEIN&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Gratitude is not only the greatest of virtues, but the parent of all others.&amp;rdquo; — CICERO
The last chapter &amp;ldquo;The Photograph&amp;rdquo; had a very interesting twist and had an amazing poem called “When Tomorrow Starts Without Me.” by David Romano.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where to find the book to buy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;eBay : &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ebay.com/ctg/Proof-of-Heaven-A-Neurosurgeons-Journey-into-the-Afterlife-by-Eben-III-Alexander-2012-Paperback/143365475&#34;&gt;http://www.ebay.com/ctg/Proof-of-Heaven-A-Neurosurgeons-Journey-into-the-Afterlife-by-Eben-III-Alexander-2012-Paperback/143365475&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amazon : &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Proof-Heaven-Neurosurgeons-Journey-Afterlife/dp/1451695195&#34;&gt;http://www.amazon.com/Proof-Heaven-Neurosurgeons-Journey-Afterlife/dp/1451695195&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Header Image - &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Great Light A&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; by Birrell Walsh via &lt;a href=&#34;https://flic.kr/p/cw9yz&#34;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2014-01-20-the-spinning-melody-and-gateway/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Quotes</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/quotes/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/quotes/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/quotes/ -&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Nothing in the world can take the place of Persistence. Talent will not; nothing is more common than unsuccessful men with talent. Genius will not; unrewarded genius is almost a proverb. Education will not; the world is full of educated derelicts. Persistence and determination alone are omnipotent. The slogan &amp;lsquo;Press On&amp;rsquo; has solved and always will solve the problems of the human race.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;
~ &lt;strong&gt;Calvin Coolidge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Whatever you can do or dream you can, begin it. Boldness has genius, power and magic in it.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;
~ &lt;strong&gt;Goethe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t practice until you get it right. Practice until you cannot get it wrong.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;
~ &lt;strong&gt;Anonymous&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Somewhere in the world someone is training when you are not. When you race him, he will win.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;
~ &lt;strong&gt;Tom Fleming&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;A smooth sea never made a skilled sailor.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;
~ &lt;strong&gt;Anonymous&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;When you grow up you tend to get told the world is the way it is and your life is just to live your life inside the world. Try not to bash into the walls too much. Try to have a nice family, have fun, save a little money. That&amp;rsquo;s a very limited life. Life can be much broader once you discover one simple fact: Everything around you that you call life was made up by people that were no smarter than you and you can change it, you can influence it, you can build your own things that other people can use.
Once you learn that, you&amp;rsquo;ll never be the same again.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;
~ &lt;strong&gt;Steve Jobs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;If you always put limits on everything you do, physical or anything else, it will spread into your work and into your life. There are no limits. There are only plateaus, and you must not stay there, you must go beyond them.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;
~ &lt;strong&gt;Bruce Lee&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;People often become what they believe themselves to be. If I believe I cannot do something, it makes me incapable of doing it. But when I believe I can, then I acquire the ability to do it even if I didn&amp;rsquo;t have it in the beginning.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;
~ &lt;strong&gt;Mahathma Gandhi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Failure is simply the opportunity to begin again, this time more intelligently.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;
~ &lt;strong&gt;Henry Ford&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Life is not a matter of holding good cards, but of playing a poor hand well.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;
~ &lt;strong&gt;Robert L. Stevenson&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;You never know how strong you are until being strong is the only option left.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Be the change you want to see.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;
~ &lt;strong&gt;Mahatma Gandhi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;In any compromise between food and poison, it is only death that can win. In any compromise between good and evil, it is only evil that can profit.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;
~ &lt;strong&gt;Ayn Rand&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Work banishes those three great evils: boredom, vice and poverty.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;
~ &lt;strong&gt;Voltaire&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Failure is the condiment that gives success its flavor.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;
~ &lt;strong&gt;Truman Capote&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Believe in your dreams and they may come true; believe in yourself and they will come true.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;
~ &lt;strong&gt;Anonymous&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Look at the clock when you waste your time, Running in it is not pin of the clock but your life.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;
~ &lt;strong&gt;Anonymous&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Gratitude is not only the greatest of virtues, but the parent of all others.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;
~ &lt;strong&gt;Cicero&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/quotes/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>The Other World</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2009-01-11-the-other-world/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2009 17:24:36 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2009-01-11-the-other-world/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2009-01-11-the-other-world/ -&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ankle deep, he waded through the bluebells. His spirit rose and exalted&amp;hellip; as he breathed in the sun-drenched air. The glorious day was in its last decline. Long shadows lay on the sward&amp;hellip; and from above the leaves dripped their shimmering drops of gold-green light.
Moths and butterflies swarmed in merry hosts&amp;hellip; flittering here, glimmering there.
But, hush. Could that be a deer?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we were searching for &amp;ldquo;Tess of d&amp;rsquo;Urbervilles&amp;rdquo; in the library memories rushed in, almost overwhelming me.
Memories of school days when I would look at a bookshelf and see different worlds,
when Hercule Poirot and Dirk Pitt and Sherlock Holmes loomed larger than life,
when the reality of life was less real than those in books,
when my sadness and happiness and mood changes did not depend on what happened in the life I was living but in the lives of characters that I was closely following,
when even though the only place I had been to, other than Bangalore, that too occasionally, was Pathanamthitta in Kerala, I felt as thought I&amp;rsquo;d really travelled allover the world - London, New York, Paris, Venice, Rome, you name it .. and not only to the 21st century versions of foreign lands but also in the 20, and 19th and 18th and 17th and even backwards into the past even though I seemed to linger more in the 17th and18th century country side England.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen a movie that showed this more clearly than &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Howards_End&#34;&gt;Howards End&lt;/a&gt;. The passage at the beginning of this post is from the movie when Leonard Bast gets lost completely in what he is reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, why &amp;ldquo;Tess &amp;quot; ? Why were we searching for Tess ? A was channel surfing and accidentally halted at a channel which was airing &amp;ldquo;Tess of d&amp;rsquo;Urbevilles - Part 1&amp;rdquo;. Sometimes I think my zeal to tell a story runs ahead of me and I tell the important points, mainly glorifying the best aspects beyond what they are.  I&amp;rsquo;ve pumped so much of awe and mystery around my favourite novels, mostly &amp;ldquo;Kane and Abel&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;The Godfather&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;The Bourne Identity&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Atlas Shrugged&amp;rdquo; .. , that most of my friends did read them eventually. Sometimes I feel if you praise something so much, the person who is listening to you almost feels obliged to try that at least to make you happy.
But to be fair to her, she saw the movie for sometime and actually liked it. Luckily the channel did not air part 2 and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t ready to tell her the ending. Only mentioned that it was a tragedy.
For long, I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting her to read &amp;ldquo;The Return of the Native&amp;rdquo; (I think I&amp;rsquo;ve told her the story of the novel twice already) and other novels of Hardy. Afterall, he was my fav author at one time.  For now she&amp;rsquo;s said she has to read Tess. Ah ! so be it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Header Image - &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;The birthplace of Thomas Hardy at Bockhampton in Dorset&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; by Anguskirk via &lt;a href=&#34;https://flic.kr/p/fPUaC7&#34;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2009-01-11-the-other-world/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>A New Beginning</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2009-01-04-new-beginning/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2009 14:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2009-01-04-new-beginning/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2009-01-04-new-beginning/ -&lt;p&gt;More than a year whizzed past without me writing anything here.
When you&amp;rsquo;re working for a company that does more than double the work in less than half the time that the client does it in and if the client happens to be this uber-fast techie company that rolls out 8 million lines of code once every 2 weeks with almost 50K lines of code changing every week, time is a pricey quantity. It is a given !
But to get a chance to walk shoulder to shoulder with giants, ah! other concerns vanish into obscurity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a new plan. I guess one should plan things with the view that the world goes around in 8hr cycles and force oneself to get stuff done. 8 ? Why not 12 ? 8 is too less. I always aim to finish something faster than the target and finish on target. I tell A, give me 2 hrs and I&amp;rsquo;d be done with it and it might usually take 3. I used to do this every night in the initial days. &amp;ldquo;Here you go.. we&amp;rsquo;ll sleep at 12. &amp;ldquo;, &amp;ldquo;1 O clock, surely&amp;rdquo; but the offshore calls would make it slip a bit always. But now I &amp;lsquo;add the buffer&amp;rsquo; as they they during scoping times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, for a long time I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking that I&amp;rsquo;ll get up in the mornings and write at least 152 words even if they don&amp;rsquo;t mean anything.
[152 ?? See &amp;lsquo;You&amp;rsquo;ve got mail&amp;rsquo;. And it adds up to 8 ;)]
I&amp;rsquo;m particularly attached to the number 8, not because I was born on 8th, not because it can represent all the numbers and letters in the English Alphabet in the digital world, not because it symbolises infinity (tilt your head 90 degrees and look at eight), not because it represents Oxygen, not because it is connected to Music, (ah.. you see i&amp;rsquo;ve done some research on 8 ! yeah.. during my OCD college days) but because, many times things arnd me have added up to 8 and they&amp;rsquo;ve worked well for me. A, who actually knows Numerology and about all these things, keys in nature, I&amp;rsquo;d say, maintains that the number that is good for me or ppl with 8 is 4.
Well, I guess everyone goes about life, first seeking the patterns that they identify with intimately, second recognizing the pattern in all things around them and third fighting with their life to hold on to those. May be that&amp;rsquo;s why we become less broad minded as we grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve blown the dust off my writing desk, I guess and hope I can come here often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must go to the forest, To seek a new beginning. Come, &amp;lsquo;Turtles Run&amp;rsquo;.
(Apocalypto)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do I make this a multiple of 152 ? I guess it&amp;rsquo;s done !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Header Image - &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Flamingo Number Eight&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; by Gidzy via &lt;a href=&#34;https://flic.kr/p/5yAmH6&#34;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2009-01-04-new-beginning/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Write now, Right now!</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2009-01-04-write-now-right-now/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2009 01:55:42 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2009-01-04-write-now-right-now/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2009-01-04-write-now-right-now/ -&lt;p&gt;A has given me the ultimatum.
&amp;ldquo;It is too much. You&amp;rsquo;ve been fooling me for more than a year. Write now. Just 10 minutes. Whatever comes to your mind&amp;rdquo;
She&amp;rsquo;s been hitting the url for over a year expecting me to surprise her by writing something and I&amp;rsquo;ve always been saying.. I will, I will.
But more than a year of procrastination is bad I guess. At least for your loved one&amp;rsquo;s patience &amp;hellip;
It&amp;rsquo;s coming, the pasting of a new rainbow butterfly in a fresh page.. in moments.
10 minutes if you want to time it.
Go, now !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2009-01-04-write-now-right-now/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Astral Blueberries</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2007-11-13-astral-blueberries/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2007 03:19:32 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2007-11-13-astral-blueberries/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2007-11-13-astral-blueberries/ -&lt;p&gt;I’m lying flat on my back and looking at the open sky. It is clear. There are no stars. Only a single moon.
Is the queen of the night sky smiling at me ?
Or at the seabird sitting at the stern.
Or at her own beauty that is reflected by the sea ?
Well, at least I’m happy that she’s there and she’s smiling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The seabird has been sitting there, at the pointed end of the boat, quietly, for hours now. She didn’t bring the astral blueberries this time. She couldn’t have forgotten for sure. May be she gave them to others on her way, ones who yearned for them more than I did. May be she traveled too long and couldn’t bring it this far. Had I come that far? In my quest to see new places, to uncover new truths, to discover new wonders, I’d rowed faster and faster towards exotic places in the far corners of the sea. Had I gone too far ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The astral blueberries, the melodies that resonate my soul - I’ve almost forgotten their taste. Sometimes I feel I’m chewing on to one – one of those soft fleshy fruits which melt in my mouth and taste like honey .. and then suddenly wake up to find that there is nothing. I lick my lips and close my eyes – to feel the long lost taste. Renewing remembrances – those old songs – they do play a tug of war with my heart.
Ttime, time, time, take me back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A seems to always have them. How does she manage? Maybe a singer always takes them along, in a tiny chest in some unknown corner. May be a singer has a bottomless bowl of astral blueberries. She threw one at me yesterday. I bent down to pick it up and I saw three more. Quite a magic! We ate them together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m in need of them again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;I am in need of music that would flow
Over my fretful, feeling fingertips,
Over my bitter-tainted, trembling lips,
With melody, deep, clear, and liquid-slow.
Oh, for the healing swaying, old and low,
Of some song sung to rest the tired dead,
A song to fall like water on my head,
And over quivering limbs, dream flushed to glow!

There is a magic made by melody:
A spell of rest, and quiet breath, and cool
Heart, that sinks through fading colors deep
To the subaqueous stillness of the sea,
And floats forever in a moon-green pool,
Held in the arms of rhythm and of sleep.

~ Elizabeth Bishop
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Header Image - &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;astral_projection_by_tahyon&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; by tanner.marlow via &lt;a href=&#34;https://flic.kr/p/maa11d&#34;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2007-11-13-astral-blueberries/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Rainbow Butterflies</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2007-11-09-rainbow-butterflies/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2007 08:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2007-11-09-rainbow-butterflies/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2007-11-09-rainbow-butterflies/ -&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Header Image - &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Orange Sulphur in Miss Huff&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; by Vicki DeLoach via &lt;a href=&#34;https://flic.kr/p/dUyi9W&#34;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2007-11-09-rainbow-butterflies/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>A Poet&#39;s Corner</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2007-08-07-poets-corner/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2007 01:49:31 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2007-08-07-poets-corner/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2007-08-07-poets-corner/ -&lt;p&gt;Re-lived a wonderful moment when I accidentally read one of my old scribblings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I think back, there is much more to describe. Much more beyond description.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Header Image - &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;hand-carved flutes&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; by Kristen Burns via &lt;a href=&#34;https://flic.kr/p/cBiy83&#34;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2007-08-07-poets-corner/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Waking Dream</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2007-08-05-waking-dream/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2007 04:07:11 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2007-08-05-waking-dream/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2007-08-05-waking-dream/ -&lt;p&gt;In my dream I was sleeping. A was shaking my hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Achaya..wake up.. wake up.. I can’t find the books.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What books ? ”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The ones I kept in the box yesterday. The box is empty now.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Yeah, the books walked away. You ignored them for too long. You know indifference is a punishment more severe than hatred.” (Sorry. I’m sometimes sarcastic when woken up from sleep)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“He he ! stupid joke.” (clap, clap ! here is someone who doesn’t take offense.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went with her to the inner room. She was showing me the empty box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“How could it be. I’m so certain that I took all the books sprawled under the bed and put it into this box. ”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gave a sheepish smile - “I know I know.. ”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took the box in my hand and turned it upside down. Opened it from the other end. All the books were there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Wow !”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This is a magician’s box.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to show her the trapdoor and explain it to her.
But at that moment my eyes caught ‘Histories’ - Histories by Herodotus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suddenly, everything dissolved. There was no box. There was no A.
I was looking through a window into a room in which a nurse was reading this book to a burnt, faceless man on a bed. The man was recounting his past and the scenes were flashing on the wall behind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could see Katherine reading the book by a fire - time leapt forward - now Almasy is leaving the injured Katherine in a cave - is walking in the desert for days - tragedy ! - he is captured by Germans - now he is back in a glider - carries her dead body in his arms - &amp;hellip;.
It was a story in which everybody had a story - a sad story. Afterall it was a time of war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie ends with Hana reading Katherine’s words written on the margins of the last few pages of Herodotus. As Hana escapes from the monastery, Katherine&amp;rsquo;s voice is heard ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought ‘Histories’ the next day after I saw the movie, but never read it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now it’s 4 AM.
I’m awake wondering why I dreamt about &amp;lsquo;Histories&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;The English Patient&amp;rsquo;.
I’ve taken the book out of the shelf.
It’s totally unlike the worn out, dog eared one in the movie, the actual kind of books that I love to read. It is fresh and new. I’ve always loved the old books. The books which someone has read. To think that someone went through exactly the same experiences as I’m about to go through makes me happy I guess.
I’m sitting here thinking the same thoughts, feeling the same feelings, of the undercurrent of undying love in ‘The English Patient’. I close my eyes and I can see the images flashing. Can I go back to my dream now? After all, it is the dream that got me this feeling. Can I go back to the dream through this feeling?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Header Image - &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Painting of men in the Cave of the Swimmers, Wadi Sura, Gilf Kebir, Western Desert, Egypt&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; by Roland Unger via &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cave_of_Swimmers#/media/File:WadiSuraHumans.jpg&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2007-08-05-waking-dream/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>The Blue Lenses</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2007-04-19-the-blue-lenses/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2007 08:46:31 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2007-04-19-the-blue-lenses/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2007-04-19-the-blue-lenses/ -&lt;p&gt;A recent trip to Mount Shasta became more memorable due to me losing my glasses. When the optician asked me if I wanted the sunlight coating, I said yes. Well ! when someone sounds as though she’s offering the best thing in the world, you’ve got no option but to have it. Moreover insurance covered it (Insurance ! The secret American Ace). Just think of having a pair of glasses that turns black when you walk outside in sunlight and turns plain inside. Great ! I ordered one and the moment I started wearing, I didn’t like them. It looked as though I was wearing sun glasses all day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But suddenly every day was a pleasant day. Be it sunny or cloudy, the day looked the same. Set me thinking.. Why do some people always see goodness ? Because they wear sunglasses in their minds. When they look into the world, they don’t see the scorching intense heat but pleasant evening. Always.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reminds me of a duMaurier short story that I’d read sometime back - &lt;em&gt;‘The Blue Lenses’&lt;/em&gt;. The book which contains this story has another story you might’ve heard about – Birds. Yup. That famous Hitchcock movie was based on this.
Coming back, Imagine ! You suddenly turn into a person to whom the only thing that is obvious about other people are their bad attributes. You look at them and you see them as .. animals.
They talk to you and you cant talk may be because of hatred or may be dread.
That’s exactly what happens in &amp;ldquo;The blue lenses&amp;rdquo;. The main protagonist undergoes an eye operation where she is made to put on a pair of blue lenses before the actual lenses. She begins to see everyone strangely – all humans with animal heads and human bodies. One nurse has kitten’s head, the doc is a terrier, sis nancy is a snake. First she thinks it is a joke but she realizes it is not. She mentions this and gets varied responses. Mostly others are offended.
If you perceive something/someone as bad, should you tell them ? Is it because they’ve suddenly metamorphosed into something bad or your outlook has changed ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Header Image - &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Morning Calmness - San Francisco bay bridge&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; by David Yu via &lt;a href=&#34;https://flic.kr/p/raydCW&#34;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2007-04-19-the-blue-lenses/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>7 Habits of Highly Effective People by Steven Covey</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/books/2006-12-10-7-habits-highly-effective-people/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2006 10:27:11 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/books/2006-12-10-7-habits-highly-effective-people/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/books/2006-12-10-7-habits-highly-effective-people/ -&lt;p&gt;There are many books that when I think back on them, I have this lingering feeling that either due to reading quickly or not taking notes, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really take in the full essence of the book. There is more to be understood and when there is time, I need to get back to it. &amp;ldquo;7 Habits of Highly Effective People&amp;rdquo; by Steven Covey is one such book. My classmate from school, RR, was probably the first person to recommend the book to me. I have probably read the first chapter at least 5 or 6 times before I finally was able to finish reading the book around 2002 when I was working in Chennai. This is the second time I&amp;rsquo;ve read this book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is one of those books which the moment you finish reading, you will feel inspired, to do more, to yearn to lead a more fulfilling life. You will see the world in a new perspective with a feeling within you that things are more in your control than not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-1---paradigms-and-principles&#34;&gt;PART 1 - Paradigms and principles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inside-out&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;There is no real excellence in all this world which can be separated from right living.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo;
~ David Starr Jordan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Seven Habits : an overview&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;We are what we repeatedly do. Excellence, then, is not an act, but a habit.&amp;rdquo;
~ Aristotle&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-2---private-victory&#34;&gt;PART 2 - Private victory&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Habit 1 - Be Proactive&lt;/strong&gt; - Principles of personal vision&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;I know of no more encouraging fact than the unquestionable ability of man to elevate his life by conscious endeavor.&amp;rdquo;
~ Henry David Thoreau&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be proactive and have control over the outcomes rather than being reactive to everything around you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Habit 2 - Begin with the End in Mind&lt;/strong&gt;- Principles of personal leadership&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What lies behind us and what lies before us are tiny matters compared to what lies within us.&amp;rdquo;
~ Oliver Wendell Holmes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always visualize the end before starting something and this habit will help you focus better towards the goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Habit 3 - Put First Things First&lt;/strong&gt; - Principles of personal management&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Things which matter most must never be at the mercy of things which matter least.&amp;rdquo;
~ Goethe&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you begin with end in mind and start implementing things, prioritize so that you always put most important things first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-3---public-victory---paradigms-on-interdependence&#34;&gt;PART 3 - Public victory - Paradigms on interdependence&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Habit 4 - Think Win-Win&lt;/strong&gt; - Principles of interpersonal leadership&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There can be no friendship without confidence, and no confidence without integrity.&amp;rdquo; ~ Samuel Johnson
&amp;ldquo;We have committed the Golden Rule to memory; let us now commit it to life.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; ~ Edwin Markha&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Most things in life don&amp;rsquo;t have to be a zero sum game. Win-Win is based on the assumption that there is plenty for everyone, and that success follows a co-operative approach more naturally than the confrontation of win-or-lose.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Habit 5 - Seek First to Understand and then to be Understood&lt;/strong&gt; - Principles of empathic communication&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The heart has its reasons which reason knows not of.&amp;rdquo; ~ Pascal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Habit 6 - Synergize&lt;/strong&gt; - Principles of creative cooperation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I take as my guide the hope of a saint &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
in crucial things, unity &amp;ndash; &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
in important things, diversity &amp;ndash; &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
in all things, generosity&amp;rdquo;
~ Inaugural Address of President George Bush&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Synergy means that 1 + 1 may equal 8, 16, or even 1,600.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-4---renewal&#34;&gt;PART 4 - Renewal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Habit 7 - Sharpen the Saw&lt;/strong&gt; - Principles of balanced self-renewal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sometimes when I consider what tremendous consequences come from little things&amp;hellip;. I am tempted to think&amp;hellip;there are no little things.&amp;rdquo;
~ Bruce Barton&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inside-out again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Lord works from the inside out. The world works from the outside in. The world would take people out of the slums. Christ takes the slums out of people, and then they take themselves out of the slums. The world would mold men by changing their environment. Christ changes men, who then change their environment. The world would  shape human behavior, but Christ can change human nature.
~ Ezra Taft Benson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/books/2006-12-10-7-habits-highly-effective-people/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>The Spice of Life - Movies and Songs</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-08-12-spice-of-life-movies-and-songs/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2006 22:43:11 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-08-12-spice-of-life-movies-and-songs/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-08-12-spice-of-life-movies-and-songs/ -&lt;p&gt;S called. Before he started speaking, I knew what he’d say. Let’s meet up and study something. Yeah ! it’s been over a month since 2nd semester started and we hadn’t even looked into the books list. EC1 was a couple of weeks ahead. It was time.
He was in Stanford meeting up with some friend. He wanted to catch up with me in the library after lunch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;S - “Library le meet pannalam. Books list eduthuko. We’ll find them there and also plan for studying for this sem. ”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me – “Wokay. I have some work in the bank. Athu mudichittu, I’ll leave to library.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As planned, we met in the library but couldn’t find the books. They’d all been taken. After talking about textbooks for a while, the conversation just slipped into movies and songs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me - “Have you heard this song ‘Ragasiyamanadu kaadal’ ? A gem of a song. I was listening to top 10 on raaga yesterday and came upon this .. Quite accidentally”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;S - “Haven’t heard of it. New song ? Which movie ?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Kodambakkam”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“k. Have you listened to ‘New york nagaram’ ? A R Rahman is back to Tamil. He’s simply awesome. You heard his other songs ?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Sure. I love his songs.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon we were talking about movies. He’s a big time Kamal fan. So spoke about the much awaited ‘Vettayadu Vilayadu’ and old hit movies like 16 Vayathinile , Apoorva Sahodarangal, Indian …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sometime feel that talking about a movie brings the best out of a person. Being a movie buff myself, I&amp;rsquo;ve felt really happy whenever I’ve lost myself fully into a movie. A good movie is like a drug. When you’re seeing it the surrounding just disappears. Same with a good song. You could close your eyes and totally get lost in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I was listening to A R Rahman’s ‘New York Nagaram’, I thought I’d write down my top 5 movies and songs. Also, I’d been wanting to put such a list in orkut for long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://robinsonraju.info/blog/2006-08-12-top-5-movies-and-songs/&#34;&gt;Top 5 Movies and Songs List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;movies&#34;&gt;Movies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;English&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Matrix&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forrest Gump&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;T2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Saint&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Terminal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Malayalam&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thalavattam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manichittrathazhu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Veendum chila veetu kaaryangal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kireedam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sanmanassulavarku samadhanam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kannada&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ramachari&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Muthina Haara&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nammura Mandara Hoove&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rayaru bandaru mavana manege&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amruthavarshini&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hindi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sarfarosh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deewar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rang De Basanti&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anand&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ghulam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tamil&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Indian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gentleman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apoorva Sahodarangal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basha&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roja&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;songs&#34;&gt;Songs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;English&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wind of change (Scorpions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turn back time (Aqua)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tourniquet (Evanescence)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chiquitita (ABBA)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dreamy Eyes (Aguilera)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Malayalam&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pinneyum pinneyum (Krishnagudiyil oru .. )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ponveene ennullil (Thalavattam)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aayiram kannumay (Nokketha doorathu …)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kanneer poovinte (Kireedam)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ithiri poovinte (Manivathoorile aayiram sivaraathrikal)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kannada&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aakashadage(Ramachari)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jothe jotheyali (Geetha)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hindustanavu endu mareyada (Amrutha Ghalige)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cheluve nanna (Suprabhata)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manadaase Hakkiyage(Nammura Mandara Hoove)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hindi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mere rangon mei (Maine pyaar kiya)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jadoo hai tera hi jaadoo(Ghulam)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Khalbali(Rang de basanti)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pehla Nasha (Jo Jeeta Woh Sikander)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dil kya Karen (Julie)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tamil&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chinna chinna aasai(Roja)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pachai nirame(Alaipayuthey)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vaseegara(Minnale)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Onra renda(Kaaka kaaka)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ragasiyamanathu kaathal (Kodambakkam)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mal Gospel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aayiram soorya golangal onnichudichalum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mohathinte therileri pokaruthe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dukhathine paanapathram karthavente kayyil thannal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paithalam yeshuve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raathri rathri rajatha raathri&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Header Image - &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;E.T&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; by Luz Adriana Villa via &lt;a href=&#34;https://flic.kr/p/4zXjNo&#34;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-08-12-spice-of-life-movies-and-songs/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Top 5 Movies and Songs</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-08-12-top-5-movies-and-songs/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2006 22:43:11 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-08-12-top-5-movies-and-songs/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-08-12-top-5-movies-and-songs/ -&lt;h3 id=&#34;movies&#34;&gt;Movies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;English&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Matrix&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forrest Gump&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;T2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Saint&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Terminal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Malayalam&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thalavattam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manichittrathazhu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Veendum chila veetu kaaryangal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kireedam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sanmanassulavarku samadhanam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kannada&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ramachari&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Muthina Haara&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nammura Mandara Hoove&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rayaru bandaru mavana manege&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amruthavarshini&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hindi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sarfarosh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deewar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rang De Basanti&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anand&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ghulam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tamil&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Indian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gentleman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apoorva Sahodarangal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basha&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roja&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;songs&#34;&gt;Songs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;English&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wind of change (Scorpions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turn back time (Aqua)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tourniquet (Evanescence)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chiquitita (ABBA)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dreamy Eyes (Aguilera)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Malayalam&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pinneyum pinneyum (Krishnagudiyil oru .. )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ponveene ennullil (Thalavattam)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aayiram kannumay (Nokketha doorathu …)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kanneer poovinte (Kireedam)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ithiri poovinte (Manivathoorile aayiram sivaraathrikal)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kannada&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aakashadage(Ramachari)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jothe jotheyali (Geetha)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hindustanavu endu mareyada (Amrutha Ghalige)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cheluve nanna (Suprabhata)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manadaase Hakkiyage(Nammura Mandara Hoove)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hindi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mere rangon mei (Maine pyaar kiya)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jadoo hai tera hi jaadoo(Ghulam)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Khalbali(Rang de basanti)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pehla Nasha (Jo Jeeta Woh Sikander)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dil kya Karen (Julie)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tamil&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chinna chinna aasai(Roja)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pachai nirame(Alaipayuthey)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vaseegara(Minnale)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Onra renda(Kaaka kaaka)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ragasiyamanathu kaathal (Kodambakkam)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mal Gospel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aayiram soorya golangal onnichudichalum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mohathinte therileri pokaruthe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dukhathine paanapathram karthavente kayyil thannal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paithalam yeshuve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raathri rathri rajatha raathri&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Header Image - &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;E.T&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; by Luz Adriana Villa via &lt;a href=&#34;https://flic.kr/p/4zXjNo&#34;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-08-12-top-5-movies-and-songs/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Is Infinity lit ?</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-08-10-is-infinity-lit/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2006 12:02:01 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-08-10-is-infinity-lit/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-08-10-is-infinity-lit/ -&lt;p&gt;He was standing near the sun. There was brightness everywhere, almost blinding him. He could see the rays going away – far away to distant lands, giving light, feeding happiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But he couldn’t stand there for long. Some strong force was pulling him away. He clenched his teeth, tightened his muscles, held his fists in a tight grip, He tried .. to hold on for longer. It broke. But he wasn’t ready to give away, not yet. He leapt, stretched his hand and grasped a light ray. In a moment he wasn’t himself. As the luminous shaft shot ahead with break neck speed, his vision became blurred, he ceased to think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When he opened his eyes, he was far away. He was still riding on the light ray. But there was no sun, no planets in the vicinity. It was mostly dark. At a distance he could see specks of light from stars, light years away. He could feel that he wasn’t traveling as fast as he was in the beginning. Was the ray weakening ? A dread swept through him. What would happen ? Would the light die leaving him in groping in the darkness ? Without being able to see something, to hold somewhere ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It came back suddenly! The talk. That was a different time, a different age, a different place. SN was talking.
&amp;ldquo;You can see light only when it hits some object – say dust, and gets reflected. If there was no dust, no matter, i.e if there were only vacuum here, we wouldn’t see light. So, actually the universe is full of light. We cannot see it because of vacuum. In vacuum, light travels till infinity. It never reduces, never falters.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He looked down. The light ray he was traveling on, it wasn’t there ! It struck him then, there are infinite rays of light around. He just couldn’t see them. He reached his hand above and felt another ray. He jumped on to it. The traveler continued his journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Header Image - &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Infinity&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; by Phil Dolby via &lt;a href=&#34;https://flic.kr/p/yv7KFN&#34;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-08-10-is-infinity-lit/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss> 