<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rob&#39;s Notes</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.info/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Rob&#39;s Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2020 Robinson Raju</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://robinsonraju.info/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>The Spinning Melody and the Gateway</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2014-01-20-the-spinning-melody-and-gateway/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2014 16:35:56 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2014-01-20-the-spinning-melody-and-gateway/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2014-01-20-the-spinning-melody-and-gateway/ -&lt;p&gt;Reading &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Proof of Heaven&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; by Dr. Eben Alexander is almost like experiencing the NDE that he went through, to really be at the hospital with him where his loved ones were holding his hand 24/7 while he was in a coma, to be with him while he went through the underground, the gateway and the core back and forth experiencing the bright light and the melodious songs and the angelic being, to be able to hear with the whole being without anyone talking, to be able to see without physical eyes, to not have a concept of time, to feel a divine presence and be overjoyed to the fullest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t feeling well over this long weekend. Couldn&amp;rsquo;t go out because I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to spread the flu around. Couldn&amp;rsquo;t watch TV or browse the net since eyes were hurting. Couldn&amp;rsquo;t sleep because, I&amp;rsquo;d start coughing the moment I was in bed. So though of reading a book that I&amp;rsquo;d wanted to read for a couple of months. A had finished reading and told me the gist, but I wanted to read it too. So made some hot water, poured it into the flask and came upstairs to my room. Poured some hot water into a cup, opened a sachet of Emergen-C and eased myself on the beanbag with the book in one hand and cup in another. I was almost completely immersed into the book for almost two days. Slept a couple of times in the middle, refilled the cup with hot water almost mechanically, went down to have food ..etc but my mind was in the book and I completely forgot about everything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting up after finishing the book was like going into a theatre and coming out. In fact he explains that going from &amp;lsquo;the realm of the Earthworm&amp;rsquo;s eye-view&amp;rsquo; to the gateway is like coming out to the welcoming warmth of a sunny summer afternoon after being in a dark theatre for couple of hours - that experience multiplied 1000 times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is much more to write but this is one of those books where a person has to either read and engage in conversation with another who has read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some chapters had very good quotes at the beginning. I felt that the chapter headings were also good. It kind of gave an anticipation to what we might find in the chapter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A man should look for what is, and not for what he thinks should be.&amp;rdquo; — ALBERT EINSTEIN&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The true value of a human being is determined primarily by the measure and the sense in which he has attained liberation from the self.&amp;rdquo; — ALBERT EINSTEIN&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We must believe in free will. We have no choice.&amp;rdquo; — ISAAC B. SINGER&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There are two ways to be fooled. One is to believe what isn’t true; the other is to refuse to believe what is true.&amp;rdquo; — SØREN KIERKEGAARD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;And the drawing near of Death, which alike levels all, alike impresses all with a last revelation, which only an author from the dead could adequately tell.&amp;rdquo; — HERMAN MELVILLE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I maintain that the human mystery is incredibly demeaned by scientific reductionism, with its claim in promissory materialism to account eventually for all of the spiritual world in terms of patterns of neuronal activity. This belief must be classed as a superstition . . . . we have to recognize that we are spiritual beings with souls existing in a spiritual world as well as material beings with bodies and brains existing in a material world.&amp;rdquo; — SIR JOHN C. ECCLES
&amp;ldquo;There are only two ways to live your life. One is as though nothing is a miracle. The other is as if everything is.&amp;rdquo; — ALBERT EINSTEIN&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you would be a real seeker after truth, it is necessary that at least once in your life you doubt, as far as possible, all things.&amp;rdquo; — RENÉ DESCARTES&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I must be willing to give up what I am in order to become what I will be.&amp;rdquo; — ALBERT EINSTEIN&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Gratitude is not only the greatest of virtues, but the parent of all others.&amp;rdquo; — CICERO
The last chapter &amp;ldquo;The Photograph&amp;rdquo; had a very interesting twist and had an amazing poem called “When Tomorrow Starts Without Me.” by David Romano.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where to find the book to buy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;eBay : &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ebay.com/ctg/Proof-of-Heaven-A-Neurosurgeons-Journey-into-the-Afterlife-by-Eben-III-Alexander-2012-Paperback/143365475&#34;&gt;http://www.ebay.com/ctg/Proof-of-Heaven-A-Neurosurgeons-Journey-into-the-Afterlife-by-Eben-III-Alexander-2012-Paperback/143365475&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amazon : &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Proof-Heaven-Neurosurgeons-Journey-Afterlife/dp/1451695195&#34;&gt;http://www.amazon.com/Proof-Heaven-Neurosurgeons-Journey-Afterlife/dp/1451695195&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Header Image - &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Great Light A&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; by Birrell Walsh via &lt;a href=&#34;https://flic.kr/p/cw9yz&#34;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2014-01-20-the-spinning-melody-and-gateway/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Quotes</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/quotes/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/quotes/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/quotes/ -&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Nothing in the world can take the place of Persistence. Talent will not; nothing is more common than unsuccessful men with talent. Genius will not; unrewarded genius is almost a proverb. Education will not; the world is full of educated derelicts. Persistence and determination alone are omnipotent. The slogan &amp;lsquo;Press On&amp;rsquo; has solved and always will solve the problems of the human race.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;
~ &lt;strong&gt;Calvin Coolidge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Whatever you can do or dream you can, begin it. Boldness has genius, power and magic in it.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;
~ &lt;strong&gt;Goethe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t practice until you get it right. Practice until you cannot get it wrong.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;
~ &lt;strong&gt;Anonymous&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Somewhere in the world someone is training when you are not. When you race him, he will win.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;
~ &lt;strong&gt;Tom Fleming&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;A smooth sea never made a skilled sailor.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;
~ &lt;strong&gt;Anonymous&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;When you grow up you tend to get told the world is the way it is and your life is just to live your life inside the world. Try not to bash into the walls too much. Try to have a nice family, have fun, save a little money. That&amp;rsquo;s a very limited life. Life can be much broader once you discover one simple fact: Everything around you that you call life was made up by people that were no smarter than you and you can change it, you can influence it, you can build your own things that other people can use.
Once you learn that, you&amp;rsquo;ll never be the same again.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;
~ &lt;strong&gt;Steve Jobs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;If you always put limits on everything you do, physical or anything else, it will spread into your work and into your life. There are no limits. There are only plateaus, and you must not stay there, you must go beyond them.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;
~ &lt;strong&gt;Bruce Lee&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;People often become what they believe themselves to be. If I believe I cannot do something, it makes me incapable of doing it. But when I believe I can, then I acquire the ability to do it even if I didn&amp;rsquo;t have it in the beginning.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;
~ &lt;strong&gt;Mahathma Gandhi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Failure is simply the opportunity to begin again, this time more intelligently.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;
~ &lt;strong&gt;Henry Ford&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Life is not a matter of holding good cards, but of playing a poor hand well.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;
~ &lt;strong&gt;Robert L. Stevenson&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;You never know how strong you are until being strong is the only option left.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Be the change you want to see.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;
~ &lt;strong&gt;Mahatma Gandhi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;In any compromise between food and poison, it is only death that can win. In any compromise between good and evil, it is only evil that can profit.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;
~ &lt;strong&gt;Ayn Rand&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Work banishes those three great evils: boredom, vice and poverty.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;
~ &lt;strong&gt;Voltaire&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Failure is the condiment that gives success its flavor.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;
~ &lt;strong&gt;Truman Capote&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Believe in your dreams and they may come true; believe in yourself and they will come true.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;
~ &lt;strong&gt;Anonymous&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Look at the clock when you waste your time, Running in it is not pin of the clock but your life.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;
~ &lt;strong&gt;Anonymous&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Gratitude is not only the greatest of virtues, but the parent of all others.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;
~ &lt;strong&gt;Cicero&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/quotes/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>The Other World</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2009-01-11-the-other-world/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2009 17:24:36 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2009-01-11-the-other-world/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2009-01-11-the-other-world/ -&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ankle deep, he waded through the bluebells. His spirit rose and exalted&amp;hellip; as he breathed in the sun-drenched air. The glorious day was in its last decline. Long shadows lay on the sward&amp;hellip; and from above the leaves dripped their shimmering drops of gold-green light.
Moths and butterflies swarmed in merry hosts&amp;hellip; flittering here, glimmering there.
But, hush. Could that be a deer?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we were searching for &amp;ldquo;Tess of d&amp;rsquo;Urbervilles&amp;rdquo; in the library memories rushed in, almost overwhelming me.
Memories of school days when I would look at a bookshelf and see different worlds,
when Hercule Poirot and Dirk Pitt and Sherlock Holmes loomed larger than life,
when the reality of life was less real than those in books,
when my sadness and happiness and mood changes did not depend on what happened in the life I was living but in the lives of characters that I was closely following,
when even though the only place I had been to, other than Bangalore, that too occasionally, was Pathanamthitta in Kerala, I felt as thought I&amp;rsquo;d really travelled allover the world - London, New York, Paris, Venice, Rome, you name it .. and not only to the 21st century versions of foreign lands but also in the 20, and 19th and 18th and 17th and even backwards into the past even though I seemed to linger more in the 17th and18th century country side England.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen a movie that showed this more clearly than &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Howards_End&#34;&gt;Howards End&lt;/a&gt;. The passage at the beginning of this post is from the movie when Leonard Bast gets lost completely in what he is reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, why &amp;ldquo;Tess &amp;quot; ? Why were we searching for Tess ? A was channel surfing and accidentally halted at a channel which was airing &amp;ldquo;Tess of d&amp;rsquo;Urbevilles - Part 1&amp;rdquo;. Sometimes I think my zeal to tell a story runs ahead of me and I tell the important points, mainly glorifying the best aspects beyond what they are.  I&amp;rsquo;ve pumped so much of awe and mystery around my favourite novels, mostly &amp;ldquo;Kane and Abel&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;The Godfather&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;The Bourne Identity&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Atlas Shrugged&amp;rdquo; .. , that most of my friends did read them eventually. Sometimes I feel if you praise something so much, the person who is listening to you almost feels obliged to try that at least to make you happy.
But to be fair to her, she saw the movie for sometime and actually liked it. Luckily the channel did not air part 2 and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t ready to tell her the ending. Only mentioned that it was a tragedy.
For long, I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting her to read &amp;ldquo;The Return of the Native&amp;rdquo; (I think I&amp;rsquo;ve told her the story of the novel twice already) and other novels of Hardy. Afterall, he was my fav author at one time.  For now she&amp;rsquo;s said she has to read Tess. Ah ! so be it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Header Image - &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;The birthplace of Thomas Hardy at Bockhampton in Dorset&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; by Anguskirk via &lt;a href=&#34;https://flic.kr/p/fPUaC7&#34;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2009-01-11-the-other-world/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>A New Beginning</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2009-01-04-new-beginning/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2009 14:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2009-01-04-new-beginning/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2009-01-04-new-beginning/ -&lt;p&gt;More than a year whizzed past without me writing anything here.
When you&amp;rsquo;re working for a company that does more than double the work in less than half the time that the client does it in and if the client happens to be this uber-fast techie company that rolls out 8 million lines of code once every 2 weeks with almost 50K lines of code changing every week, time is a pricey quantity. It is a given !
But to get a chance to walk shoulder to shoulder with giants, ah! other concerns vanish into obscurity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a new plan. I guess one should plan things with the view that the world goes around in 8hr cycles and force oneself to get stuff done. 8 ? Why not 12 ? 8 is too less. I always aim to finish something faster than the target and finish on target. I tell A, give me 2 hrs and I&amp;rsquo;d be done with it and it might usually take 3. I used to do this every night in the initial days. &amp;ldquo;Here you go.. we&amp;rsquo;ll sleep at 12. &amp;ldquo;, &amp;ldquo;1 O clock, surely&amp;rdquo; but the offshore calls would make it slip a bit always. But now I &amp;lsquo;add the buffer&amp;rsquo; as they they during scoping times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, for a long time I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking that I&amp;rsquo;ll get up in the mornings and write at least 152 words even if they don&amp;rsquo;t mean anything.
[152 ?? See &amp;lsquo;You&amp;rsquo;ve got mail&amp;rsquo;. And it adds up to 8 ;)]
I&amp;rsquo;m particularly attached to the number 8, not because I was born on 8th, not because it can represent all the numbers and letters in the English Alphabet in the digital world, not because it symbolises infinity (tilt your head 90 degrees and look at eight), not because it represents Oxygen, not because it is connected to Music, (ah.. you see i&amp;rsquo;ve done some research on 8 ! yeah.. during my OCD college days) but because, many times things arnd me have added up to 8 and they&amp;rsquo;ve worked well for me. A, who actually knows Numerology and about all these things, keys in nature, I&amp;rsquo;d say, maintains that the number that is good for me or ppl with 8 is 4.
Well, I guess everyone goes about life, first seeking the patterns that they identify with intimately, second recognizing the pattern in all things around them and third fighting with their life to hold on to those. May be that&amp;rsquo;s why we become less broad minded as we grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve blown the dust off my writing desk, I guess and hope I can come here often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must go to the forest, To seek a new beginning. Come, &amp;lsquo;Turtles Run&amp;rsquo;.
(Apocalypto)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do I make this a multiple of 152 ? I guess it&amp;rsquo;s done !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Header Image - &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Flamingo Number Eight&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; by Gidzy via &lt;a href=&#34;https://flic.kr/p/5yAmH6&#34;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2009-01-04-new-beginning/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Write now, Right now!</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2009-01-04-write-now-right-now/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2009 01:55:42 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2009-01-04-write-now-right-now/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2009-01-04-write-now-right-now/ -&lt;p&gt;A has given me the ultimatum.
&amp;ldquo;It is too much. You&amp;rsquo;ve been fooling me for more than a year. Write now. Just 10 minutes. Whatever comes to your mind&amp;rdquo;
She&amp;rsquo;s been hitting the url for over a year expecting me to surprise her by writing something and I&amp;rsquo;ve always been saying.. I will, I will.
But more than a year of procrastination is bad I guess. At least for your loved one&amp;rsquo;s patience &amp;hellip;
It&amp;rsquo;s coming, the pasting of a new rainbow butterfly in a fresh page.. in moments.
10 minutes if you want to time it.
Go, now !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2009-01-04-write-now-right-now/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Astral Blueberries</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2007-11-13-astral-blueberries/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2007 03:19:32 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2007-11-13-astral-blueberries/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2007-11-13-astral-blueberries/ -&lt;p&gt;I’m lying flat on my back and looking at the open sky. It is clear. There are no stars. Only a single moon.
Is the queen of the night sky smiling at me ?
Or at the seabird sitting at the stern.
Or at her own beauty that is reflected by the sea ?
Well, at least I’m happy that she’s there and she’s smiling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The seabird has been sitting there, at the pointed end of the boat, quietly, for hours now. She didn’t bring the astral blueberries this time. She couldn’t have forgotten for sure. May be she gave them to others on her way, ones who yearned for them more than I did. May be she traveled too long and couldn’t bring it this far. Had I come that far? In my quest to see new places, to uncover new truths, to discover new wonders, I’d rowed faster and faster towards exotic places in the far corners of the sea. Had I gone too far ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The astral blueberries, the melodies that resonate my soul - I’ve almost forgotten their taste. Sometimes I feel I’m chewing on to one – one of those soft fleshy fruits which melt in my mouth and taste like honey .. and then suddenly wake up to find that there is nothing. I lick my lips and close my eyes – to feel the long lost taste. Renewing remembrances – those old songs – they do play a tug of war with my heart.
Ttime, time, time, take me back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A seems to always have them. How does she manage? Maybe a singer always takes them along, in a tiny chest in some unknown corner. May be a singer has a bottomless bowl of astral blueberries. She threw one at me yesterday. I bent down to pick it up and I saw three more. Quite a magic! We ate them together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m in need of them again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;I am in need of music that would flow
Over my fretful, feeling fingertips,
Over my bitter-tainted, trembling lips,
With melody, deep, clear, and liquid-slow.
Oh, for the healing swaying, old and low,
Of some song sung to rest the tired dead,
A song to fall like water on my head,
And over quivering limbs, dream flushed to glow!

There is a magic made by melody:
A spell of rest, and quiet breath, and cool
Heart, that sinks through fading colors deep
To the subaqueous stillness of the sea,
And floats forever in a moon-green pool,
Held in the arms of rhythm and of sleep.

~ Elizabeth Bishop
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Header Image - &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;astral_projection_by_tahyon&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; by tanner.marlow via &lt;a href=&#34;https://flic.kr/p/maa11d&#34;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2007-11-13-astral-blueberries/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Rainbow Butterflies</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2007-11-09-rainbow-butterflies/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2007 08:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2007-11-09-rainbow-butterflies/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2007-11-09-rainbow-butterflies/ -&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Header Image - &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Orange Sulphur in Miss Huff&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; by Vicki DeLoach via &lt;a href=&#34;https://flic.kr/p/dUyi9W&#34;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2007-11-09-rainbow-butterflies/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>A Poet&#39;s Corner</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2007-08-07-poets-corner/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2007 01:49:31 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2007-08-07-poets-corner/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2007-08-07-poets-corner/ -&lt;p&gt;Re-lived a wonderful moment when I accidentally read one of my old scribblings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I think back, there is much more to describe. Much more beyond description.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Header Image - &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;hand-carved flutes&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; by Kristen Burns via &lt;a href=&#34;https://flic.kr/p/cBiy83&#34;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2007-08-07-poets-corner/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Waking Dream</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2007-08-05-waking-dream/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2007 04:07:11 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2007-08-05-waking-dream/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2007-08-05-waking-dream/ -&lt;p&gt;In my dream I was sleeping. A was shaking my hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Achaya..wake up.. wake up.. I can’t find the books.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What books ? ”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The ones I kept in the box yesterday. The box is empty now.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Yeah, the books walked away. You ignored them for too long. You know indifference is a punishment more severe than hatred.” (Sorry. I’m sometimes sarcastic when woken up from sleep)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“He he ! stupid joke.” (clap, clap ! here is someone who doesn’t take offense.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went with her to the inner room. She was showing me the empty box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“How could it be. I’m so certain that I took all the books sprawled under the bed and put it into this box. ”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gave a sheepish smile - “I know I know.. ”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took the box in my hand and turned it upside down. Opened it from the other end. All the books were there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Wow !”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This is a magician’s box.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to show her the trapdoor and explain it to her.
But at that moment my eyes caught ‘Histories’ - Histories by Herodotus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suddenly, everything dissolved. There was no box. There was no A.
I was looking through a window into a room in which a nurse was reading this book to a burnt, faceless man on a bed. The man was recounting his past and the scenes were flashing on the wall behind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could see Katherine reading the book by a fire - time leapt forward - now Almasy is leaving the injured Katherine in a cave - is walking in the desert for days - tragedy ! - he is captured by Germans - now he is back in a glider - carries her dead body in his arms - &amp;hellip;.
It was a story in which everybody had a story - a sad story. Afterall it was a time of war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie ends with Hana reading Katherine’s words written on the margins of the last few pages of Herodotus. As Hana escapes from the monastery, Katherine&amp;rsquo;s voice is heard ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought ‘Histories’ the next day after I saw the movie, but never read it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now it’s 4 AM.
I’m awake wondering why I dreamt about &amp;lsquo;Histories&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;The English Patient&amp;rsquo;.
I’ve taken the book out of the shelf.
It’s totally unlike the worn out, dog eared one in the movie, the actual kind of books that I love to read. It is fresh and new. I’ve always loved the old books. The books which someone has read. To think that someone went through exactly the same experiences as I’m about to go through makes me happy I guess.
I’m sitting here thinking the same thoughts, feeling the same feelings, of the undercurrent of undying love in ‘The English Patient’. I close my eyes and I can see the images flashing. Can I go back to my dream now? After all, it is the dream that got me this feeling. Can I go back to the dream through this feeling?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Header Image - &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Painting of men in the Cave of the Swimmers, Wadi Sura, Gilf Kebir, Western Desert, Egypt&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; by Roland Unger via &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cave_of_Swimmers#/media/File:WadiSuraHumans.jpg&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2007-08-05-waking-dream/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>The Blue Lenses</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2007-04-19-the-blue-lenses/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2007 08:46:31 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2007-04-19-the-blue-lenses/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2007-04-19-the-blue-lenses/ -&lt;p&gt;A recent trip to Mount Shasta became more memorable due to me losing my glasses. When the optician asked me if I wanted the sunlight coating, I said yes. Well ! when someone sounds as though she’s offering the best thing in the world, you’ve got no option but to have it. Moreover insurance covered it (Insurance ! The secret American Ace). Just think of having a pair of glasses that turns black when you walk outside in sunlight and turns plain inside. Great ! I ordered one and the moment I started wearing, I didn’t like them. It looked as though I was wearing sun glasses all day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But suddenly every day was a pleasant day. Be it sunny or cloudy, the day looked the same. Set me thinking.. Why do some people always see goodness ? Because they wear sunglasses in their minds. When they look into the world, they don’t see the scorching intense heat but pleasant evening. Always.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reminds me of a duMaurier short story that I’d read sometime back - &lt;em&gt;‘The Blue Lenses’&lt;/em&gt;. The book which contains this story has another story you might’ve heard about – Birds. Yup. That famous Hitchcock movie was based on this.
Coming back, Imagine ! You suddenly turn into a person to whom the only thing that is obvious about other people are their bad attributes. You look at them and you see them as .. animals.
They talk to you and you cant talk may be because of hatred or may be dread.
That’s exactly what happens in &amp;ldquo;The blue lenses&amp;rdquo;. The main protagonist undergoes an eye operation where she is made to put on a pair of blue lenses before the actual lenses. She begins to see everyone strangely – all humans with animal heads and human bodies. One nurse has kitten’s head, the doc is a terrier, sis nancy is a snake. First she thinks it is a joke but she realizes it is not. She mentions this and gets varied responses. Mostly others are offended.
If you perceive something/someone as bad, should you tell them ? Is it because they’ve suddenly metamorphosed into something bad or your outlook has changed ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Header Image - &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Morning Calmness - San Francisco bay bridge&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; by David Yu via &lt;a href=&#34;https://flic.kr/p/raydCW&#34;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2007-04-19-the-blue-lenses/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>7 Habits of Highly Effective People by Steven Covey</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-12-10-7-habits-highly-effective-people/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2006 10:27:11 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-12-10-7-habits-highly-effective-people/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-12-10-7-habits-highly-effective-people/ -&lt;p&gt;There are many books that when I think back on them, I have this lingering feeling that either due to reading quickly or not taking notes, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really take in the full essence of the book. There is more to be understood and when there is time, I need to get back to it. &amp;ldquo;7 Habits of Highly Effective People&amp;rdquo; by Steven Covey is one such book. My classmate from school, RR, was probably the first person to recommend the book to me. I have probably read the first chapter at least 5 or 6 times before I finally was able to finish reading the book around 2002 when I was working in Chennai. This is the second time I&amp;rsquo;ve read this book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is one of those books which the moment you finish reading, you will feel inspired, to do more, to yearn to lead a more fulfilling life. You will see the world in a new perspective with a feeling within you that things are more in your control than not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-1---paradigms-and-principles&#34;&gt;PART 1 - Paradigms and principles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inside-out&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;There is no real excellence in all this world which can be separated from right living.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo;
~ David Starr Jordan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Seven Habits : an overview&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;We are what we repeatedly do. Excellence, then, is not an act, but a habit.&amp;rdquo;
~ Aristotle&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-2---private-victory&#34;&gt;PART 2 - Private victory&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Habit 1 - Be Proactive&lt;/strong&gt; - Principles of personal vision&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;I know of no more encouraging fact than the unquestionable ability of man to elevate his life by conscious endeavor.&amp;rdquo;
~ Henry David Thoreau&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be proactive and have control over the outcomes rather than being reactive to everything around you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Habit 2 - Begin with the End in Mind&lt;/strong&gt;- Principles of personal leadership&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What lies behind us and what lies before us are tiny matters compared to what lies within us.&amp;rdquo;
~ Oliver Wendell Holmes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always visualize the end before starting something and this habit will help you focus better towards the goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Habit 3 - Put First Things First&lt;/strong&gt; - Principles of personal management&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Things which matter most must never be at the mercy of things which matter least.&amp;rdquo;
~ Goethe&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you begin with end in mind and start implementing things, prioritize so that you always put most important things first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-3---public-victory---paradigms-on-interdependence&#34;&gt;PART 3 - Public victory - Paradigms on interdependence&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Habit 4 - Think Win-Win&lt;/strong&gt; - Principles of interpersonal leadership&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There can be no friendship without confidence, and no confidence without integrity.&amp;rdquo; ~ Samuel Johnson
&amp;ldquo;We have committed the Golden Rule to memory; let us now commit it to life.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; ~ Edwin Markha&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Most things in life don&amp;rsquo;t have to be a zero sum game. Win-Win is based on the assumption that there is plenty for everyone, and that success follows a co-operative approach more naturally than the confrontation of win-or-lose.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Habit 5 - Seek First to Understand and then to be Understood&lt;/strong&gt; - Principles of empathic communication&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The heart has its reasons which reason knows not of.&amp;rdquo; ~ Pascal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Habit 6 - Synergize&lt;/strong&gt; - Principles of creative cooperation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I take as my guide the hope of a saint &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
in crucial things, unity &amp;ndash; &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
in important things, diversity &amp;ndash; &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
in all things, generosity&amp;rdquo;
~ Inaugural Address of President George Bush&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Synergy means that 1 + 1 may equal 8, 16, or even 1,600.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-4---renewal&#34;&gt;PART 4 - Renewal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Habit 7 - Sharpen the Saw&lt;/strong&gt; - Principles of balanced self-renewal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sometimes when I consider what tremendous consequences come from little things&amp;hellip;. I am tempted to think&amp;hellip;there are no little things.&amp;rdquo;
~ Bruce Barton&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inside-out again&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Lord works from the inside out. The world works from the outside in. The world would take people out of the slums. Christ takes the slums out of people, and then they take themselves out of the slums. The world would mold men by changing their environment. Christ changes men, who then change their environment. The world would  shape human behavior, but Christ can change human nature.
~ Ezra Taft Benson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-12-10-7-habits-highly-effective-people/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>The Spice of Life - Movies and Songs</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-08-12-spice-of-life-movies-and-songs/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2006 22:43:11 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-08-12-spice-of-life-movies-and-songs/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-08-12-spice-of-life-movies-and-songs/ -&lt;p&gt;S called. Before he started speaking, I knew what he’d say. Let’s meet up and study something. Yeah ! it’s been over a month since 2nd semester started and we hadn’t even looked into the books list. EC1 was a couple of weeks ahead. It was time.
He was in Stanford meeting up with some friend. He wanted to catch up with me in the library after lunch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;S - “Library le meet pannalam. Books list eduthuko. We’ll find them there and also plan for studying for this sem. ”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me – “Wokay. I have some work in the bank. Athu mudichittu, I’ll leave to library.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As planned, we met in the library but couldn’t find the books. They’d all been taken. After talking about textbooks for a while, the conversation just slipped into movies and songs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me - “Have you heard this song ‘Ragasiyamanadu kaadal’ ? A gem of a song. I was listening to top 10 on raaga yesterday and came upon this .. Quite accidentally”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;S - “Haven’t heard of it. New song ? Which movie ?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Kodambakkam”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“k. Have you listened to ‘New york nagaram’ ? A R Rahman is back to Tamil. He’s simply awesome. You heard his other songs ?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Sure. I love his songs.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon we were talking about movies. He’s a big time Kamal fan. So spoke about the much awaited ‘Vettayadu Vilayadu’ and old hit movies like 16 Vayathinile , Apoorva Sahodarangal, Indian …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sometime feel that talking about a movie brings the best out of a person. Being a movie buff myself, I&amp;rsquo;ve felt really happy whenever I’ve lost myself fully into a movie. A good movie is like a drug. When you’re seeing it the surrounding just disappears. Same with a good song. You could close your eyes and totally get lost in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I was listening to A R Rahman’s ‘New York Nagaram’, I thought I’d write down my top 5 movies and songs. Also, I’d been wanting to put such a list in orkut for long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://robinsonraju.info/blog/2006-08-12-top-5-movies-and-songs/&#34;&gt;Top 5 Movies and Songs List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;movies&#34;&gt;Movies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;English&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Matrix&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forrest Gump&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;T2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Saint&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Terminal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Malayalam&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thalavattam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manichittrathazhu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Veendum chila veetu kaaryangal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kireedam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sanmanassulavarku samadhanam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kannada&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ramachari&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Muthina Haara&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nammura Mandara Hoove&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rayaru bandaru mavana manege&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amruthavarshini&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hindi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sarfarosh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deewar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rang De Basanti&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anand&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ghulam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tamil&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Indian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gentleman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apoorva Sahodarangal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basha&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roja&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;songs&#34;&gt;Songs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;English&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wind of change (Scorpions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turn back time (Aqua)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tourniquet (Evanescence)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chiquitita (ABBA)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dreamy Eyes (Aguilera)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Malayalam&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pinneyum pinneyum (Krishnagudiyil oru .. )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ponveene ennullil (Thalavattam)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aayiram kannumay (Nokketha doorathu …)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kanneer poovinte (Kireedam)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ithiri poovinte (Manivathoorile aayiram sivaraathrikal)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kannada&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aakashadage(Ramachari)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jothe jotheyali (Geetha)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hindustanavu endu mareyada (Amrutha Ghalige)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cheluve nanna (Suprabhata)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manadaase Hakkiyage(Nammura Mandara Hoove)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hindi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mere rangon mei (Maine pyaar kiya)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jadoo hai tera hi jaadoo(Ghulam)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Khalbali(Rang de basanti)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pehla Nasha (Jo Jeeta Woh Sikander)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dil kya Karen (Julie)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tamil&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chinna chinna aasai(Roja)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pachai nirame(Alaipayuthey)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vaseegara(Minnale)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Onra renda(Kaaka kaaka)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ragasiyamanathu kaathal (Kodambakkam)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mal Gospel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aayiram soorya golangal onnichudichalum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mohathinte therileri pokaruthe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dukhathine paanapathram karthavente kayyil thannal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paithalam yeshuve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raathri rathri rajatha raathri&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Header Image - &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;E.T&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; by Luz Adriana Villa via &lt;a href=&#34;https://flic.kr/p/4zXjNo&#34;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-08-12-spice-of-life-movies-and-songs/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Top 5 Movies and Songs</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-08-12-top-5-movies-and-songs/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2006 22:43:11 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-08-12-top-5-movies-and-songs/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-08-12-top-5-movies-and-songs/ -&lt;h3 id=&#34;movies&#34;&gt;Movies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;English&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Matrix&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forrest Gump&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;T2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Saint&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Terminal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Malayalam&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thalavattam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manichittrathazhu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Veendum chila veetu kaaryangal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kireedam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sanmanassulavarku samadhanam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kannada&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ramachari&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Muthina Haara&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nammura Mandara Hoove&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rayaru bandaru mavana manege&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amruthavarshini&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hindi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sarfarosh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deewar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rang De Basanti&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anand&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ghulam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tamil&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Indian&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gentleman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apoorva Sahodarangal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basha&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Roja&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;songs&#34;&gt;Songs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;English&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wind of change (Scorpions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turn back time (Aqua)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tourniquet (Evanescence)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chiquitita (ABBA)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dreamy Eyes (Aguilera)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Malayalam&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pinneyum pinneyum (Krishnagudiyil oru .. )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ponveene ennullil (Thalavattam)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aayiram kannumay (Nokketha doorathu …)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kanneer poovinte (Kireedam)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ithiri poovinte (Manivathoorile aayiram sivaraathrikal)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kannada&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aakashadage(Ramachari)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jothe jotheyali (Geetha)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hindustanavu endu mareyada (Amrutha Ghalige)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cheluve nanna (Suprabhata)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manadaase Hakkiyage(Nammura Mandara Hoove)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hindi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mere rangon mei (Maine pyaar kiya)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jadoo hai tera hi jaadoo(Ghulam)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Khalbali(Rang de basanti)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pehla Nasha (Jo Jeeta Woh Sikander)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dil kya Karen (Julie)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tamil&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chinna chinna aasai(Roja)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pachai nirame(Alaipayuthey)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vaseegara(Minnale)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Onra renda(Kaaka kaaka)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ragasiyamanathu kaathal (Kodambakkam)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mal Gospel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aayiram soorya golangal onnichudichalum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mohathinte therileri pokaruthe&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dukhathine paanapathram karthavente kayyil thannal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paithalam yeshuve&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raathri rathri rajatha raathri&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Header Image - &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;E.T&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; by Luz Adriana Villa via &lt;a href=&#34;https://flic.kr/p/4zXjNo&#34;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-08-12-top-5-movies-and-songs/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Is Infinity lit ?</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-08-10-is-infinity-lit/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2006 12:02:01 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-08-10-is-infinity-lit/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-08-10-is-infinity-lit/ -&lt;p&gt;He was standing near the sun. There was brightness everywhere, almost blinding him. He could see the rays going away – far away to distant lands, giving light, feeding happiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But he couldn’t stand there for long. Some strong force was pulling him away. He clenched his teeth, tightened his muscles, held his fists in a tight grip, He tried .. to hold on for longer. It broke. But he wasn’t ready to give away, not yet. He leapt, stretched his hand and grasped a light ray. In a moment he wasn’t himself. As the luminous shaft shot ahead with break neck speed, his vision became blurred, he ceased to think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When he opened his eyes, he was far away. He was still riding on the light ray. But there was no sun, no planets in the vicinity. It was mostly dark. At a distance he could see specks of light from stars, light years away. He could feel that he wasn’t traveling as fast as he was in the beginning. Was the ray weakening ? A dread swept through him. What would happen ? Would the light die leaving him in groping in the darkness ? Without being able to see something, to hold somewhere ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It came back suddenly! The talk. That was a different time, a different age, a different place. SN was talking.
&amp;ldquo;You can see light only when it hits some object – say dust, and gets reflected. If there was no dust, no matter, i.e if there were only vacuum here, we wouldn’t see light. So, actually the universe is full of light. We cannot see it because of vacuum. In vacuum, light travels till infinity. It never reduces, never falters.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He looked down. The light ray he was traveling on, it wasn’t there ! It struck him then, there are infinite rays of light around. He just couldn’t see them. He reached his hand above and felt another ray. He jumped on to it. The traveler continued his journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Header Image - &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Infinity&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; by Phil Dolby via &lt;a href=&#34;https://flic.kr/p/yv7KFN&#34;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-08-10-is-infinity-lit/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>The destruction of Sennacherib</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-07-05-destruction-of-sennacherib/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2006 02:05:33 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-07-05-destruction-of-sennacherib/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-07-05-destruction-of-sennacherib/ -&lt;p&gt;Some days you get up slowly ..&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
sit or sometimes sit n sleep on the bed for sometime ..&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
wait for thoughts to gather, slowly come into terms with the world – as though you need time to gradually transition from one world to completely different one – as though you just came out of water and you’re gasping for breath.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, Some other days you get up with a jerk – immediately springing into action – as though the very reason that you got up was to do that . It’s as though you’ve been awake all along but had just closed your eyes temporarily..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today was one of those ‘some other’ days.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
It was a holiday but I just got up and immediately wanted to check out ‘the destruction of Sennacherib’. I wanted to read the Biblical passage which mentioned this incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This out-of-ordinary behavior was because just yesterday I started with this book named &amp;ldquo;Familiar Poems, Annotated&amp;rdquo; by Asimov.
For starters, Isaac Asimov was a master science fiction writer, the most famous in his time and the best of them all. He was a child prodigy who started writing books at the age of 7 and has written books on almost topics .. even Bible &amp;amp; Shakespeare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Familiar Poems..&amp;rdquo; is not just another compilation of poems. It is a glimpse into the times.. into history. The poems are arranged chronologically. After each poem he gives a backdrop.. So when you read the poem, read the description and once again read the poem, you don’t see beautiful words strung brilliantly to produce rhythm and rhyme but the play .. the actual scene being enacted right in front of your eyes.
&amp;ldquo;The destruction ..&amp;rdquo; was the second poem , Ozymandias being the first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I got up ..&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
reached under the cot for the laptop &amp;amp; specs..&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
googled..&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
2 Kings Ch 18 &amp;amp; 19. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
The Bible says 18,500 people were dead .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;Like the leaves of the forest when summer is green,
That host with their banners at sunset were seen:
Like the leaves of the forest when autumn hath blown,
That host on the morrow lay withered and strown.

For the Angel of Death spread his wings on the blast,
And breathed in the face of the foe as he passed:
And the eyes of the sleepers waxed deadly and chill,
And their hearts but once heaved, and for ever grew still! &amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finished reading it .. also read the wikipedia article about it. It said that the biblical account was one sided and actually Judah had lost to the Assyrian King. Whatever !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Came out of the room and found that T and his friends were almost ready .. his friends had come from different places in the US to visit the west coast and he was kind of taking them around. They were going to San Francisco today.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Since I’m a sleep-early (actually sleep-more) kind of a chap, and they came over pretty late, I never got to speak to them. Thought I’d get acquainted in the morning and now they were about to leave..&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Their departure set me thinking .. Did they eat anything in the morning? Gosh ! May be I should’ve asked them if they wanted to have something ! Frozen Idiappam ?&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Nah ! People brought up in Kerala usually don’t brighten up so much when they hear ‘idiappam’/ ‘kappa’ / ‘aluva’ ..etc in comparison to those brought up outside.. Well! there was nothing much to eat anyway !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you’re staying as a bachelor and when friends’s friends usually drop in .. you kind of lose the host-guest feeling .. You’d slowly tend to stop worrying about such things.. bachelorhood..decadence of social skills ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s ok.. Things can only get better in future..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Had breakfast ..&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Saw the spelling bee contest .. Gee!! how do these small kids know the spellings of all those difficult words. amazing !&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Watched soccer.. I was routing for Germany and they lost ! 2 – 0 . Whatta disgrace .&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Went to San Francisco in the evening to see Independence day fireworks.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
We could see them only from far. So didn’t enjoy it as much as the new year fireworks.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
But the number of people ! There were so many. I guess I’d been missing a real crowd for a long time.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
End of Day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Header Image - &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Sennacherib&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; by Justin Ennis via &lt;a href=&#34;https://flic.kr/p/aLTzAZ&#34;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-07-05-destruction-of-sennacherib/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Fermat&#39;s Last Theorem - Amir Aczel</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-07-02-fermats-last-theorem/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2006 23:44:13 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-07-02-fermats-last-theorem/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-07-02-fermats-last-theorem/ -&lt;p&gt;Amir Aczel’s &amp;ldquo;Fermat’s Last Theorem&amp;rdquo; begins with this amazing quote by Andrew Wiles.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Yes ! he is the one .. the mathematician who solved the most famous unsolvable problem in the history of Mathematics . Over a span of 3 centuries, thousands of brilliant and hardworking men and women were at it.. and in the quest had discovered so many ground-breaking theories ..even new branches of Maths!&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
I was just dumbfounded the moment I read it - at the sheer truth behind it. Here it goes ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exactly !! I think this applies to most situations in life! &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
I’ve been in this groping-in-the-dark-what-do-I-do-next state so many times !&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
May be that’s the joy of teaching.. you see someone groping in the dark and help him/her to the switch and when the room lightens up .. the look on the bright face..that look is the bliss of teaching. And vice versa.. anyone’d be really happy to be with a person who ‘knows’!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are so many mathematicians mentioned in the book.. Euler.. Gauss .. Galois .. Sophie Germain .. I can see them all..as though they spent their lives on earth just recently. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Whatever was written about Gauss in the book, I already knew.. even the story of his teacher giving the 7 yr old Gauss with a difficult monotonous problem like 1+2+3+..100 as punishment and him solving it in a couple of minutes ! &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Galois was a revelation .. I was reminded of Marlowe.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
A really bright star who came in, brightened the whole sky with brilliant blinding light , then swiftly disappeared.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
He was so brilliant that he could solve most equations in his mind. In fact he couldn’t get into the most famous college at that time because he wrote the answers directly without intermediate steps. While still a schoolboy, he’d learnt all the higher level mathematical theories extant at that time and had developed the theory in his name – the Galois theory !&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Galois died in a political duel. The night before the duel.. he was so convinced he would die, that he wrote down his complete mathematical theory and sent it to his friend. At the time of his death, he was just 20!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Header Image - &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Maison Fermat&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; by Karine C. via &lt;a href=&#34;https://flic.kr/p/aFXxXK&#34;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-07-02-fermats-last-theorem/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Message in a bottle ?</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-05-19-message-in-a-bottle/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2006 02:12:11 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-05-19-message-in-a-bottle/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-05-19-message-in-a-bottle/ -&lt;p&gt;Though sleeping, reading and watching movies were the only major things that I did during this weekend, what I really wanted to do was to go to a beach, write something, put it into a bottle and throw it into the sea.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Yeah ! Yes ! just like that !&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Much as I&amp;rsquo;d like to think that someone&amp;rsquo;ll pick it up and read and mail and .. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Nothing..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Header Image - &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Message in a Bottle&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; by Karen Kirby via &lt;a href=&#34;https://flic.kr/p/smj7sF&#34;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-05-19-message-in-a-bottle/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Appearances are deceptive !</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-05-15-appearances-are-deceptive/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2006 00:07:31 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-05-15-appearances-are-deceptive/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-05-15-appearances-are-deceptive/ -&lt;p&gt;Gosh ! I jus came to know that A’d changed from specs to lenses. When ? &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Now I got it ! I met him last week.. that too after a gap of a year ! he asked if I noticed any change in him. I get into this confused-i-wanna-chicken-out kind of state when someone asks me this !&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
I think I’d said “haha .. you look exactly the same. You don’t eat much. Do you ? I guess I too haven’t changed much.”&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
(A might’ve been thinking – ‘bummer! I’ve gotten rid my specs and you don’t even notice the difference ! grr !!’)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This’s been a problem which, for a long time I never knew ! Some friend wears a new dress or gets a new get-up and I never notice. The fact of the matter is, this hurts people…sometimes. v
Once I thought I’d fix it … &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
had told myself “watch it ! from today .. I’m gonna get more interested in the ‘appearance’” &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The very next day I caught P coming to office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me – “hey P, you look different ! you’ve started wearing specs, haven’t you ? Cool ! I must say you now look your true intellectual self.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was really happy I that I noticed some change as soon as I wanted to. Man ! there is nothing in life that you can’t learn once you put your mind into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P’d looked at me curiously and laughed – “what’s wrong with you? I’ve been wearing specs from high school”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much for bothering about looks ! I guess I’ll have to stick to what people feel, like or read !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Header Image - &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Hidden view - A double exposure self portrait&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; by Jon Bush via &lt;a href=&#34;https://flic.kr/p/z9Nrzo&#34;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-05-15-appearances-are-deceptive/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>A time to celebrate</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-05-07-time-to-celebrate/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2006 00:06:11 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-05-07-time-to-celebrate/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-05-07-time-to-celebrate/ -&lt;p&gt;St.George’s festival. Theophilus thirumeni (formerly MC Cherian achen) went over St. George’s life – the same story that had been told to me many times as a kid – more so because I had this paranoid fear of snakes. I’ve had moments in which I missed stamping on a snake or a snake bite by sheer luck ! If you said there was just one in a million chance to see a snake in the city of Bangalore.. yes.. may be.. but there is that one in a million..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a photo of him, St.George – an old, almost faded, small but framed one, in which the brave hero stands face to face with the dragon with a spear in his hand on a white horse . He is staring into the dragon’s eyes and the open mouthed dragon is lunging towards him. The dragon isn’t afraid and he isn’t even a bit scared !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Takes me back to the times when we used to go to kerala during summer vacations. Everything seemed to happen right during that time. Mango’s came at that time. It rained at that time. And this perunal too. It was one time we could have the most delicious of kozhi (chicken) currys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was also the day of Mexican celebration – Cinco de Mayo (simply means – the 5th of May). As I was returning home I could see a lot of people on the streets holding the Mexican flag. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
We went to the park in the evening. Guardalupe park was full of people. After coming from India I’d never seen so many people together in one single place. There were many stalls. There were a couple of stages in which some bands were playing. The music was good. There was a dancing corner. But I didn’t try it out. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
There are a few things that I can best do alone ! dancing may be one of them !!&lt;/p&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-05-07-time-to-celebrate/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>A beautiful day</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-04-30-a-beautiful-day/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2006 23:56:11 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-04-30-a-beautiful-day/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-04-30-a-beautiful-day/ -&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing that I did was to watch the rest of &amp;lsquo;The Sound of Music&#39;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
The &amp;lsquo;favourite things&amp;rsquo; song was still afresh in my mind. I&amp;rsquo;d watched it till Maria stealthily ran away to the abbey. D had said it was the best of movies ! must-watch-should-not-be-missed kind of movie. It is a musical about a wannabe nun being a governess in a Captains house (palace!) gaining the confidence of his 7 kids. It’s a classic. It’s a jolly ride, I’d say – jolly roller coaster musical flow in and out of good times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time I finished everyone was awake.. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
N, reading paper – &amp;ldquo;They’ve opened a new park near downtown. Let’s go.&amp;rdquo; &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Me – &amp;ldquo;Yup..I anyway needed to go to the library.&amp;rdquo; &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
N – “ok. We’ll cook something, take it and eat it from there.”&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
Me – “We’ll eat here and then go there. I don’t like to eat in open spaces.”&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
N – “It’ll be cool to eat in the park. It’ll be like a picnic. We’ll eat there.”&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May be because I’ve seen too many parks littered with leftovers .. I don’t like to eat in parks. Aren’t parks meant to be .. I don’t know .. heaven-in-the-middle-of-rubble or something ? a serene place ? a place where you just sat silently or walked slowly or.. whatever.. well ! it’s my personal prob. I’d rather not impose my ideas into someone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to the library .. and to my surprise saw that there was a book sale going on there. Bought some books. That kind of put me back into good spirits. Called up N to find out if he was coming to the park. He was ready. We found the park, sat on the green grass.. Using bag as pillow I lay flat on the grass and started reading ‘message in a bottle’. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
N unpacked and had his lunch. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
After a while he turned towards me .. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
“How was the sale ? what did you buy ?”&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
“Not many .. arnd 5.”&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
N inspected . he put aside ‘Frenchman’s Creek’ , ‘Life of Pi’ …and other books. I knew his eye’d stop at Republic and it did ! ‘Plato’s Republic ! boy ! I always wanted to read it..’ He started reading it and before long, WE started reading it. The whole book’s in the form of dialogues. He read a dialogue and I the next. We played Socrates, Polemarchus, Thrasymachus alternatively .. and even as we were returning home.. we were arguing .. about ‘justice’&lt;/p&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2006-04-30-a-beautiful-day/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss> 