<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rob&#39;s Notes</title>
    <link>https://robinsonraju.info/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Rob&#39;s Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2020 Robinson Raju</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://robinsonraju.info/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Security news today</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2020-06-02-security-news-today/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2020-06-02-security-news-today/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2020-06-02-security-news-today/ -&lt;p&gt;The optimism around cybersecurity was dampened today by a news article on WSJ - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wsj.com/articles/cybersecurity-startups-feel-a-pinch-on-funding-and-sales-11591090202&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Cybersecurity Startups Feel a Pinch on Funding and Sales&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cybersecurity startups are finding they have to do more with less, as the economic drag of coronavirus precautions makes it difficult to sell their products and enlist new customers while it simultaneously diminishes the size of their funding rounds, investors say.&lt;/em&gt;[1]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article also mentioned that there are thousands of small cybersecurity vendors trying to get business from Fortune 500 companies. So is the author hinting at &amp;ldquo;more supply than demand&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But a New York Times article and many such suggest that there are millions of jobs being unfilled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A stunning statistic is reverberating in cybersecurity: An estimated 3.5 million cybersecurity jobs will be available but unfilled by 2021.&lt;/em&gt; [2]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that as more people adopt to digital life, either due to COVID-19 or due to other reasons, cybersecurity becomes center stage. Take Zoom, for example. As more people started using the software, few security and privacy issues were found. &amp;lsquo;Zoombombing&amp;rsquo; became a new buzzword where people were sharing instances of strangers joining their calls. So, though the recent slump may weed out some startups, there are surely many more on the horizon. The times we live in, demands it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In another article, a security researcher claimed 100K for exposing a vulnerability with apple sign-in [3]. Wow! But I was immediately thinking of the engineers on the other side. Zero-day vulnerabilities (A type of vulnerability that is not known to the software dev or vendor but to the attacker), are the worst. Companies pour money into bug bounty programs to find these. As someone who managed a sensitive application, I have been on the other side. It is like standing on a needle where every second is valuable, and it&amp;rsquo;s a race to resolve it before anyone else finds out. It is AHOD, you gather the most important folks, don&amp;rsquo;t talk about it to anyone during the issue resolution and once it&amp;rsquo;s done, you forget about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That reminds me to start writing notes about &amp;lsquo;Life After Google&amp;rsquo; [4]. Gilder does list a few items that he thinks should be the cornerstone of a new blockchain-based system. Here are the 7 principles of &lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;The Blockstack movement&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt;, as mentioned in the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Distributed cadastre&lt;/strong&gt;: Assures security through logical centralization&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Maximum scalability&lt;/strong&gt;: Assures performance and scalability by separating the control plane from the data plane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Single prototype&lt;/strong&gt;: Establishes property rights by upholding the principle and precedence of singular documents, time-stamped, recorded, and algorithmically allocated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Parallel complement&lt;/strong&gt;: Its expansion confers benefits of privacy and property on its participants without directly threatening incumbents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Low-entropy carrier&lt;/strong&gt;: Provides a stable, predictable, and monolithic foundation for the high-entropy metaverse on the edge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Free migration&lt;/strong&gt;: It allows unobstructed passage from one blockchain or network to another without locking in users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. End-to-end, trust-to-trust&lt;/strong&gt;: All nodes rest on roots of trust that are not heavily dependent on outside authorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know enough to be able to talk much about these things yet, but would definitely be interested in knowing more about #3 - Single prototype.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] Rundle, James. “Cybersecurity Startups Feel a Pinch on Funding and Sales.” The Wall Street Journal. Dow Jones &amp;amp; Company, June 2, 2020. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wsj.com/articles/cybersecurity-startups-feel-a-pinch-on-funding-and-sales-11591090202&#34;&gt;https://www.wsj.com/articles/cybersecurity-startups-feel-a-pinch-on-funding-and-sales-11591090202&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2] Perhach, Paulette. “The Mad Dash to Find a Cybersecurity Force,” November 7, 2018. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/07/business/the-mad-dash-to-find-a-cybersecurity-force.html&#34;&gt;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/11/07/business/the-mad-dash-to-find-a-cybersecurity-force.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[3] Lyngaas, Sean. “Researcher Claims $100,000 for &amp;lsquo;Sign in with Apple&amp;rsquo; Hack.” CyberScoop. CyberScoop, June 1, 2020. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cyberscoop.com/apple-sign-in-vulnerability-bug-bounty/&#34;&gt;https://www.cyberscoop.com/apple-sign-in-vulnerability-bug-bounty/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[4] Gilder, George. Life After Google: The Fall of Big Data and the Rise of the Blockchain Economy (pp. 159-160). Gateway Editions. Kindle Edition.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2020-06-02-security-news-today/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Position or Knowledge?</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2020-06-01-position-or-knowledge/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2020-06-01-position-or-knowledge/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2020-06-01-position-or-knowledge/ -&lt;p&gt;For the past few years, I have read quite a few materials on cybersecurity. In 2017, my professor at SJSU asked me to write a paper on IoT Security and Machine Learning techniques used to protect IoT systems. That was really interesting. Learnt about IoT, Fog Computing, Privacy and Security issues with IoT systems during that time. Since then, I&amp;rsquo;ve spent a few hours on the weekends on this topic, did a Coursera course, some readings as part of SCW (Secure Code Warrior) and beat CTF competitions. I was even thinking of enrolling in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://bootcamp.berkeley.edu/cybersecurity/&#34;&gt;Cybersecurity Bootcamp at Berkeley&lt;/a&gt;. But there was never time. There was always a burning issue in the to-do list that was past due.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if there is a question about continuing in the same domain and possibly growing to a higher position or trying to learn something new? I could divide my 18+ years of experience after B.E. graduation as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8 years of Payments (6 yrs at PayPal, 2 years at ebay PGW/Billing, few months with a Gas Station CC Transaction Processing system)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8 years of e-commerce (at ebay)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a couple of years in misc domains (Healthcare, Insurance).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you had a finite number of working years, say 40, would you pack it with one domain or multiple? The answer probably is different for different people. Of course, a domain like Payments is a mansion with a lot of rooms. A lifetime is not enough to cover all the payment processing schemes and rails. But for a Computer Scientist, a domain is another problem space that needs the right software tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone in the past had asked me to do this Thought Experiment when confronted with the question of this or that - &amp;ldquo;If you had all the money that you wanted, what would you do?&amp;quot;. In this case, I would definitely say, time to learn something new. I think the idea of learning something new or doing the same thing in a new way, appeals to people at a fundamental level. In small or big ways, everyone is an inventor. Invention is at the heart of being human.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though knowledge wins hands down, most of the time, the biggest inertia for a job change is always the people. The people  you work with have become your friends and like extended family, especially if you&amp;rsquo;ve pulled off a project or two that had extremely tough deadlines, debugged several hairy bugs together or brainstormed and argued about the design of new systems, etc. It is the people that make work enjoyable, they are the loved ones that have your back. But the best way to expand your friend circle is also to charter into new domains to forge new fellowships and be a bridge between different circles of your friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, the greatest work is one that is enjoyed and done with the heart&amp;rsquo;s content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And what is it to work with love?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;It is to weave the cloth with threads drawn from your heart&lt;/strong&gt;,&lt;br&gt;
even as if your beloved were to wear that cloth.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;It is to build a house with affection&lt;/strong&gt;,&lt;br&gt;
even as if your beloved were to dwell in that house.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;It is to sow seeds with tenderness and reap the harvest with joy&lt;/strong&gt;,&lt;br&gt;
even as if your beloved were to eat the fruit.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;It is to charge all things you fashion with a breath of your own spirit&lt;/strong&gt;,&lt;br&gt;
And to know that all the blessed dead&lt;br&gt;
are standing about you and watching.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~ Kahlil Gibran&lt;/p&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2020-06-01-position-or-knowledge/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Baby steps on Go</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2020-05-31-golang-example/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2020-05-31-golang-example/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2020-05-31-golang-example/ -&lt;p&gt;Starting to read up on blockchain. RV mentioned that I might need to learn &lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org/&#34;&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt; if I need to tryout some &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hyperledger.org/&#34;&gt;HyperLedger frameworks&lt;/a&gt; in the future. Go has a cool &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.golang.org/&#34;&gt;playground&lt;/a&gt; to try things online and a &lt;a href=&#34;https://tour.golang.org/welcome/1&#34;&gt;tour&lt;/a&gt; which teaches you basics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than looking at them, I wanted to look at some actual code and infer how things work. Most of the people in the Software industry learn things that way anyway. You take up a new project or a join a new team and the first thing that you do is to setup the codebase and figure your way around. In the past (say a decade back), setting up someone&amp;rsquo;s codebase was the toughest thing. The first setup never worked and you had to actually get a help from one of the past developers to set some esoteric environment variable or have a specific folder structure or have specific versions of Java or some special dependencies. Maven simplified a lot of these dependency issues but still it was a struggle. But fast-forward to 2020, most repos have instructions on how to setup and they are pretty straight forward to setup even if there are no instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though I&amp;rsquo;ve developed a lot of front-end applications over the years, my expertise has been backend services. So why not look at how to develop a simple REST API using golang? Was thinking of loading a small dataset like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaggle.com/bilalyussef/google-books-dataset&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;Books data&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.ics.uci.edu/ml/datasets/iris&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;Iris data&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;installing-go&#34;&gt;Installing Go&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Installed Go from the golang website. &lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org/dl/&#34;&gt;https://golang.org/dl/&lt;/a&gt;.
Checked if it was installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;cmd&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;go version&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got the response back as &lt;code&gt;go version go1.14.3 darwin/amd64&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sample-codebase&#34;&gt;Sample Codebase&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Searched &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com&#34;&gt;github.com&lt;/a&gt; and got the following go repos for &amp;ldquo;bookdata&amp;rdquo;. Looks like people are using this to learn Go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://robinsonraju.info/images/githubsearch-bookdata.png&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;h4&gt;GitHub Search Bookdata&lt;/h4&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first application seems to be pretty good. It even has documentation on the API paths that are supported.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;setting-up-sample-codebase&#34;&gt;Setting up sample codebase&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;cmd&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/moficodes/bookdata-api.git&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was assuming, and hoping that there should be no other setup that is needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;starting-the-server&#34;&gt;Starting the server&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;cmd&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd bookdata-api&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;pre class=&#34;cmd&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;go run .&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;testing-the-api&#34;&gt;Testing the API&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The documentation has the following REST APIs.
All api endpoints are prefixed with &lt;code&gt;/api/v1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#eed;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;Get Books by Author
&amp;#34;/books/authors/{author}&amp;#34;
Optional query parameter for ratingAbove ratingBelow limit and skip

Get Books by BookName
&amp;#34;/books/book-name/{bookName}&amp;#34;
Optional query parameter for ratingAbove ratingBelow limit and skip

Get Book by ISBN
&amp;#34;/book/isbn/{isbn}&amp;#34;

Delete Book by ISBN
&amp;#34;/book/isbn/{isbn}&amp;#34;

Create New Book
&amp;#34;/book&amp;#34;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Looking at the dataset in &lt;code&gt;./assets/books.csv&lt;/code&gt;, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure if Author&amp;rsquo;s names with spaces would work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first line in the dataset was this -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#eed;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;1,Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince (Harry Potter  #6),
J.K. Rowling-Mary GrandPré,4.56,0439785960,9780439785969,eng,652,1944099,26249
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Decided to open up Postman and do a search using ISBN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#eed;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;GET http://localhost:8080/api/v1/book/isbn/0439785960
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;voila!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://robinsonraju.info/images/postman-response.png&#34; alt=&#34;postman-response&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was super surprised that it even worked the first time. Exciting stuff. Thanks to &lt;code&gt;moficodes&lt;/code&gt; for creating this app and sharing it on github.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;inspecting-the-codebase&#34;&gt;Inspecting the codebase&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people think that reading through a codebase written in a language that you don&amp;rsquo;t yet know, would not be possible. Definitely not! Programming languages are not like human languages. It is usually easy to figure out the simple stuff since the same patterns repeat everywhere, especially if you have been coding or reading code for sometime. Of course, the difficult stuff is not easy. Reading through a complex codebase might take time even if you have a decade or two of coding experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The codebase here seems quite simple enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;server.go&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; Has a main function with all the API paths defined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;routes.go&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; Has the functions called in server.go like &amp;lsquo;searchByAuthor&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;searchByISBN&amp;rsquo;, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;loader.go&lt;/code&gt; in &amp;lsquo;loader&amp;rsquo; folder -&amp;gt; Has the definition of BookData data structure and a function to load the data.
I&amp;rsquo;d assume that this gets invoked during the server start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;memory.go&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; Has initialize method which has code to load data from a file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no correlation between the filename and the classname as in Java. A file contains a &lt;code&gt;package&lt;/code&gt; statement, similar to Java, &lt;code&gt;import&lt;/code&gt; statement which has packages to be imported. The syntax for import is different but you get what it is trying to do. Most files seem to be a series of functions declared by the keyword &lt;code&gt;func&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://robinsonraju.info/images/files-in-the-codebase.png&#34; alt=&#34;files-in-the-codebase&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://robinsonraju.info/images/main-function.png&#34; alt=&#34;main-function&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;next-steps&#34;&gt;Next steps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hard part of actually learning the language starts now. It is one thing to read a codebase and understand what it does and totally a different thing to be able to write or even do code reviews. As a next step, I&amp;rsquo;ll go through the Tour and understand the basics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2020-05-31-golang-example/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Automating the Hugo build and push to GitHub</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2020-05-23-automating-build-n-push/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2020-05-23-automating-build-n-push/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2020-05-23-automating-build-n-push/ -&lt;p&gt;Instead of remembering to build and push to GitHub, wanted to automate it. The steps are simple enough to write a script and have a cron job execute it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://robinsonraju.info/tech-notes/2020-05-04-setting-up-hugo-site/#3-deploying-to-github-pages&#34;&gt;steps&lt;/a&gt; from the post on &lt;a href=&#34;https://robinsonraju.info/tech-notes/2020-05-04-setting-up-hugo-site/&#34;&gt;Setting up hugo site and publishing to github&lt;/a&gt; are below&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#eed;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;cd &amp;lt;site directory&amp;gt;

hugo

cd &amp;lt;user&amp;gt;.github.io

git add .

git commit -m &amp;#34;Regenerate Site&amp;#34;

git push
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The process is pretty simple. Got to know that &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;crontab&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; was deprecated and &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;launchd&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; was the preferred way to go. There are only 2 steps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a property list (plist) XML giving it details like label and program arguments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put the plist file in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;~/Library/LaunchAgents&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, load and start the job.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;defining-the-job&#34;&gt;Defining the Job&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First step in this is to create a script that you can run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I created &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;gitpush.sh&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; that could execute all the steps above. One thing that didn&amp;rsquo;t work was &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; command. Had to change to include the full path. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;/usr/local/Cellar/hugo/0.69.2/bin/hugo&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the script is created, tested it is time to define the job by creating a plist.
A sample plist XML is available in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/library/archive/documentation/MacOSX/Conceptual/BPSystemStartup/Chapters/ScheduledJobs.html&#34;&gt;Apple Developer Website for Scheduling Timed Jobs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#eed;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;... copy this portion from reference&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;plist version=&amp;#34;1.0&amp;#34;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;dict&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;key&amp;gt;Label&amp;lt;/key&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;io.github.robinsonraju&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;key&amp;gt;ProgramArguments&amp;lt;/key&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;array&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;string&amp;gt;/Users/.../gitpush.sh&amp;lt;/string&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/array&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;key&amp;gt;StartInterval&amp;lt;/key&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;integer&amp;gt;86400&amp;lt;/integer&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/dict&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/plist&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Things configured above -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Label &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; : Unique identifier of the job.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ProgramArguments &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; : Give the script to run here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;StartInterval &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; : This is used to run the job every N seconds. The above example runs every day. Another option is to use &lt;code&gt;StartCalendarInterval&lt;/code&gt; which has the ability to schedule on specific days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;loading-and-running-the-job&#34;&gt;Loading and running the Job&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loading the job&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#eed;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;launchctl load /Library/LaunchAgents/&amp;lt;LABEL&amp;gt;.plist
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Starting the job&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#eed;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;launchctl start &amp;lt;LABEL&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stopping the job&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#eed;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;launchctl stop &amp;lt;LABEL&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unloading a job&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#eed;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;launchctl unload /Library/LaunchAgents/&amp;lt;LABEL&amp;gt;.plist
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had some difficulty in running it initially and it had errored out with code 78. You can either use Mac&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;console&lt;/code&gt; app to look at the system.log or configure &lt;code&gt;StandardOutPath&lt;/code&gt; &amp;amp;  &lt;code&gt;StandardErrorPath&lt;/code&gt; in the plist to direct the logs to another place of your liking. Also, my initial progam argument string was &lt;code&gt;source /Users/.../gitpush.sh&lt;/code&gt;. Then found that it was not needed and I could just give the shell script.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/library/archive/documentation/MacOSX/Conceptual/BPSystemStartup/Chapters/ScheduledJobs.html&#34;&gt;Apple Developer Website for Scheduling Timed Jobs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ss64.com/osx/launchctl.html&#34;&gt;launchctl man page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2020-05-23-automating-build-n-push/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Cloud Atlas</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2020-05-23-cloud-atlas/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2020-05-23-cloud-atlas/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2020-05-23-cloud-atlas/ -&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Yesterday, my life was headed in one direction. Today, it is headed in another.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was super glad to see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B000SEGUDE/ref=cm_sw_r_tw_dp_U_x_D6tYEbNW5R77M&#34;&gt;Cloud Atlas&lt;/a&gt; as one of the books in Bill Gates&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gatesnotes.com/About-Bill-Gates/Summer-Books-2020&#34;&gt;reading list&lt;/a&gt; for this summer. I bought the book back in 2013 but haven&amp;rsquo;t read it yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still remember the first time I saw a trailer for the movie Cloud Atlas and being amazed and speechless. It was probably one of the best trailers I&amp;rsquo;d seen and the concept of interwoven lives and people being connected across generations really appealed to me. The quote above, is one from the movie trailer and I can&amp;rsquo;t believe that the quote found its way to me at this point in time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have always felt that the whole of humanity is bound in some way and that the people we encounter matter to us more than we give credit for. There are people that we&amp;rsquo;re happy to be with, people that we want to connect to, even if it is just for a chat, light up our days like no other, music that we hear for the first time and somehow feel that we&amp;rsquo;ve always known it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We think that we&amp;rsquo;re the sum total of all the things that&amp;rsquo;ve learnt from childhood, and like climbing a ladder, we keep going up, growing up, with each new thing that we learn every minute. But we actually know more than what we&amp;rsquo;ve been taught or learnt on our own, more than what extrapolations of data accumulated in our minds can explain. Where did that extra knowledge come from?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.warnerbros.com/movies/cloud-atlas/&#34;&gt;movie&lt;/a&gt; a couple of times and probably will see it again. It is a sci-fi movie as well as historical fiction with stunning visuals and great acting. Hope to read the book this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a another memorable quote from the Book/Movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;A half-finished book is, after all, a half-finished love affair.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2020-05-23-cloud-atlas/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Setting up Hugo Site and Migrating from Jekyll</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2020-05-04-setting-up-hugo-site/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2020-05-04-setting-up-hugo-site/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2020-05-04-setting-up-hugo-site/ -&lt;p&gt;A couple of years back, I chanced upon an article where someone was describing how simple it was to set up a static website using &lt;a href=&#34;https://ghost.org/&#34;&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt;. That made me think if I should explore moving from &lt;a href=&#34;https://jekyllrb.com/&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; to something newer. New frameworks keep coming up and it probably is a good idea to shift to keep up. So googled for static website generators to see comparisons to products similar to Jekyll. Found that there are many. Hugo caught my attention and I had wanted to migrate my site to Hugo since then. All that was needed was couple of hours or so but I think I probably spent more time exploring through &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo Themes&lt;/a&gt; for many days and months. My initial thought was to have a theme similar to the one that I had with Jekyll, which was the &lt;a href=&#34;http://blackrockdigital.github.io/startbootstrap-clean-blog-jekyll/&#34;&gt;Clean &lt;/a&gt; theme. What I had liked the most about the theme was the font, especially the italics version. But I didn&amp;rsquo;t like banner images. Thinking of choosing the right image for an article itself seemed like a chore. I&amp;rsquo;d rather prefer just typing text. My first choice was to go with a theme called &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/hugo-theme-even/&#34;&gt;Even&lt;/a&gt;. It didn&amp;rsquo;t quite workout the way I intended it to. I wanted to have a left-nav and also a starting page which was not a list of blog entries. After a couple of tries, used a theme called &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/anatole/&#34;&gt;Anatole&lt;/a&gt;. It was super simple to set up and modify.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;setting-up-the-hugo-site&#34;&gt;Setting up the Hugo Site&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The steps to set up are pretty simple like Jekyll. Hugo&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/getting-started/quick-start/&#34;&gt;Quick Start&lt;/a&gt; page covers the basics very clearly. I&amp;rsquo;ll review what I did in addition to setting up the Hugo site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-install-hugo--create-a-new-site&#34;&gt;1. Install hugo &amp;amp; Create a new site&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step is to install hugo. It is pretty simple on the Mac if you already have &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;brew&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; installed. Installation steps for other OSs are in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/getting-started/installing/&#34;&gt;hugo-install&lt;/a&gt; site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#eed;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;brew install hugo
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can use &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo version&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to check if the insallation was done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#eed;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;hugo new site rr_site
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is that simple. This creates a new site with all the default code that is needed. You can start the server by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo server -D&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; but it would be an empty site. In this step it differs from Jekyll where you get a ready made site right away. In order to view something meaningful, you need to configure your site with a theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-configure-the-site-with-a-theme&#34;&gt;2. Configure the site with a theme&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#eed;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;cd rr_site

git init

git submodule add https://github.com/lxndrblz/anatole.git themes/anatole

cp themes/anatole/exampleSite/config.toml .
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This steps assumes that you already know about &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and you have it installed.
Change the directory to the directory of your site. Initialize it as a git repository. Add the theme as a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;git submodule&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. After this, copy the config.toml from the examplesite in the theme to the main folder. The other option is to append the theme using &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;echo &#39;theme = &amp;quot;anatole&amp;quot;&#39; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; config.toml&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to the default &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; that was added when the site was created. But this option would be a bare config without much in it. In order to leverage the theme better, it is a good idea to copy the config.toml over and modify it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-add-content--start-the-server&#34;&gt;3. Add Content &amp;amp; Start the server&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the content for the site are expected to be in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;content&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; folder as markdown files. For the first try, you can either add content by using hugo command &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo new posts/my-first-post.md&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, or copy sample content from the example site within the theme folder &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;./themes/anatole/exampleSite/content&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#eed;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;hugo server -D
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This starts the server and you&amp;rsquo;d be able to view it at &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313&#34;&gt;http://localhost:1313&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can modify the content and the site will automatically rebuild. You can manually rebuild by simply typing &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; command on the command prompt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;migrate-content-from-jekyll&#34;&gt;Migrate content from Jekyll&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-content&#34;&gt;1. Content&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I initially thought I&amp;rsquo;d just move all the files from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; directory in Jekyll root folder to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;content&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; folder in Hugo root folder. But that gave a lot of parsing errors. Got to know that Hugo support &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;TOML&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; format where metadata is enclosed with 2 lines of +++ and has &lt;em&gt;key = &amp;ldquo;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; structure and also &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;YAML&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; format where metadata is enclosed with 2 lines of &amp;mdash; and has &lt;em&gt;key : value&lt;/em&gt; structure. So it should support Jekyll&amp;rsquo;s YAML structure automatically. One of the keys &amp;lsquo;category&amp;rsquo; was a String in my yaml file and in the new theme, it was an array. So changing that to array, fixed the issue and I was able to copy over all the content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-static-files---images-css&#34;&gt;2. Static files - images, css&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Jekyll set up had specific folders named &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;css, js, img&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, etc. under the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;root&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; folder to store static data. In Hugo, it is all in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;static&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; folder under the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;root&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; folder .
I copied over css from the theme folder to override. Also copied over some template HTMLs from theme to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;layouts&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://robinsonraju.info/images/screenshot-layouts.png&#34; alt=&#34;layouts folder&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://robinsonraju.info/images/screenshot-static.png&#34; alt=&#34;static folder&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-deploying-to-github-pages&#34;&gt;3. Deploying to Github pages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Github pages natively support Jekyll but not Hugo. So if I just replaced my github.io content with all the files from Hugo, it would not work at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I already had my static page on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/robinsonraju/robinsonraju.github.io&#34;&gt;https://github.com/robinsonraju/robinsonraju.github.io&lt;/a&gt;. Github automatically builds Jekyll pages, and puts the static files into &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; directory. So we need to do the same. i.e., do a build, generate static files and put them into &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; directory in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;user&amp;gt;.github.io repo&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. The first thing I did was to take a backup of the contents inside &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;user&amp;gt;.github.io&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; repo and delete everything in it. After that, went through the process to generate static files with hugo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process is pretty simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add the github repo as a submodule of the project repo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#eed;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;git submodule add https://github.com/&amp;lt;user&amp;gt;/&amp;lt;user&amp;gt;.github.io.git &amp;lt;user&amp;gt;.github.io
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change config.toml and update the publish directory - &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;publishDir = &amp;quot;&amp;lt;user&amp;gt;.github.io&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#eed;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;baseURL = &amp;#34;https://&amp;lt;user&amp;gt;.github.io/&amp;#34;

title = &amp;#34;Website Title&amp;#34;

theme = &amp;#34;anatole&amp;#34;

publishDir = &amp;#34;&amp;lt;user&amp;gt;.github.io&amp;#34;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do a build using the command &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in the command line. This updates &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; folder in the publish directory which is our submodule.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#eed;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;hugo
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Push the changes in the submodule to github.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#eed;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;cd &amp;lt;user&amp;gt;.github.io

git add .

git commit -m &amp;#34;Initial commit of HTML generated from hugo.&amp;#34;

git push -u origin master
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few other files that I had to copy over from my backup to the github.io repo were CNAME, google site verification html and favicon.ico. Otherwise, it worked as is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-customizations-optional&#34;&gt;4. Customizations (Optional)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might notice that the website (&lt;a href=&#34;https://robinsonraju.info&#34;&gt;https://robinsonraju.info&lt;/a&gt;) is different from anatole theme. It has 3 columns, the left nav is not as wide, the font is different, etc.
As I mentioned earlier, I copied over css from the theme folder to override and changed a bunch of them.
I wanted to have a TOC on the posts and followed instructions from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bram.us/2020/01/10/smooth-scrolling-sticky-scrollspy-navigation/&#34;&gt;https://www.bram.us/2020/01/10/smooth-scrolling-sticky-scrollspy-navigation/&lt;/a&gt; to achieve that. Copied over &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;single.html&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; from themes layouts into the local &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;layouts/_default&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; folder and modified it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it. All the best on your Hugo site.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2020-05-04-setting-up-hugo-site/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>The Great Mental Models: Volume 1 by Shane Parrish &amp; Rhiannon Beaubien</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2020-04-28-great-mental-models/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2020-04-28-great-mental-models/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2020-04-28-great-mental-models/ -&lt;p&gt;I was introduced to &lt;a href=&#34;https://fs.blog/knowledge-project/&#34;&gt;The Knowledge Project&lt;/a&gt; by AJ last year during one of our 1-1 walks around the campus. He sent me the link to &lt;a href=&#34;https://fs.blog/knowledge-project/naval-ravikant/&#34;&gt;Naval Ravikant&lt;/a&gt;&amp;lsquo;s podcast after the walk, and I listened to it in the bus on the way back home. It was one of the best podcasts that I had listened to and was totally taken aback. It was like listening to a philosopher.  I subscribed to the podcast and to the newsletter. One of the newsletters earlier this month spoke about the release of Volume 2 of The Great Mental Models. And I was like, wow, I haven&amp;rsquo;t even read the first volume. In order to be not left behind, I bought the kindle version of the books right away and started reading it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a good read. But I think, it is one of those books where the hardcover would be better. Better formatted, with right things in the right pages. The book has many &amp;lsquo;sidebar&amp;rsquo; anecdotes or snippets that are very interesting but break the flow of the current topic at hand. Also, sometimes a picture that a paragraph refers to, could be found a couple of pages later. A kindle book is great when the content is mostly just text and it flows continuously. Going by the pictures of the book pages on &lt;a href=&#34;https://fs.blog/tgmm/#volume_one&#34;&gt;fs.blog&lt;/a&gt;, looks like the hardcover would be a good buy. Probably will wait for all the books in the series to come out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-a-mental-model&#34;&gt;What is a Mental Model?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the book says, &lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;A mental model is simply a representation of how something works.&#39;&lt;/em&gt; It is a way of looking at things and approaching problems that are presented to us. The chief goal in life, i.e if you want a comfortable life, is to have as few blind spots as one can. Either you work in a narrow area of your expertise or learn fast or try different things, you&amp;rsquo;re always consciously or unconsciously trying to figure out how to make tomorrow better than today. I feel that everyone has a mental model of what is needed to effectively do something. They are all probably smaller variations of some universal mental models. Knowing more, would enable us to think better and make informed decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book presents nine mental models as &amp;lsquo;general thinking concepts&amp;rsquo;. They are things that you&amp;rsquo;ve probably already heard of of know, but it is presented in a simple manner, with great quotes and memorable anecdotes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following are the mental models -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Map is not the Territory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Circle of competence (Supporting Idea - Falsifiability)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First principles thinking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thought experiment (Supporting Idea - Necessity and Sufficiency)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Second-order thinking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Probabilistic thinking (Supporting Idea - Causation vs Correlation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inversion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Occam’s razor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hanlon’s razor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-the-map-is-not-the-territory&#34;&gt;1. The Map is not the territory&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &amp;lsquo;The Map is not the territory&amp;rsquo; the Authors outline that the &amp;lsquo;map&amp;rsquo; is a miniature version of the land and not the land itself. Knowing the map can help navigate the terrain but only going on the terrain gives full understanding of the terrain. Maps are very useful since they abstract away a lot of complexities and information bloat. When we read news or a book summary, we&amp;rsquo;re reading abstractions created by other people who have condensed the information to smaller chunks to represent the actual information. The key issue with using maps is many times, we mistake map for the reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I think of religion, I think though most religions have doctrines that are universal, many have rules that were written in the context of some particular scenario which has probably no relevance now. Map is useful only if we&amp;rsquo;re able to use feedback loops to update the map based on the changed terrain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chapter gives example of Newtonian physics and how it couldn&amp;rsquo;t explain interstellar phenomena that Einstein&amp;rsquo;s Special theory of relativity explains well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t quite understand if the sidebar on &amp;lsquo;Tragedy of Commons&amp;rsquo; was cautioning against every person looking out to profit for themselves or not. Probably it means that if we&amp;rsquo;re working on a shared resource, the map becomes useless if everyone does things that doesn&amp;rsquo;t align with &amp;lsquo;sharing&amp;rsquo; principle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to use the map effectively, one must take 3 important considerations -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a. Reality is the ultimate update - The actual terrain may be different, map might have missed something.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;b. Consider the cartographer - The map maker might not be objective. What you might be seeing is one representation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;c. Maps can influence territories - It is dangerous to fit complexity into simplification or extrapolate wrongly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chapter concludes by a short snippet about Frederick Taylor&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Scientific Theory of Management&lt;/em&gt; of breaking down tasks into smaller pieces and specializing people which worked great on the factory floor but had to be changed with time in different office settings. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t but wonder if Agile methodology is same as this!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-circle-of-competence&#34;&gt;2. Circle of competence&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When one knows little, there is a sense of feeling of high confidence. The unknown unknowns are a lot. The chapter talks about a novice vs a lifer. A lifer is someone who has been in the place or industry for a long time and knows a lot of things about the domain. It would always make sense to get inputs from a lifer. To have a lifer as a mentor would be a great asset. Having sherpas as guides to climb Mt. Everest is a good example. A lifer/competent person knows what he/she doesn&amp;rsquo;t know and is able to make quickly and relatively accurately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, even if you are an expert now, you should not operate as though the circle of competence is static. You must keep the knowledge updated. There are 3 key practices to build/maintain the circle of competence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Willingness to learn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monitor track record in areas that you have/want to have competence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Occasionally solicit external feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 parts to successfully operate outside the circle of competence -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn by basics while acknowledging that you&amp;rsquo;re a novice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talk to experts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use a broad understanding of the basic mental models of the world to augment your understanding of the new field.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chapter cites examples of Queen Elizabeth 1, Warren Buffet&amp;rsquo;s advice on not straying from the circle of competence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Falsifiability - If you can&amp;rsquo;t prove something wrong, you can&amp;rsquo;t really prove it right either. if you keep eliminating things that don&amp;rsquo;t work, you strengthen things that work (evolution example). Karl Popper, who propounded the theory of Falsifiability, also put forth another idea on our false notion of historicism. We use examples from the past to make definite conclusions about what is going to happen in the future. This is dangerous. Think of the worst events in history. We look at the worst in the past and prepare for that. But the future could be worse than the worst.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-first-principles-thinking&#34;&gt;3. First Principles Thinking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a way of breaking down any complex system or ideas into simple fundamental things, or building blocks. Once you see everything in terms of first principles, you&amp;rsquo;d be able to see how disparate things are connected. It is like taking apart a computer or a machine and putting it together. Once you&amp;rsquo;re able to do that you&amp;rsquo;re not only able to debug issues faster but also build new systems from the building blocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two techniques - Socratic questioning and the Five Whys.
Socratic questioning - disciplined questioning process, stops one from relying on gut and limits strong emotional responses.
Five Whys - Determine the root cause of something by repeatedly asking &amp;lsquo;Why&amp;rsquo;. Each why is based on the previous answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First principles thinking gives amazing results and innovative breakthroughs. E.g - H.pylori (stomach bacteria) discovery by Marshall and Warren, Curved carrier chute by Temple Grandin,First principles of meat, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-thought-expriment&#34;&gt;4. Thought Expriment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thought exeperiment is a technique wherein one uses imagination to think through things that are not in existence or are not available currently. Lot of philosophical ideas have been based on thought experiements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chapter examines 3 areas in which thought experiments are very useful -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagining physical impossibilities - e.g. Einsten&amp;rsquo;s theory of Relativity or the train and the platform example in Stephen Hawking&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;A Brief History of Time&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Re-imagining history - This is one of my favorite things to think about thing. Love TV series like &amp;lsquo;The Man in the High Castle&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;Outlander&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;12 Monkeys&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;Battlestar Galactica&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;The Expanse&amp;rsquo;, etc. which dwell not only on alternate history but also possible futures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intuiting the non-intuitive - A thought experiment allows us to verify if our gut instincts are correct or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Necessity and Sufficiency&lt;/strong&gt; -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The gap between what is necessary to succeed and what is sufficient is often luck, chance, or some other factor beyond your direct control.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hard truth - There could be thousands of people who write well and are able to publish but everyone cannot be J.K Rowling. Talent and hardwork is necessary to become a published author but not sufficient to become J.K Rowling. The gap, is huge!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;5-second-order-thinking&#34;&gt;5. Second-Order Thinking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost everyone can think of immediate consequences of doing something. But about the ripple effects? Second-order thinking is the ability think farther than immediate consequences. A lot of disasters in the world could be attributed to lack of second-order thinking.
Example - During the colonial rule, The British wanted to reduce the number of poisonous snakes in Delhi and announced a reward for people who brought in dead snakes. People did. By growing more snakes to make money, they inadvertently increased the number of snakes!
Use of plastics, smoking, bad city planning, overgrazing - there are too many examples of lack of thought when we look around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stupidity is the same as evil if you judge by the results.&lt;/em&gt;
~ Margaret Atwood&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a quote !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key think is to think forward as much as possible with all the information at hand. &amp;ldquo;Haste makes waste!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;6-probabilistic-thinking&#34;&gt;6. Probabilistic Thinking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probablistic thinking is to try to estimate the likelihood of an outcome by using data at hand. The whole world probably runs on Probablity! A self-driving car, a complex search algorithm, a Machine Learning model, they&amp;rsquo;re all using probability to produce an outcome that is most likely. The same is probably true of our minds also. The feedback loop is pretty great for our brains though. The success of ANN (Artificial Neural Networks) is greatly due to it being modeled after neurons. Probablistic thinking avoids analysis paralysis and also waiting for ever for all the perfect data to be made available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three important aspects that you need to be aware&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bayesian thinking / Conditional probability - When making uncertain decisions, it is always important to check prior conditions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fat-tailed curves - Beware of fat-tailed curves. They distort risk estimations. A small error is measuring the risk of an extreme event can mean we&amp;rsquo;re way off - by orders of magnitude, not 100 fold but 10,000 fold. I think the corona virus epidemic and the lack of preparation is a good example.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assymetries - How often do you leave “on time” and arrive 20% early? Almost never? How often do you leave “on time” and arrive 20% late? All the time? Or when you aim to get 25% returns on an investment, are you more likely to get 10% (-15) or 40% (+15) ?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;7-inversion&#34;&gt;7. Inversion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inversion is a technique to think from the opposite end of the problem. Flip the problem, think backward, start from the end rather than beginning, etc.
The chapter gives example of Edward Bernays&amp;rsquo;s revolutionary campaign to get women to smoke cigarettes. He approached by problem by imagining how it would be if smoking was already an accepted norm.
If you&amp;rsquo;re stuck with something, invert. Even if not stuck, it always helps to think from different angles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;8-occams-razor&#34;&gt;8. Occam’s razor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The simplest solutions are most likely to be the right ones. Simple explanations are more likely than complex ones.
David Hume was very cautious about believing in miracles.
Vera Rubin was able to explain behavior of galaxies using the simpler theory of &amp;lsquo;dark matter&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;9-hanlons-razor&#34;&gt;9. Hanlon’s razor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of things that we attribute to malice might be more easily explained by stupidity or laziness. Brings me back to the earlier quote from Margaret Atwood - &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Stupidity is the same as evil if you judge by the results.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2020-04-28-great-mental-models/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>21 Lessons for the 21st Century by Yuval Noah Harari</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2020-01-18-21_lessons/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2020-01-18-21_lessons/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2020-01-18-21_lessons/ -&lt;p&gt;I read this book on the way to and during the Alaska Trip that we took during last winter (2019). Read on the flight from SF to Portland and from there to Anchorage. The bulk of the reading was done during the full-day train journey from Anchorage to Fairbanks on the 3rd day of the trip. That was a magical train journey - to go through untouched snow in a vast land seemingly out of nowhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had listened to &amp;lsquo;Sapiens&amp;rsquo; through Hoopla a couple of years back. Probably twice. During my practice runs for the half-marathon that I was running that year and also during the run itself. Audio books are much slower reads than actual reading and I sometimes tend to zone out. Hoping to read the book on print/kindle in the future. But whatever I had heard, it was thought provoking and a well written book. It alters your perspective of the world and you begin to see the entire human history in a different light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The author mentions that Sapiens was about the past of humanity, Home Deus was about the future and this book is about the present. He takes 21 problems, or 21 pressing concerns that the world if facing right now and addresses each of them. It is like reading 21 essays on different topics, well-articulated essays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-i-the-technological-challenge&#34;&gt;Part I: The Technological Challenge&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-1-disillusionment&#34;&gt;Chapter 1: Disillusionment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humans think in stories than facts. Harari had mentioned in Sapiens that the key reason for ascendency of Homo Sapiens was the story telling ability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The fascist story&lt;/strong&gt; - History is a struggle of nations/races and one tries to subjugate another. Let&amp;rsquo;s give importance to our nation and our ideals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The communist story&lt;/strong&gt; - History is a struggle of classes where the upper class always tried to subjugate the lower. Let&amp;rsquo;s envision a classless society.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The liberal story&lt;/strong&gt; - History is a struggle of liberty and tyranny. Let&amp;rsquo;s build a world of freedom and equality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1938 - 3 global stories to choose from, 1968 - 2 stories to choose from (liberal, communist), 1998 - a single story (liberal democracy), 2018 - no story. Disillusionment !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harari says that 2008 financial crisis precipitated the disillusionment and gave rise to a lot of pro-national sentiments. With the rise of Trump and Brexit in 2016, people seem to have developed a liking for the old racist and nationalist views. Nostalgia - Britain thinking of old glory, Islamist thinking of how things were 1400 yrs back during Caliphate, Zionists dreaming of going back 2,500 years back, and so forth!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loved the paragraph about &amp;ldquo;Humans vote with their feet&amp;rdquo;. So true! There are millions of people who wish to immigrate to the US, Germany, Canada or Australia. How many wish to immigrate to China, India or Vietnam? People are willing to undergo extreme hardship to just cross the border and come to the US though there is so much bad press about how immigrants are treated badly, especially the ones from south of the border. How many Islamists from Syria or other countries want to migrate to Kuwait or Saudi vs Germany?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harari defines a liberal set menu which outlines what it means at National and International level for Economic, Political and Personal areas. He is optimistic that people will not abandon liberal ideas altogether because of lack of viable alternatives. The dish might contain some items from the menu if not all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-2-work&#34;&gt;Chapter 2: Work&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fear of losing job to a machine has been there since the beginning of Industrial Revolution. But, if you look at the stats, for every job lost to a machine, at least one new job was created. Every job lost to the machine raised the standard of living multi-fold. But future may be different. Work in 2050 might to totally different since AI seeks to not just replace the mechanical work that humans do but cognitive also.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some tasks that AI is much better than humans. For e.g. driving. Driverless cars could reduce fatality by 90%! degree. Two important non-human abilities that AI possesses are connectivity and updatability. If there are a billion doctors in the world who need to be updated about a new disease, it is almost impossible, but if there were AI-doctors who are networked, it is almost instantaneous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In areas like elder care, music, art, etc., it might take longer for AI to do what humans do.
In many fields, there might be more AI cooperation than competition. Also new jobs to debug, service AI will be created. But the key thing about the new jobs that will get created will be that they will require expertise. So retraining might be difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2017 Google&amp;rsquo;s AlphaZero defeated Stockfish 8 program in a game of chess. The milestone was critical since AlphaZero learnt chess from scratch in 4 hours! AI is competing with other AI and not with humans anymore!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The author does say that rise of AI may not lead to exploitation of humans like it happened during the Industrial Revolution. It might get to a point where everything becomes efficient and people are provided with what they need - food, clothing &amp;amp; shelter. If one gets these things for free, will people go into irrelevance? Wow, one is reminded of &amp;lsquo;The Matrix&amp;rsquo; here. AI could actually put all humans to sleep and keep them in a dream state so that they don&amp;rsquo;t destroy the earth!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The author talks about UBI (Universal Basic Income) or Universal Basic Services where social services are subsidized. It could become the utopian vision of communism!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He gives example of ultra-orthodox Jews who are poor and unemployed and spend all their time in studying scriptures. They are supported by the government and they are reported to have higher life satisfaction than other groups who have money and are employed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chapter ends with a positive, powerful note - &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;The quest for meaning and community might eclipse the quest for a job. If we manage to combine a universal economic safety net with strong communities and meaningful pursuits, losing our jobs to algorithms might actually turn out to be a blessing.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-3-liberty&#34;&gt;Chapter 3: Liberty&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the Brexit vote, Ricard Dawkins had said that normal people should not have been asked to vote since most of them are not equipped to know the economic and political consequences of the decision. Elections are about what we feel and not what may be good for us. What people feel are mostly defined by their news feed or search results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computer algorithm might be better equipped to counsel humans than human feelings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;b×c×d = ahh&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Biological knowledge multiplied by Computing power multiplied by Data equals Ability to Hack Humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Algorithm could help you choose a better movie that you might like than you could, decide what to do based on mood, what to buy, which career to choose, etc. Human feelings are shaped by survival and reproduction a million years ago but it is not the case with AI/Algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The author says that knowledge of Philosophy will be in great demand since the algorithms need it to make basic decisions to create more complex ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital dictatorship is more dangerous than any dictatorship that we&amp;rsquo;ve seen in the past. Stalin didn&amp;rsquo;t possibly know or have control over normal citizens. But AI could know about every single citizen. Big Data algorithms might extinguish liberty and also might simultaneously create the most unequal societies that ever existed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-4-equality&#34;&gt;Chapter 4: Equality&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rise of liberalism and increase in globalization in the 1900s promised a more egalitarian society than all the centuries in the past put together. People in India and Egypt could enjoy the same opportunities and privileges as Finland and Canada!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in the 2000s, the trend is changing. Wealth seems to be getting concentrated with the 1%. The richest 100 people own more than the poorest 4 billion people!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the rise of AI and breakthroughs in biotechnology, the divide could get larger and impossible to reduce. Rich people in the past could buy more possessions or live in grandeur. The average rich person was not more intelligent than an average poor person. But now, they could soon have the ability to extend life, have more brain capacity, be more beautiful. The rich might become a set of superhumans who are like gods. This would result in the separation of humankind into a small class of superhumans and a massive underclass of ordinary Homo sapiens. Similar to Greek mythology!
As the superhumans evolve to a different species, they might choose to wall themselves off widening the inequality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 21st century, data will eclipse land and machinery as the most important asset. The race to control more data is already on with all the big corporations vying for more control. At the moment, ordinary people are more than willing to give away their personal data. In a battle between privacy and health, health is likely to win. But that is fraught with so many dangers even leading to people losing their liberty. But there is no way to ensure private ownership of data at the moment. A technology innovation in that area is very necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-ii-the-political-challenge&#34;&gt;Part II: The Political Challenge&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-5-community&#34;&gt;Chapter 5: Community&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response to the growing nationalist sentiments after the 2016 elections, in 2017, Mark Zuckerberg published an audacious manifesto on the need to build a global community and that Facebook&amp;rsquo;s mission was to take this on. Breakdown of human communities was lamentable and Facebook could help people join meaningful communities online. Harari says that &amp;ldquo;finding meaningful communities and also strengthening our social fabric to bring the world closer together&amp;rdquo;, is more ambitious than even self-driving car. The goal is timely and noble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But as more and more people live online, they are losing touch of their body, how it feels. People could listen to birds, know if a snake was in the grass by listening to the rustling, but now those skills are going away since people mostly are on their cellphones. People disconnected from their bodies are likely to feel alienated and disoriented. The time and energy you spend in communities online to connect with people across the world will be at the expense of your body, your family and your next door neighbors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-6-civilization&#34;&gt;Chapter 6: Civilization&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harari says that there is only one civilization in the world now. &amp;ldquo;The West&amp;rdquo; and the &amp;ldquo;The Muslim World&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;The East&amp;rdquo;, etc. may seem different but they are all operating under the same guidelines of modern civilization. Humans in the past were divided into isolated civilizations but not anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He gives example of Olympics, it was probably inconceivable to conduct Olympic games at an international level 1000 years back but now it is possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another example is medicine. In the past, people in different places were treated differently accordingly to the local belief systems or superstitions. But now, it is mostly identical. People use the same proven scientific approaches and believe in cells and bacteria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-7-nationalism&#34;&gt;Chapter 7: Nationalism&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nationalism was and is needed for people to support large systems. Harari gives the example of tribes along the Nile river. A tribe or a small group could have easily perished in a famine if multiple tribes hadn&amp;rsquo;t come together as a nation to help build dam along the Aswan or other infrastructure to feed a large number of people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nationalism is actually not in the DNA of a Human. People might prefer to feed their immediate family rather than pay taxes to feed millions of unknown but still they do it. They believe in the propaganda and flag-waving and the feeling of shared history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem starts when benign patriotism morphs into chauvinistic ultranationalism. Instead of believing that your nation is unique, if you believe that your nation is supreme and you will be blindly loyal to do whatever it takes to exert its superiority, your thinking is muddled and you&amp;rsquo;ve declared war. Reminded of Gandhi&amp;rsquo;s quote - &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;An eye for an eye makes the whole world blind.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Economic Challenge - Harari points out that extreme isolationism is completely divorced from economic realities. Without a global trade network, all existing national economies will collapse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nuclear Challenge - As more nations have nuclear power, without a robust system of international cooperation, there is no way to protect the world from nuclear destruction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ecological Challenge - Without international cooperation of multiple countries, the disastrous effects of global warming cannot be prevented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technological Challenge - With the rise of biotechnology, if there is no globally accepted ethical guidelines, it could be open season for Dr. Frankenstein.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The take away - &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;In order to take good care of your compatriots, you must cooperate with foreigners. So good nationalists should now be globalists.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-8-religion&#34;&gt;Chapter 8: Religion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even in the 21st century, truly secular people are a minority. Billions of people still ardently profess belief in Christianity, Hinduism or Islam. But are they really helping solve the problems of today? In many places, religion is part of the problem of humanity and not the solution, it seeks to divide people and not unite, which is very unfortunate since, of all the ideologies that Homo Sapiens have had over the last millions of years, religion is probably the best unifying force.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 types of problems in the 21st century&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technical problems - Agriculture/Medicine - How should farmers deal with severe droughts caused by global warming? If someone is very sick, should he/she be taken to a hospital or a religious place? Religious authority has dwindled in medicine and farming because people don&amp;rsquo;t associate religion with those anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Policy problems - Economics - For questions like raising taxes, signing tariff agreements, grant authority to AI to make decisions about people&amp;rsquo;s lives, etc., people/govts turn to Economists and other modern financial theory. Does religion have much to contribute to the great policy debates of our time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identity problems - Even in the 21st century, religion gets to define who is &amp;lsquo;us&amp;rsquo; vs &amp;lsquo;them&amp;rsquo;. Many religions use it to divide people. The right approach probably is to adapt religion to new realities to unite people. Harari gives example of Japanese people having reinvented Shintoism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-9-immigration&#34;&gt;Chapter 9: Immigration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As he said earlier, &amp;ldquo;Humans vote with their feet&amp;rdquo;. World is more connected than ever and immigration is a reality. Harari views immigration as a deal with 3 basic conditions or terms -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The host country allows the immigrants in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In return, the immigrants must embrace at least the core norms and values of the host country, even if this means giving up their traditional norms. &amp;ldquo;When in Rome, be Roman&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If immigrants assimilate, over time, they become &amp;lsquo;us&amp;rsquo; than &amp;lsquo;them&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are always people in both camps. pro-immigration as well as anti-immigration. It is mostly a socio-economic issue. Many countries turn a blind eye to illegal immigration since they want to benefit from cheap labor of young foreigners. But they refuse to legalize the status, thus creating a society of upper class citizens who exploit powerless foreigners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immigration also depends on the cultural make up of a country. Some countries are more tolerant and have mechanisms in place to assimilate them. For e.g. German culture in the twenty-first century is more welcoming of immigrants than Saudi culture. So a Syrian refugee might actually prefer to flee to Germany and not to Saudi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harari illustrates the cultural differences using an example of fictional Coldians and Warmlanders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 points to remember -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It would be wrong for any government to force large scale immigration on a local population if they are unwilling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Though people might oppose immigration, they should realize that they have an obligation towards foreigners.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-iii-despair-and-hope&#34;&gt;Part III: Despair and Hope&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-10-terrorism&#34;&gt;Chapter 10: Terrorism&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 9/11, terrorism has killed around 25,000 people. In contrast, traffic accidents killed 1.25 million people, diabetes killed 3.5 million people and air pollution 7 million people. Terrorists kill few people but instill fear on billions and rattle big governments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harari says that terrorists are like a fly that wants to destroy a china shop. But the fly is weak and has no power to even move a single cup. What does it do? It goes into a bulls ear and starts buzzing. The bull destroys the china shop!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-11-war&#34;&gt;Chapter 11: War&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past, war was the way of the world, the way to get more land and more manpower. But in the present, war is expensive, and countries that have not gone to war have prospered better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human stupidity is one of the most important forces in history, yet we often tend to discount it. One potential remedy for human stupidity is a dose of humility. National, religious, and cultural tensions are made worse by the grandiose feeling that my nation, my religion, and my culture are the most important in the world. People need to realize their true place in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-12-humility&#34;&gt;Chapter 12: Humility&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The truth is, everyone claims superiority. People are brainwashed from a young age to believe that their group, their religion is the center of the world. The key thing to remember is that the world is large and humans have created hundreds or religions. When we see things in the right perspective, you automatically become humble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-13-god&#34;&gt;Chapter 13: God&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harari says that you don&amp;rsquo;t need to necessarily believe in God to be moral. If you believe in not causing suffering to another human being or reducing the suffering of others, that would suffice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would a human really care about another person&amp;rsquo;s misery? Most probably yes, people are social animals and their happiness depends to a large extent on the relations with others. So the belief in not causing suffering to another human is at the core of our existence and doesn&amp;rsquo;t need belief or fear of God to be so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Religious belief can create compassion and kindness in people but it can also stoke anger against people who do not follow their belief system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-14-secularism&#34;&gt;Chapter 14: Secularism&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secularism is a positive and active worldview. It is not opposed to religion. In fact, the core of most religion are secularist principles. Secularism views morality and wisdom as the natural legacy of all humans, not something handed down from God to a specific set of humans at a point in time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Secular Ideals -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commitment to truth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compassion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commitment to equality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cherish Responsibility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Questions you cannot answer are usually far better for you than answers you cannot question.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-iv-truth&#34;&gt;Part IV: Truth&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-15-ignorance&#34;&gt;Chapter 15: Ignorance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Individual humans are pretty ignorant of their world. We rely mostly on the expertise of others whether we acknowledge it or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of people&amp;rsquo;s views are shaped by communal groupthink rather than individual rationality, and they hold on to these views due to group loyalty. Stating facts to convince someone might actually backfire. True especially for superstitions people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harari talks about how power acts like a blackhole that warps the spacetime around it. Leaders are trapped in it. They have the best knowledge at their disposal but might not be able to leverage it since people might say the right things other than flattery due to the lack of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-16-justice&#34;&gt;Chapter 16: Justice&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Harari, there is injustice all around the world and most people live on being ignorant of the part that they are playing. What if the phone that I bought was created by child laborers? What if the company that I invested in and gives me 5% returns is involved in dumping toxic waste that kills sealife? What if the sugar that I&amp;rsquo;m having for tea results in slave trade across the world?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world is so complex and interdependent that only the ignorant can judge and blame other. One could be abetting a crime just by sitting at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-17-post-truth&#34;&gt;Chapter 17: Post-Truth&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re now living in a tragic world of fake news. There is no real way of separating truth from fake news. Propaganda and disinformation is nothing new. It existed in the past - Japanese army created the fake country of Manchukuo to legitimize its conquests, China has long denied that Tibet ever existed as an independent country, British settlement in Australia was justified by the legal doctrine of terra nullius (&amp;ldquo;no one&amp;rsquo;s land&amp;rdquo;), etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;When a thousand people believe some made-up story for one month, that’s fake news. When a billion people believe it for a thousand years, that’s a religion&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; !!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harari mentions that it is our responsibility to invest time and effort in uncovering our biases and in verifying our sources of information. Also, if you want reliable information, pay good money for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;If you get your news for free, you might well be the product.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-18-science-fiction&#34;&gt;Chapter 18: Science Fiction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harari says that in the 21st century, perhaps the most important genre is science fiction. It gets people excited (or fearful) about the future possibilities and also teaches about fields of Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence more than what people try to read to find out. From that perspective, it is a great responsibility also. Sci-fi authors and movies can distort people&amp;rsquo;s views and give them bad ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harari cites examples from Orwell&amp;rsquo;s 1984 and Huxley&amp;rsquo;s Brave New World.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-v-resilience&#34;&gt;Part V: Resilience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-19-education&#34;&gt;Chapter 19: Education&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is more difficult than ever to predict the future. So we don&amp;rsquo;t know how things will be in 2050 and cannot really know what we should teach kids to prepare themselves for 2050. The schooling system has foundations in a past world when information was scarce and just knowing to read and write and getting the basics of geography, history and biology was a great improvement. But in today&amp;rsquo;s world, there is an information overload. So cramming information into kids is probably not the best use of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about teaching technologies that are important today - say coding in C++ or to talk Chinese? But after investing a lot of time in this, we might discover in 2050 that machines/AI can do this better than humans! What should the schools be teaching ? Experts agree on &amp;ldquo;the four Cs&amp;rdquo; — &lt;strong&gt;Critical thinking, Communication, Collaboration, and Creativity&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ability to constantly learn and reinvent yourself would be the key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-20-meaning&#34;&gt;Chapter 20: Meaning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do we have a fixed &amp;lsquo;true&amp;rsquo; identity that determines our duties in life? Is our purpose in life to find this identity and fulfill it? Simba the lion was born to eat antelopes and Arjuna the warrior was born to fight battles and if they don&amp;rsquo;t they are shunning the natural course of events in a Circle of Life. Are they? Harari goes through a few more worldviews and concludes that &lt;strong&gt;all stories are incomplete&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to give meaning to life, a story needs to satisfy 2 conditions -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It must give the individual a role to play.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It must extend beyond the individuals horizons (as religious stories extends to eternity).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You cannot leave anything meaningfully tangible behind. So you might be better off just helping someone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human quest for meaning all too often ends with a succession of sacrifices - self or others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 basic realities of the universe by The Buddha -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everything is constantly changing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nothing has any enduring essence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nothing is completely satisfying&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-21-meditation&#34;&gt;Chapter 21: Meditation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was surprised to see Harari mention about Vipassana meditation course. I&amp;rsquo;d heard about it from AM who has been my colleague since 2011.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harari talks about his first experience with meditation and says that he learned more about himself and about humans in general by observing his sensations for those ten days than he had learnt in his whole life up to that point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He meditates for 2 hours every day! Remarkable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He concludes by saying that we have a choice to make an effort and investigate who we really are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2020-01-18-21_lessons/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Factfulness By Hans Rosling,  Anna Rosling Rönnlund, Ola Rosling</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2020-01-04-factfulness/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2020-01-04-factfulness/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2020-01-04-factfulness/ -&lt;p&gt;I read this book on the way back from our Alaska Trip during during last winter (2019). The trip itself was magical since it was like going to a different land that I&amp;rsquo;ve only seen in movies or read in books. Read the book in Fairbanks airport, in the flight from Fairbanks to Anchorage, Anchorage airport, in the flight from Anchorage to Portland, Portland airport and in the flight from Portland to SFO. The whole journey took a day since we started around 9-ish in the morning. The book was engaging and awesome. The twist in the end totally took me by surprise. Throughout the book, you feel like Hans Rosling is directly talking to you and then ..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a positive book. It tells us that the world is in a much better state than we think it is in. In that way it is very similar to Steven Pinker&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Better Angels of Our Nature&amp;rdquo;. Better Angels was the second book that Mark Zuckerberg had read in his 2015 book reading challenge. There are a lot of interesting insights in the book that would enable us to see life and the world in a different light. Instead of dividing the world and developed and developing, he divides it as Level 1, L2, L3 and level 4. One begins to see that many developing countries are much better off now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The gap instinct&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The negativity instinct&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The straight line instinct&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The fear instinct&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The size instinct&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The generalization instinct&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The destiny instinct&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The single perspective instinct&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The blame instinct&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The urgency instinct&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Factfulness in practice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Factfulness rules of thumb.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2020-01-04-factfulness/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Of Love and Other Demons by Gabriel Garcia Marquez</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2019-10-15-of-love-and-other-demons/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2019-10-15-of-love-and-other-demons/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2019-10-15-of-love-and-other-demons/ -&lt;p&gt;There are some novels that start slowly, and build up momentum as we progress through the story. And there are others that start with a bang. &amp;lsquo;Of love and other demons&amp;rsquo; is definitely in the latter category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The books opens with a letter from Marquez on how he came upon the story. On a routine round to cover a story for his newspaper, the author is sent to find out about the emptying/transportation of crypts of Santa Clara Convent, which is in a dilapidated state. He comes across an astonishing sight when after one of the crypts is open, they see copper colored hair  on a skeleton head. It was as if the hair grew after death out of the skeleton. The author is reminded of a story that his grandmother had told him about a young girl with long hair, who got bitten by a dog, became mad and was later venerated as a saint since she performed miracles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the get go, when &amp;ldquo;an ash gray dog with a white blaze&amp;rdquo;, charges into a market and bites the protagonist, a young girl who is the daughter of a local nobleman, the novel transports the reader to a different place in a different era, and doesn&amp;rsquo;t let go. Till the last page, we&amp;rsquo;re intrigued by what is going to happen and are rooting for Sierva Maria to come out of the whole ordeal victorious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d always wanted to read Marquez. I&amp;rsquo;d heard about this famous book &amp;lsquo;One Hundred Years of Solitude&amp;rsquo; in high school or college, as a quiz question or may be it was a crossword puzzle on The Hindu. It was at the back of my mind. I read the prologue of this book our local library and was totally hooked. It was a worth read. AK also read the book. She also bought &amp;lsquo;One Hundred Years&amp;rsquo;. Haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten to reading that yet though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, the novel is about a young girl getting bitten (very small bite) by a dog. She is actually not affected but due to the rumours and superstitions, she is forced to undergo exorcism by many people. Finally is brought to a convent. The young priest there falls in love with the girl. Though he recommends that she is not mad, the authorities don&amp;rsquo;t listen. It ends tragically for all the &amp;lsquo;good&amp;rsquo; people in the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is good and not good is often a gray area. If you follow society&amp;rsquo;s norms and act in the way it expects, then you&amp;rsquo;re branded as good. The religious fanaticism that existed in the 17th century South America exists even today, almost everywhere in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The novel explores many themes, and one of them is the fight between good and evil. One could say that the &amp;lsquo;good&amp;rsquo; is the truth and everything that is natural in the world. The &amp;lsquo;evil&amp;rsquo; is dogma and superstition that plagued the society during that time period. A strong belief in demons and reliance on hearsay, made the people around Sierva Maria see her differently than what she really was. She was just a 12 year old adolescent who was coming out of childhood into adulthood. She was also a victim of neglect by her parents. Her Yoruban beliefs, songs, dances, painting her face black, etc. were part of her growing up and it was natural for her. But it was tangential to her European parents or the Church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a way, the novel conveys that going against the confines of the present norms can sometimes work, or sometimes go awry. When a new idea upends an old one, it is many times because of myriads of factors that led to that time. Though people always venerate heroes who led the revolution without realizing that the people were the instruments and the revolution would have happened regardless of that particular person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I think the novel depicts that the conflict between good and evil is a human condition. Though we could judge the people based on our moral compass and group them as good vs evil, every person is fighting the battle against evil. What he or she thinks is evil could be based on his/her level of intelligence or what they&amp;rsquo;ve been told. It is not just the external evil but also the internal one. The internal conflict sometimes manifests externally by being too good to people or too cruel. So a human life&amp;rsquo;s journey is about fighting their own battle with their hidden evil and also fighting the external forces of evil from their standpoint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The novel also alludes to the fact that people may not fully be in control of their destiny. One can only attempt to be true to oneself and hope that it aligns with the surroundings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/dp/1400034922/ref=cm_sw_r_tw_dp_U_x_tPCTEbME0VVKJ&#34;&gt;Of Love and Other Demons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2019-10-15-of-love-and-other-demons/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Snow Crash by Neal Stephenson</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2019-02-20-snow-crash/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 13:18:21 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2019-02-20-snow-crash/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2019-02-20-snow-crash/ -&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d always wanted to read a novel by Neal Stephenson. Back in 2005, NC had mentioned him as a great author who wrote cyber thrillers and I should definitely read. Time passed by, I forgot about this and when someone recently mentioned Stephenson in a chat about books, I thought I must get hold of a copy. Reading a paperback after a long time was fun. I felt it didn&amp;rsquo;t live up to the hype and it took me a bit of time to get into the book. But if you read the backcover, you&amp;rsquo;d surely be intrigued enough to give it a try. Here it is, verbatim -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Only once in a great while does a writer come along who defies comparison&amp;ndash;a writer so original he redefines the way we look at the world. Neal Stephenson is such a writer and Snow Crash is such a novel, weaving virtual reality, Sumerian myth, and just about everything in between with a cool, hip cybersensibility to bring us the gigathriller of the information age.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2019-02-20-snow-crash/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Payment Systems in the US - Second Edition by Carol Coye Benson , Scott Loftesness</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2019-01-31-payment-systems/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 15:18:21 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2019-01-31-payment-systems/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2019-01-31-payment-systems/ -&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is probably the 3rd time I&amp;rsquo;m reading this book. Got this book when I attended Payments 101 &amp;amp; 201 by Glenbrook in Jan/Feb 2015. It was just a couple of days but was one of the best courses I&amp;rsquo;ve attended. It is simple, easy to read and helps to connect with a lot of projects that I deal with on a daily basis. It felt great to read it again.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2019-01-31-payment-systems/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>How to Become CEO - The Rules for Rising to the Top of Any Organization by Jeffrey J. Fox</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2018-12-05-how-to-become-ceo/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2018-12-05-how-to-become-ceo/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2018-12-05-how-to-become-ceo/ -&lt;p&gt;This is a great book. You can open any page and random and find tidbits that immediately resonate with you. It has so many &amp;ldquo;I should be doing this, I should have done this, This is super advice&amp;rdquo; kind of messages. I had given it as a gift to my manager and he said he&amp;rsquo;s read it over 50 times!! Of course, he is someone who has a &amp;lsquo;yes&amp;rsquo; tickmark to most of the items in the list. I have a long way to go though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are 75 guidelines in the book presented as pearls of wisdom by someone who has &amp;lsquo;been there, done that&amp;rsquo;. In a way, it is not about becoming the CEO, but feeling like a CEO, like someone who has things in control, even if you&amp;rsquo;re a first level manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always take the job that offers the best money&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avoid staff jobs, seek line jobs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t expect the personnel department to plan your career&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get and keep customers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep physically fit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do something hard and lonely&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never write a nasty memo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think for one hour everyday&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep and Use a Special Idea Notebook&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t have a drink with the gang&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t Smoke&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skip all office parties&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friday is “How Ya’ Doing?” Day&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Makes Allies of your Peer’s subordinates&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know everybody by their first name&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organize “One-line Good job” Tours&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make one More Call&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arrive forty-five minutes early and leave fifteen minutes late&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t take work home from the office&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earn Your “Invitation Credentials”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avoid Superiors When You Travel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eat in Your Hotel Room&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work, Don’t Read Paperbacks, on the Airplane&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep a “People File”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Send handwritten notes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t get Buddy-Buddy with Your Superiors&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t Hide an Elephant&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be visible: Practice “WACADAD”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Words are cheap and deeds are dear&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;29&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always take vacations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always Say “Yes” to a Senior Executive Request&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never Surprise Your Boss&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make Your Boss Look Good and Your Boss’s Boss Look Better&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never Let a Good Boss Make a Mistake&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go to the Library one day a month&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add One Big New Thing to Your Life Each Year&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Study These Books&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Obvious Adams, Acres of Diamonds, The Bible, The Art of War, The Book of Five Rings, On War, The Prince, Bartlett&amp;rsquo;s Familiar Quotations, Webster&amp;rsquo;s Third Unabridged Dictionary, The Forbes Book of Business Quotations, The Complete Works of Shakespeare, On Advertising, The Sun Also Rises, The Elements of Style, Huckleberry Finn, Anything by Thomas Jefferson&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of the list above, I&amp;rsquo;ve read the Bible (parts of it consciously, most of it as routine), some works of Shakespeare. E.B. White&amp;rsquo;s Elements of Style is a book that I need to read at some point, also letters by Jefferson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;37&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Dress for a Dance”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overinvest in People&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overpay Your People&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Stop, Look, and Listen”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be a Flag-Waving Company Patriot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find and Fill the “Data Gaps”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Homework, Homework, Homework&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never Panic … or Lose Your Temper&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn to Speak and Write in Plain English&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Treat All People as Special&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be a Credit Maker, Not a Credit Taker&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give Informal Surprise Bonuses&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please, Be Polite with Everyone&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ten Things to Say that Make People Feel Good&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Glory and the Glamour Came after the Grunt work&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tinker, Tailor, Try&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haste Makes Waste&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pour the Coals to a Good Thing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put the Importance on the Bright Idea, Not the Source of the Idea&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay Out of Office Politics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look Sharp and Be Sharp&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emulate, Study, and Cherish the Great Boss&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t Go Over Budget&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never Underestimate an Opponent&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assassinate the Character Assassin with a Single Phrase&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Become a Member of the “Shouldn’t Have Club”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Concept Doesn’t Have to Be Perfect, but the Execution of It Does&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Record and Collect Your Mistakes with Care and Pride&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live for today; Plan for tomorrow; Forget about yesterday&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have fun, laugh&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Treat your family as your number one client&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No Goals, no Glory&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always remember your Subordinate’s Spouses&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the job through the Salespeople’s eyes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be a very tough “Heller Seller”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t be an Empire Builder&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Push Products, Not Paper&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To Teach is to Learn and to Lead&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not get discouraged by idea killers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2018-12-05-how-to-become-ceo/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Blink - The Power of Thinking Without Thinking by Malcom Gladwell</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2016-12-15-blink/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 15:18:21 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2016-12-15-blink/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2016-12-15-blink/ -&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I like the writing style of Malcom Gladwell. With enchanting short real-life stories and fascinating anecdotes, he takes you right into the book, to a different world where you are a student who is observing and studying the behavior of the people in different parts of the world, effortlessly moving to and fro through different periods of time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction---the-statue-that-didnt-look-right&#34;&gt;INTRODUCTION - The Statue That Didn’t Look Right&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fast and Frugal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Internal Computer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Different and Better World&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This chapter tells the story of a kouros that was purchased by Paul Getty museum. The museum authorities had certified it as legitimate after over 2 years of research. But during the opening, some art historians and other experts &amp;lsquo;felt&amp;rsquo; that it was fake by just looking at it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first two seconds of looking — in a single glance — they were able to understand more about the essence of the statue than the team at the Getty was able to understand after fourteen months.
&lt;strong&gt;Blink is a book about those first two seconds&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The chapter lays a foundation for what the book is about and is a very engaging introduction to keep you from putting the book down.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;one---the-theory-of-thin-slices-how-a-little-bit-of-knowledge-goes-a-long-way&#34;&gt;ONE - The Theory of Thin Slices: How a Little Bit of Knowledge Goes a Long Way&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Love Lab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marriage and Morse Code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Importance of Contempt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Secrets of the Bedroom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Listening to Doctors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Power of the Glance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The chapter starts with the story of a couple in their twenties - Bill &amp;amp; Susan - who go to the University of Washington to visit the laboratory of a psychologist named John Gottman. They talk about their dog and Gottman videotapes the conversation for 15 minutes. Gottman and team then assign a SPAFF code to every second of the couple&amp;rsquo;s interaction. [SPAFF code assigns a number to every emotion - Disgust is 1, contempt is 2, anger is 7, defensiveness is 10 .. and so on]. Gottman has proven that he got 95% success of predicting whether a marriage will endure or not by using 1 hour of video and 90% success by 15 minutes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make an accurate prediction about something as serious as the future of a marriage indeed, to make a prediction of any sort — it seems that we would have to gather a lot of information and in as many different contexts as possible.
But John Gottman has proven that we don’t have to do that at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;He goes further to say that of all the emotions in the SPAFF code, he can find out much about a couple by just focusing on what he calls the &amp;ldquo;Four Horsemen&amp;rdquo;: &lt;strong&gt;defensiveness, stonewalling, criticism, and contempt&lt;/strong&gt;. Of these 4, contempt is the most important of them all. Criticism is good in a relationship but contempt is very bad.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;..presence of contempt in a marriage can even predict such things as how many colds a husband or a wife gets; in other words, having someone you love express contempt toward you is so stressful that it begins to affect the functioning of your immune system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Then he talks about doctors who get sued vs who don&amp;rsquo;t and about the research that was done by studying hundreds of recorded conversations between doctors and patients. It is not the doctors with less degrees or qualifications who get sued but mostly the ones that don&amp;rsquo;t talk much to patients.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;He also talks about how some people are able to make judgments with just a glance. Brian Grazer knew that Tom Hanks was a star material at the very first meeting !&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;two---the-locked-door-the-secret-life-of-snap-decisions&#34;&gt;TWO - The Locked Door: The Secret Life of Snap Decisions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Primed for Action&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Storytelling Problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The chapter starts with the story of Vic Braden, a top tennis coach who could predict when a player would make a double fault. Double faults are rare but he could almost always predict them. But he was unable to explain how he was able to do it. Gladwell goes on to say that snap judgements happen so fast that our conscious mind cannot grasp all the infomration that was used in that instant to arrive at the judgement. When we try to break the process down to explain, we fail to express clearly the thought process that went behind.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;He then talks about a priming experiment where when a group of students were &amp;lsquo;primed&amp;rsquo; by telling them a set of words like &amp;ldquo;rude&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;bold&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;disturb&amp;rdquo; ..etc, their behavior was different from another set of students who were primed with different set of pleasant words. Wow! What we listen to matters so much.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Then he talks about the &amp;lsquo;Speed dating&amp;rsquo; experiment done by Iyengar and Fisman from Columbia. When someone said they liked another, the researchers would ask them to explain the reason they cannot. In fact, what the participants said they liked differed from what they actually liked. For e.g, someone said they like people who are intelligent and sincere but they end up choosing someone who is attractive and funny but not particularly sincere or smart at all !&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;He goes on to say that it happens because people are not able to open the locked door - to access the subconscious that made the snap judgement.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;three---the-warren-harding-error-why-we-fall-for-tall-dark-and-handsome-men&#34;&gt;THREE - The Warren Harding Error: Why We Fall For Tall, Dark, and Handsome Men&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Dark Side of Thin Slicing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blink in Black and White&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Taking Care of the Customer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spotting the Sucker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think About Dr. King&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This chapter was a bit of a &amp;lsquo;reality check&amp;rsquo;. Until this point, we are in complete awe of the power of snap judgements, thin slicing ..etc and everything comes crashing down in this chapter. It is like someone saying - &amp;ldquo;listen to your intuition&amp;rdquo; and the moment you are prepared to do that, someone says &amp;ldquo;intuition is bad because we are swayed by our prejudices and what we have been exposed to&amp;rdquo;. The author then gives a series of word associations with European vs African American and Men vs Women. The exercise was interesting.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;He then talks about and extra ordinarily successful salesman named&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;four---paul-van-ripers-big-victory-creating-structure-for-spontaneity&#34;&gt;FOUR - Paul Van Riper’s Big Victory: Creating Structure for Spontaneity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;five---kennas-dilemma-the-right-and-wrongway-to-ask-people-what-they-want&#34;&gt;FIVE - Kenna’s Dilemma: The Right— and Wrong—Way to Ask People What They Want&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;six---seven-seconds-in-the-bronx-the-delicate-art-of-mind-reading&#34;&gt;SIX - Seven Seconds in the Bronx: The Delicate Art of Mind Reading&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion---listening-with-your-eyes-the-lessons-of-blink&#34;&gt;CONCLUSION - Listening with Your Eyes: The Lessons of Blink&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;afterword&#34;&gt;Afterword&lt;/h2&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2016-12-15-blink/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>The One Thing by Gary Keller</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2016-11-26-the-one-thing/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2016 18:17:11 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2016-11-26-the-one-thing/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2016-11-26-the-one-thing/ -&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The ONE Thing: The Surprisingly Simple Truth Behind Extraordinary Result&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by Gary Keller with Jay Papapsan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you chase two rabbits, you will not catch either one.&amp;rdquo; ~ Russian Proverb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the first book that I&amp;rsquo;m reading from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/kindle-dbs/fd/prime-pr/ref=sv_kstore_2&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Prime Reading&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; catalog. I discovered Prime reading accidentally, that too when searching for deals during thanksgiving !! It is a great offering from Amazon. I&amp;rsquo;m amazed. I always felt that kindle/prime lending wasn&amp;rsquo;t that great. You never got the book that you wanted, there were restrictions around one per month..etc. I thought I will stop my prime membership next year since I&amp;rsquo;m not using prime much and haven&amp;rsquo;t had a lot of time to view movies or TV series off late. But due to &amp;ldquo;Prime Reading&amp;rdquo;, I&amp;rsquo;ll continue with prime for a long time, I&amp;rsquo;m sure. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a great collection yet, but I think it will come. Looking forward to a day where I can borrow books from my local library through kindle. I can borrow e-books and read from &amp;lsquo;Overdrive&amp;rsquo; app on my phone but still nothing matches the experience of reading from a kindle.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My impression of reading this book was that it was very inspiring. It is an easy, fast read, one feels like the author is an inspiring preacher who talks to you from a podium and you&amp;rsquo;re listening to him with rapt attention. You would love the idea of focusing on one thing, timeblocking (4 hours !) and other practical steps to make life more streamlined. After reading the book, you walk away with a feeling that you&amp;rsquo;ve gained an insight and will transform your life to follow what was said. Of course, after a few days, you go back to being the old self, being reactive to everything around and multi-tasking and not have time for anything. I think reading the notes again will re-inforce the learning and will slowly change the way you do things.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;highlights-from-my-kindle&#34;&gt;Highlights from my Kindle&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Passion for something leads to disproportionate time practicing or working at it. That time spent eventually translates to skill, and when skill improves, results improve. Better results generally lead to more enjoyment, and more passion and more time is invested. It can be a virtuous cycle all the way to extraordinary results.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Success is about doing the right thing, not about doing everything right.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The trick to success is to choose the right habit and bring just enough discipline to establish it. That’s it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It takes an average of 66 days to acquire a new habit.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The more we use our mind, the less minding power we have.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The problem with living in the middle is that it prevents you from making extraordinary time commitments to anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;To achieve an extraordinary result you must choose what matters most and give it all the time it demands. This requires getting extremely out of balance in relation to all other work issues.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When you act on your priority, you’ll automatically go out of balance, giving more time to one thing over another.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A big opportunity is better than a small one, but a small problem is better than a big one.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The good news is that science isn’t about guessing, but rather the art of progressing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What you build today will either empower or restrict you tomorrow.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Achievement and abundance show up because they’re the natural outcomes of doing the right things with no limits attached.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A journey of a thousand miles must begin with a single step.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Quality of any answer is directly determined by the quality of the question.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Anyone who dreams of an uncommon life eventually discovers there is no choice but to seek an uncommon approach to living it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Your big ONE Thing is your purpose and your small ONE Thing is the priority you take action on to achieve it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Our purpose sets our priority and our priority determines the productivity our actions produce.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Connect today to all your tomorrows.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Putting together a life of extraordinary results simply comes down to getting the most out of what you do, when what you do matters.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The people who achieve extraordinary results don’t achieve them by working more hours. They achieve them by getting more done in the hours they work.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When you say yes to something, it’s imperative that you understand what you’re saying no to.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Actions build on action. Habits build on habit. Success builds on success.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When you’re aiming for success you can’t just skip to the end.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Life worth living might be measured in many ways, but the one way that stands above all others is living a life of no regrets.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Put yourself together, and your world falls into place. When you bring purpose to your life, know your priorities, and achieve high productivity on the priority that matters most every day, your life makes sense and the extraordinary becomes possible. All success in life starts within you.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to review your highlights, you can go here -&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://kindle.amazon.com/your_highlights&#34;&gt;https://kindle.amazon.com/your_highlights&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;chapter-notes&#34;&gt;Chapter Notes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-1--the-one-thing&#34;&gt;Chapter 1 : The ONE Thing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Be like a postage stamp— stick to one thing until you get there.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; ~ Josh Billings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key point in the chapter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.. Finally, out of desperation, I went as small as I could possibly go and asked: &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;What’s the ONE Thing you can do this week such that by doing it everything else would be easier or unnecessary?&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; And the most awesome thing happened. Results went through the roof.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-2--the-domino-effect&#34;&gt;Chapter 2 : The Domino Effect&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Every great change starts like falling dominoes.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; ~ BJ Thornton&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s line up all the &amp;lsquo;ducks in a row&amp;rsquo; is a phrase that my previous manager AH used to use often. It does make sense. When you line up the right things, with one flick, you can start a chain reaction of great things.
Success builds on success. When you see someone who has a lot of knowledge, they learned it over time. When you see someone who has done a lot, they accomplished it over time. The key is &amp;lsquo;over time&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-3--success-leaves-clues&#34;&gt;Chapter 3 : Success Leaves Clues&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;It is those who concentrate on but one thing at a time who advance in this world.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; ~ Og Mandino&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passion for something leads to disproportionate time practicing or working at it. That time spent eventually translates to skill, and when skill improves, results improve. Better results generally lead to more enjoyment, and more passion and more time is invested. It can be a virtuous cycle all the way to extraordinary results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the author says &amp;ldquo;The ONE Thing shows up time and again in the lives of the successful because it’s a fundamental truth.&amp;quot;, I&amp;rsquo;m reminded of the &amp;lsquo;Matthew Effect&amp;rsquo; from &amp;ldquo;Outliers&amp;rdquo; - &amp;lsquo;To one who has, more will be given ..&#39;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-1--the-lies---they-mislead-and-derail-us&#34;&gt;PART 1 : The Lies - They Mislead and Derail Us&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Six Lies Between You and Success:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everything Matters Equally&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multitasking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Disciplined Life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Willpower Is Always on Will-Call&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Balanced Life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Big is Bad&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-4everything-matters-equally&#34;&gt;Chapter 4.	Everything Matters Equally&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Things which matter most must never be at the mercy of things which matter least.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; —Johann Wolfgang von Goethe&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When everything feels important, everything seems equal. We become busy-bodies, fully active but not moving towards success. Busyness rarely takes care of business !!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his seminal book &lt;em&gt;Quality Control Handbook&lt;/em&gt;, Juran adopted Pareto principle of 20/80 to highlight “vital few and trivial many&amp;rdquo;. 20% of things that we do has 80% of impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transform to-do list to &amp;lsquo;success list&amp;rsquo;. Take 20% of the to-do list to make the success list. Take the 20% of that, iteratively you can reach the &amp;lsquo;one&amp;rsquo; most important thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-5multitasking&#34;&gt;Chapter 5.	Multitasking&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;To do two things at once is to do neither.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; —Publilius Syrus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multitasking is a lie. There is a cost to task-switching that most people don&amp;rsquo;t realize they are paying. Distraction undermines results and you can end up doing nothing well. Also it takes a toll on mind and body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-6a-disciplined-life&#34;&gt;Chapter 6.	A Disciplined Life&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;It’s one of the most prevalent myths of our culture: self-discipline.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; —Leo Babauta&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Success is about doing the right thing, not about doing everything right. &amp;lsquo;Selected discipline&amp;rsquo; by channeling the energy to important things is very crucial. It takes an average of 66 days to form a habit. Build one habit at a time and give each habit enough time so that it becomes a routine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-7willpower-is-always-on-will-call&#34;&gt;Chapter 7.	Willpower Is Always on Will-Call&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Odysseus understood how weak willpower actually is when he asked his crew to bind him to the mast while sailing by the seductive Sirens.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; —Patricia Cohen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Willpower is alway on-call is a lie. Like the charge of a battery, it goes down with usage. So it is super important to prioritize the right thing to do when willpower is higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Willpower is important. For e.g., the Marshamallow experiment done by Walter Michel at Stanford in the 60s and 70s where kids were given a marshamallow and were told that they could have that now or if they wait for 15 minutes, they could eat two. Kids who exercised willpower and delayed their gratification were found (on average) to be more successful later in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Willpower gets reduced on usage. Another study done at Stanford by Prof Baba Shiv - where he divided undergrad students into 2 groups and asked them to memorize some numbers. The first group had to memorize 2-digit numbers and the second 7-digit numbers. They had to then walk across a hallway, to another room and tell the numbers to someone. On the way, they were offered 2 foods - chocolate cake or fruit salad. Students who were asked to memorize 7-digit numbers were twice as likely to choose chocolate (unhealthy treat) since they had reduced willpower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Willpower gets reduced if you don&amp;rsquo;t eat. Research shows that people who do not eat make roughly twice as many errors than those who do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When willpower is low, we tend to fallback on default settings or on autopilot. This leads to errors in judgement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many things tax our willpower - Implementing new behaviors, Filtering distractions, Resisting temptation, Suppressing emotion, Restraining aggression, Suppressing impulses, Taking tests, Trying to impress others, Coping with fear, Doing something you don’t enjoy, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most important thing to remember is that when it comes to willpower, timing is crucial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-8a-balanced-life&#34;&gt;Chapter 8.	A Balanced Life&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;The truth is, balance is bunk. It is an unattainable pipe dream&amp;hellip; . The quest for balance between work and life, as we’ve come to think of it, isn’t just a losing proposition; it’s a hurtful, destructive one.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; —Keith H. Hammonds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Balanced life is a lie, a myth. The term itself was coined only in the 1980s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Magic happens at the extremes. To achieve extraordinary results one must choose what matters most and give it all the time it demands. That may be work or life. And then counterbalance later to offset it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about life as two balancing buckets - work life and personal life, each with its own counterbalancing goals and approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-9big-is-bad&#34;&gt;Chapter 9.	Big Is Bad&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;We are kept from our goal, not by obstacles but by a clear path to a lesser goal.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; —Robert Brault&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big is bad is a lie. You should not be afraid of big success and end up sabotaging your own efforts to achieve it. There are a lot of examples of people who went all in and lost everything. And those are used to create fear. So we tend to play it safe.
No one knows the ultimate limit of what we can achieve. So it is better to think big, dream big.
Think big - Act big - Succeed big.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-2--the-truth--the-simple-path-to-productivity&#34;&gt;PART 2 : The Truth – The Simple Path to Productivity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Be careful how you interpret the world; it is like that.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; — Erich Heller&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-10the-focusing-question&#34;&gt;Chapter 10.	The Focusing Question&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;There is an art to clearing away the clutter and focusing on what matters most. It is simple and it is transferable. It just requires the courage to take a different approach.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; — George Anders&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great questions are path to great answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Judge a man by his questions rather than his answers.&amp;rdquo; - Voltaire&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A prudent question is one-half of wisdom.&amp;rdquo; - Sir Francis Bacon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The power to question is the basis of all human progress.&amp;rdquo; - Indira Gandhi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Focusing Question -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;WHAT’S the one thing I can do such that by doing it, everything else will be easier or unnecessary.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-11the-success-habit&#34;&gt;Chapter 11.	The Success Habit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Success is simple. Do what’s right, the right way, at the right time.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; —Arnold H. Glasow&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Focusing Question is the foundational habit to use to achieve great results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Important areas of life&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spiritual Life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Physical Health&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personal Life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Key Relationships&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Job&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Business&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Financial Life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leverage reminders and recruit support to keep your success habit working as powerfully as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-12the-path-to-great-answers&#34;&gt;Chapter 12.	The Path to Great Answers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;People do not decide their futures, they decide their habits and their habits decide their futures.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; —F. M. Alexander&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Four options for framing a Great Question.
Q4. Small &amp;amp; Specific
Q3. Small &amp;amp; Broad
Q2. Big &amp;amp; Broad
Q1. Big &amp;amp; Specific&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you ask a Great Question, you’re in essence pursuing a great goal.
Thinking big and specific is key to a great question. Think Possibilities and benchmark and trend for the best answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-3--extraordinary-results---unlocking-the-possibilities-within-you&#34;&gt;PART 3 : Extraordinary Results - Unlocking the Possibilities Within You&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Even if you’re on the right track, you’ll get run over if you just sit there.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; — Will Rogers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-13live-with-purpose&#34;&gt;Chapter 13.	Live with Purpose&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Life isn’t about finding yourself. Life is about creating yourself.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; —George Bernard Shaw&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gary goes over Scrooge&amp;rsquo;s story to illustrate that &amp;ldquo;our purpose sets our priority and our priority determines the productivity our actions produce&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You cannot seek happiness. It happens in the journey. Discover your big &amp;ldquo;Why&amp;rdquo; and do things that bring purpose to your everyday actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-14live-by-priority&#34;&gt;Chapter 14.	Live by Priority&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Planning is bringing the future into the present so that you can do something about it now.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; —Alan Lakein&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Purpose is very important and has the power to shape our lives only in direct proportion to the power of the priority we connect it to. &lt;strong&gt;Purpose without priority is powerless.&lt;/strong&gt;
Future purpose should connect to current priority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-15live-for-productivity&#34;&gt;Chapter 15.	Live for Productivity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Productivity isn’t about being a workhorse, keeping busy or burning the midnight oil&amp;hellip; . It’s more about priorities, planning, and fiercely protecting your time.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; —Margarita Tartakovsky&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extraordinary results come when you get the most out of what you do.
Time blocking is key for achieving great productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time block 3 things in the following order -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time block your timeoff.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time block your ONE Thing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time block your planningtime.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To experience extraordinary results, be a &amp;lsquo;maker&amp;rsquo; in the morning and a &amp;lsquo;manager&amp;rsquo; in the afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4 proven ways to battle distractions -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build a bunker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Store provisions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sweep for mines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enlist support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-16the-three-commitments&#34;&gt;Chapter 16.	The Three Commitments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Nobody who ever gave his best regretted it.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; —George Halas&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mastery can happen only if you commit to be the best. Take ownership of your outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 3 commitments to your one thing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow the Path of Mastery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move from &amp;ldquo;E&amp;rdquo; (Entrepreneurial) to &amp;ldquo;P&amp;rdquo; (Purposeful).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Live the Accountability Cycle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-17the-four-thieves&#34;&gt;Chapter 17.	The Four Thieves&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Focus is a matter of deciding what things you’re not going to do.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; —John Carmack&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 4 thieves of Productivity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inability to say &amp;ldquo;No&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fear of Chaos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Poor Health Habits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Environment Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Support Your Goals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve personally had issues with 1 and 2. The key thing to remember is &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;When you say yes to something, it’s imperative that you understand what you’re saying no to.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt; Also, make peace with loose ends and clutter!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-18the-journey&#34;&gt;Chapter 18.	The Journey&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;To get through the hardest journey we need take only one step at a time, but we must keep on stepping.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; —Chinese Proverb&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A life worth living might be measured in many ways, but the one way that stands above all others is living a life of no regrets. One step at a time, focusing on the ONE big thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;putting-the-one-thing-to-work&#34;&gt;Putting The ONE Thing to Work&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;In delay there lies no plenty.&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; -William Shakespeare&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key thing to make it work is to develop the habit of asking the &amp;lsquo;Focusing Question&amp;rsquo; and keep it up.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2016-11-26-the-one-thing/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Functional Thinking by Neal Ford</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2016-10-16-functionalthinking/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 09:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2016-10-16-functionalthinking/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2016-10-16-functionalthinking/ -&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For someone who has been doing Java programming and reading through lot of OO codebase for over a decade, functional programming is truly a paradigm shift. It is not like learning a different language or different version of Java from Java 2 (1.2) to Java 8. The first time I was exposed to functional programming is probably around 2012 when I had to do a project for an ML course using R language. It was refreshing to do things differently for sure. Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;http://rovarghe.blogspot.com&#34;&gt;RV&lt;/a&gt;, I learnt the basics of Clojure last year. I&amp;rsquo;m at a stage where I can read Clojure code and understand and may be write very simple programs but not beyond that. Anyway, the paradigm shift that Ford talks about can be summarized in the example that he gives in the first chapter of the book.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s say for a moment that you are a lumberjack. You have the best axe in the forest, which makes you the most productive lumberjack in the camp. Then one day someone shows up and extols the virtues of a new tree-cutting paradigm, the chainsaw. The sales guy is persuasive, so you buy a chainsaw, but you don’t know how it works. Demonstrating your expertise with the previous tree-cutting paradigm, you swing it vigorously at a tree—without cranking it. You quickly conclude that this newfangled chainsaw is a fad, and you return to your axe. Then, someone appears and shows you how to crank the chainsaw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The best thing about the book is that he gives a lot of code examples. So one needs to just think of how to solve these examples and get the gist of what is being talked about.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-1--why&#34;&gt;Chapter 1 : Why&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;OO makes code understandable by encapsulating moving parts. FP makes code under‐ standable by minimizing moving parts.&amp;rdquo; ~ Michael Feathers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This chapter provides a broad overview and shows some examples of the mental shift that the author is teaching us.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 1-1. Word frequencies in Java&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 1-2. Word frequencies in Java 8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 1-3. indexOfAny() from Apache Commons StringUtils
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The IndexofAny() method accepts a String and an array and returns the index of the first occurrence in the String of any of the characters in the array&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 1-4. indexOfAny() example cases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 1-5. Scala version of firstIndexOfAny()&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 1-6. Returning a lazy list of matches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Excercise to self&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write a program in Java 8 or Clojure which takes in a String of words separated by space (&amp;ldquo;a quick brown fox&amp;rdquo;) and returns a map of word frequencies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write a program in Java 8 or Clojure that mimics &amp;lsquo;indexOfAny() from Apache Commons StringUtils&amp;rsquo;. This method accepts a String and an array and returns the index of the first occurrence in the String of any of the characters in the array.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-2--shift&#34;&gt;Chapter 2 : Shift&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Once garbage collection became mainstream, it simultaneously eliminated entire categories of hard-to-debug problems and allowed the runtime to manage a process that is complex and error-prone for developers. Functional programming aims to do the same thing for the algorithms you write, allowing you to work at a higher level of abstraction while freeing the runtime to perform sophisticated optimizations.&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 2-1. Typical company process (in Java)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let’s say that you are given a list of names, some of which consist of a single character, and you are asked to return a comma-delimited string with the single letter names removed, with each name capitalized.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 2-2. Pseudocode for the “company process”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 2-3. Processing functionally in Scala&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 2-4. Java 8 version of the Company Process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 2-5. Processing in Groovy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 2-6. Processing in Clojure
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;One of Clojure’s selling points is that it removes concurrency as a developer concern just as Java removed garbage collection.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 2-7. Improved readability for Clojure via the thread-last macro&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 2-8. Scala processing in parallel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 2-9. Java 8 parallel processing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 2-10. Number classifier in Java
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perfect : Sum of factors = number&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Abundant : Sum of factors &amp;gt; number&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deficient : Sum of factors &amp;lt; number&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Consider aliquotSum where sum of factors doesn&amp;rsquo;t contain the number itself.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 2-11. Slightly more functional number classifier&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 2-12. Number classifier in Java 8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 2-13. Number classifier using the Functional Java framework&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 2-14. Filtering in Java 8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 2-15. Using filtering (called findAll()) in Groovy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 2-16. Number classifier optimized&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 2-17. Groovy optimized factors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 2-18. The (classify ) function in Clojure encapsulates all the behavior within assignments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 2-19. The foldLeft() method from Functional Java&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 2-20. foldLeft() with user-supplied criteria&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The last part of the chapter is a quick overview of &lt;strong&gt;3 key &amp;lsquo;functions&amp;rsquo;&lt;/strong&gt; in functional programming languages - &lt;strong&gt;filter&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;map&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;reduce&lt;/strong&gt;. The author shows code in Scala, Groovy and Clojure.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Excercise to self&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write a progam in Java 8 or Clojure that, given a list of names, some of which consist of a single character, returns a comma-delimited string with the single letter names removed, with each name capitalized.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write a program in Java 8 or Clojure that implements Number Classification. i.e, given a number, the program outputs if the number is perfect, abundant or deficient.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write a program in Clojure that takes in a range of numbers and returns numbers that are divisible by 3.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-3--cede&#34;&gt;Chapter 3 : Cede&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Confession: I never want to work in a non-garbage-collected language again. I paid my dues in languages like C++ for too many years, and I don’t want to surrender the conveniences of modern languages. That’s the story of how software development progresses.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s so great to see this comment in the book! I spent close to a year in 2007 and over a year in 2015-2016 to re-engineer C++ applications into Java. Though the projects were for different companies (ebay and paypal), co-incidentally, both applications were related to payments!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In this chapter, the author shows five ways developers in functional languages can cede control to the language or runtime, freeing themselves to work on more relevant problems.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Iteration to Higher-Order Functions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Closures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Currying and Partial Application
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Currying&lt;/em&gt; describes the conversion of a multiargument function into a chain of single-argument functions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Partial application&lt;/em&gt; describes the conversion of a multiargument function into one that accepts fewer arguments, with values for the elided arguments supplied in advance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recursion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Streams and Work Reordering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 3-1. Simple closure binding in Groovy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 3-2. Executing the closure block&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 3-3. Another closure binding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 3-4. How closures work (in Groovy)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 3-5. makeCounter() in Java&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 3-6. Currying in Groovy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 3-7. Partial application versus currying in Groovy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 3-8. Composing functions in Groovy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 3-9. Clojure’s partial application&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 3-10. Scala’s currying of arguments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 3-11. Partially applying functions in Scala&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 3-12. Using case without match&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 3-13. Differences between map and collect&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 3-14. Defining a partial function in Scala&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 3-15. Alternative definition for answerUnits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 3-16. Defining an incrementer in Scala&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 3-17. Adder and incrementer in Groovy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 3-18. Using partial application to supply implicit values&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 3-19. List traversal using (sometimes hidden) indexes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 3-20. List traversal using recursion
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think of list as head and tail and iterate through it using recursion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 3-21. Imperative filtering with Groovy
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accepts a list and a predicate (a Boolean test) to determine if the item belongs in the list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 3-22. Recursive filtering with Groovy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 3-23. Recursive filtering in Scala&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 3-24. Java 8 version of the company process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A note on Erlang&amp;rsquo;s tail-call optimization.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Given Erlang’s impressive fault-tolerance capabilities, there are likely tail-recursive loops in production that have run for &lt;strong&gt;years&lt;/strong&gt; (!) uninterrupted.&amp;rdquo;
[&lt;code&gt;emphasis and exclamation added by self. &lt;/code&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Excercise to self&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write a closure (function that returns a function) in Clojure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write a function in Clojure that uses partial function. (partial is a function which takes a function f and a fewer-than-required number of arguments and returns a partially applied function that’s invokable when you supply the remaining arguments)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-4--smarter-not-harder&#34;&gt;Chapter 4 : Smarter, Not Harder&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Even if you don’t care about functional languages such as Scala or Clojure, functional programming will enter your life through the langauge(s) you now use as they evolve.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In this chapter Ford discusses two features common in functional languages: memoization (function level caching) and laziness (Lazy evaluation — deferral of expression evaluation for as long as possible).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 4-1. Caching sum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 4-2. Testing nonoptimized speed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 4-3. Caching everything&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 4-4. Memoizing sum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 4-5. Memoizing everything&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 4-6. Inline memoization in Groovy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 4-7. Testing memoized hashing function&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 4-8. Memoization in Clojure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 4-9. Memoization implementation in Scala&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 4-10. Pseudocode illustrating nonstrict evaluation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 4-11. Prime number finder in Java&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 4-12. Prime iterator in Java&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 4-13. Number classifier using the Totally Lazy Java framework&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 4-14. Using lazy lists in Groovy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 4-15. LazyList implementation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 4-16. Pared-down version of perfect-number classifier in Groovy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 4-17. Lazily initialized list of perfect numbers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 4-18. Building a lazy list in Groovy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 4-19. Exercising lazy lists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 4-20. Finding palindromes in Groovy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 4-21. Clojure’s palindromes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 4-22. Scala palindromes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Example 4-23. Lazy fields in Groovy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Excercise to self&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implement caching (using memoization) for Number Classifier built in Chapter 3. Cache factors and sum of factors for each number.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Given an input string, produce the rot 13 version of the string. &amp;quot;hello&amp;quot; -&amp;gt; &amp;quot;uryyb&amp;quot;. Implement memoized version in Clojure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write a Clojure function to find palindromes in a String of words.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-5--evolve&#34;&gt;Chapter 5 : Evolve&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is better to have 100 functions operate on one data structure than 10 functions on 10 data structures.&amp;rdquo; ~ Alan Perlis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2016-10-16-functionalthinking/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Outliers by Malcom Gladwell</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2016-07-10-outliers/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2016-07-10-outliers/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2016-07-10-outliers/ -- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2016-07-10-outliers/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>The Bartimaeus Trilogy by Jonathan Stroud</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2016-05-20-bartimaeus-trilogy/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2016-05-20-bartimaeus-trilogy/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2016-05-20-bartimaeus-trilogy/ -- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2016-05-20-bartimaeus-trilogy/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Reading List</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/reading-list/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/reading-list/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/reading-list/ -&lt;p&gt;Last Updated - &lt;strong&gt;06/06/2020&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;List of books that I have read, started to read, heard a lot about and want to read. I can at least talk one sentence about these books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have written a draft of my &lt;a href=&#34;https://robinsonraju.info/blog/2020-06-06-the-reading-journey/&#34;&gt;Reading Journey&lt;/a&gt; which is a short recollection of what I read when.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;leadershipmanagement&#34;&gt;Leadership/Management&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good to Great: Why Some Companies Make the Leap and Others Don’t&lt;/strong&gt; by Jim Collins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Effective Executive - The Definitive Guide to Getting the Right Things Done&lt;/strong&gt; by Peter F. Drucker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://robinsonraju.info/books/2018-12-05-how-to-become-ceo/&#34;&gt;How to become CEO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by Jeffrey J. Fox&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The One Minute Manager&lt;/strong&gt; by Kenneth Blanchard and Spencer Johnson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dilbert and the Way of the Weasel&lt;/strong&gt; by Scott Adams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Art of War&lt;/strong&gt; by Sun Tzu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t Bring It to Work&lt;/strong&gt; by Sylvia Lafair&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The 21 Irrefutable Laws of Leadership&lt;/strong&gt; by John C. Maxwell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start with Why: How Great Leaders Inspire Everyone to Take Action&lt;/strong&gt; by Simon Sinek&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Ride of a Lifetime&lt;/strong&gt; by Bob Iger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High Output Management&lt;/strong&gt; by Andy Grove&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Hard Thing About Hard Things: Building a Business When There Are No Easy Answers&lt;/strong&gt; by Ben Horowitz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Principles: Life and Work&lt;/strong&gt; by Ray Dalio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lean In: Women, Work, and the Will to Lead&lt;/strong&gt; by Sheryl Sandberg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;self-help&#34;&gt;Self-Help&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://robinsonraju.info/books/2006-12-10-7-habits-highly-effective-people/&#34;&gt;The 7 Habits of Highly Effective People&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by Stephen Covey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://robinsonraju.info/books/2016-11-26-the-one-thing/&#34;&gt;The ONE Thing: The Surprisingly Simple Truth Behind Extraordinary Result&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by Gary Keller&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Four Agreements&lt;/strong&gt; by Don Miguel Ruiz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Atomic Habits&lt;/strong&gt; by James Clear&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rich Dad, Poor Dad&lt;/strong&gt; by Robert Kiyosaki&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to Win Friends and Influence People&lt;/strong&gt; by Dale Carnegie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Think and Grow Rich&lt;/strong&gt; by Napoleon Hill&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Power of Positive Thinking&lt;/strong&gt; by Dr. Norman Vincent Peale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Awaken the Giant Within&lt;/strong&gt; by Tony Robbins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daring Greatly&lt;/strong&gt; by Brené Brown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Indistractible&lt;/strong&gt; by Nir Eyal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As a Man Thinketh&lt;/strong&gt; by James Allen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who Moved My Cheese?&lt;/strong&gt; by Spencer Johnson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t Sweat the Small Stuff&lt;/strong&gt; by Richard Carlson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;philosophy--psychology&#34;&gt;Philosophy / Psychology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meditations&lt;/strong&gt; by Marcus Aurelius&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zen and the Art of Motorcycle Maintenance&lt;/strong&gt; by Robert M. Pirsig&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Republic&lt;/strong&gt; by Plato&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nicomachean Ethics&lt;/strong&gt; by Aristotle,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Essential Epicurus&lt;/strong&gt; by Epicurus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Critique of Pure Reason&lt;/strong&gt; by Emmanuel Kant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Prince&lt;/strong&gt; by Niccolò Machiavelli&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gödel, Escher, Bach: An Eternal Golden Braid&lt;/strong&gt; by Douglas Hofstader&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beyond Good And Evil&lt;/strong&gt; by Friedrich Nietzsche&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Malcolm Gladwell
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Tipping Point, &lt;a href=&#34;https://robinsonraju.info/books/2016-12-15-blink/&#34;&gt;Blink&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://robinsonraju.info/books/2016-07-10-outliers/&#34;&gt;Outliers&lt;/a&gt;, David and Goliath, What the Dog Saw: And Other Adventures&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Selfish Gene&lt;/strong&gt; by Richard Dawkins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12 Rules for Life&lt;/strong&gt; by Jordan Peterson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flow – The Psychology of Optimal Experience&lt;/strong&gt; by Mihaly Csikszentmihalyi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://robinsonraju.info/books/2020-04-28-great-mental-models/&#34;&gt;The Great Mental Models: Volume 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by Shane Parrish&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;biographiesmemoirs&#34;&gt;Biographies/Memoirs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Walter Isaacson
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Steve Jobs, Einstein: His Life and Universe, Leonardo da Vinci, Benjamin Franklin: An American Life&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My Experiments with Truth&lt;/strong&gt; by M.K. Gandhi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Diary of a Young Girl&lt;/strong&gt; by Anne Frank&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Story of My Life&lt;/strong&gt; by Helen Keller&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Man’s Search For Meaning&lt;/strong&gt; by Victor Frankl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Man Who Knew Infinity: A Life of The Genius Ramanujan&lt;/strong&gt; by Robert Kanigel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wings of Fire&lt;/strong&gt; by APJ Abdul Kalam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Playing It My Way&lt;/strong&gt; by Sachin Tendulkar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;John Adams&lt;/strong&gt; by David McCullough&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Surely You’re Joking, Mr. Feynman!&lt;/strong&gt; by Richard P. Feynman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When Breath Becomes Air&lt;/strong&gt; by Paul Kalanithi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hit Refresh&lt;/strong&gt; by Satya Nadella&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sci-fifantasy&#34;&gt;Sci-fi/Fantasy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Lord of the Rings Series&lt;/strong&gt; by JRR Tolkien&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Harry Potter Series&lt;/strong&gt; by JK Rowling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Song of Ice and Fire&lt;/strong&gt; by George RR Martin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Hitchhiker’s Guide to the Galaxy Series&lt;/strong&gt; by Douglas Adams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Foundation Trilogy&lt;/strong&gt; by Isaac Asimov&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I, Robot&lt;/strong&gt; by Isaac Asimov&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2001: A Space Odyssey&lt;/strong&gt; by Arthur C. Clarke&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rendezvous With Rama&lt;/strong&gt; by Arthur C. Clarke&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Twenty Thousand Leagues Under the Sea&lt;/strong&gt; by Jules Verne&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journey to the Center of the Earth&lt;/strong&gt; by Jules Verne&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Dark Tower Series&lt;/strong&gt; by Stephen King&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Chronicles of Narnia&lt;/strong&gt; by CS Lewis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Divergent series&lt;/strong&gt; by Veronica Roth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Hunger Games Series&lt;/strong&gt; by Suzanne Collins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Twilight Series&lt;/strong&gt; by Stephenie Meyer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Wheel of Time Series&lt;/strong&gt; by Robert Jordan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Dark Tower&lt;/strong&gt; by Stephen King&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Time Machine&lt;/strong&gt; by H.G. Wells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dune&lt;/strong&gt; by Frank Herbert&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Martian&lt;/strong&gt; by Andy Weir&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1984&lt;/strong&gt; by George Orwell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fahrenheit 451&lt;/strong&gt; by Ray Bradbury&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brave New World&lt;/strong&gt; by Aldous Huxley&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neuromancer&lt;/strong&gt; by William Gibson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frankenstein&lt;/strong&gt; by Mary  Shelley&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Handmaid&amp;rsquo;s Tale&lt;/strong&gt; by Margaret Atwood&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The War Of The Worlds&lt;/strong&gt; by H.G. Wells&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact&lt;/strong&gt; by Carl Sagan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Time Traveler&amp;rsquo;s Wife&lt;/strong&gt; by Audrey Niffenegger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do Androids Dream Of Electric Sheep?&lt;/strong&gt; by Philip K. Dick&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Snow Crash&lt;/strong&gt; by Neal Stephenson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cryptonomicon&lt;/strong&gt; by Neal Stephenson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://robinsonraju.info/books/2016-05-20-bartimaeus-trilogy&#34;&gt;The Bartimaeus Trilogy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by Jonathan Stroud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leviathan Wakes (The Expanse Series)&lt;/strong&gt; by James S. A. Corey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Outlander Series&lt;/strong&gt; by Diana Gabaldon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Witcher&lt;/strong&gt; by Andrzej Sapkowski&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;His Dark Materials&lt;/strong&gt; by Philip Pullman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;literatureclassics&#34;&gt;Literature/Classics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Charles Dickens
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Great Expectations, A Tale of Two Cities, Oliver Twist, David Copperfield&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thomas Hardy
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Return of the Native, The Mayor of Casterbridge, Far from the Madding Crowd, Tess of the d&amp;rsquo;Urbervilles, Under the Greenwood Tree,A Pair of Blue Eye&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leo Tolstoy
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anna Karenina, War and Peace&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wuthering Heights&lt;/strong&gt; by Emily Bronte&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jane Austen
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pride and Prejudice, Sense and Sensibility, Northanger Abbey, Emma, Mansfield Park, Persuasion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jane Eyre&lt;/strong&gt; by Charlotte Bronte&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fyodor Dostoevsky
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crime and Punishment, Notes from Underground, The Brothers Karamazov&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Iliad&lt;/strong&gt; by Homer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Odyssey&lt;/strong&gt; by Homer (Emily Wilson)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Metamorphosis&lt;/strong&gt; by Franz Kafka&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Count of Monte Cristo&lt;/strong&gt; by Alexander Dumas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Three Musketeers&lt;/strong&gt; by Alexander Dumas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;George Eliot
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Mill on the Floss, Adam Bede, Silas Marner, Middlemarch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Treasure Island&lt;/strong&gt; by Robert Louis Stevenson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Scarlet Letter&lt;/strong&gt; by Nathaniel Hawthorne&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Somerset Maugham
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Of Human Bondage, The Razor&amp;rsquo;s Edge, The Moon and Sixpence&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-fiction&#34;&gt;Other Fiction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hardy Boys series&lt;/strong&gt; by Franklin W. Dixon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Agatha Christie
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Murder on the Orient Express, The Mysterious Affair at Styles, The Secret Adversary, Hercule Poirot&amp;rsquo;s Christmas, The Murder of Roger Ackroyd, The ABC Murders, And Then There Were None, Five Little Pigs, Crooked House, Endless Night, Death on the Nile&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jeffrey Archer
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kane and Abel, Not a Penny More, Not a Penny Less, Shall We Tell the President?, The Prodigal Daughter, First Among Equals, A Matter of Honour, As the Crow Flies, Honour Among Thieves, The Fourth Estate,The Eleventh Commandment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sidney Sheldon
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rage of Angels, Bloodline, If Tomorrow Comes, Nothing Lasts Forever, Windmills of the Gods, The Sands of Time, A Stranger in the Mirror, The Doomsday Conspiracy, Tell Me your dreams, Master of the Game, The Stars Shine Down, The Other Side of Midnight, Memories of Midnight, Morning, Noon and Night, Are you afraid of the Dark&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Robert Ludlum
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Bourne Identity, The Bourne Supremacy, The Bourne Ultimatum, The Holcroft Covenant, The Osterman Weekend, The Scarlatti Inheritance, The Matlock Paper, Trevayne, The Matarese Circle, The Icarus Agenda, The Scorpio Illusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Harold Robbins
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Carpetbaggers, Goodbye Janette, Never Love a Stranger, A Stone for Danny Fisher, The Dream Merchants, Dreams die first, The storyteller, Memories of another day&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alistair MacLean
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Guns of Navarone, Where Eagles Dare, Ice Station Zebra, Caravan to Vaccares&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jack Higgins
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Eagle Has Landed, The Eagle Has Flown, To Catch a King, Night of the Fox, Eye of the Storm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Daphne du Maurier
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rebecca, The House on the Strand, &lt;a href=&#34;https://robinsonraju.info/books/2005-06-11-kings-general-dumaurier/&#34;&gt;The King&amp;rsquo;s General&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://robinsonraju.info/books/2005-06-17-my-cousin-rachel-daphne-du-maurier/&#34;&gt;My Cousin Rachel&lt;/a&gt;, Frenchman&amp;rsquo;s Creek, Jamaica Inn, The Scapegoat&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dan Brown
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Da Vinci Code, Angels and Demons, Inferno, Digital Fortress, Deception Point, Origin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Michael Crichton
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jurassic Park, The Andromeda Strain, Disclosure, Sphere, Congo, Timeline, The Terminal Man, Rising Sun, The Lost World , Westworld&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perry Mason novels&lt;/strong&gt; by Erle Stanley Gardner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;James Patterson
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Along Came a Spider, Kiss the Girls, Pop Goes the Weasel, Gone&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;John Grisham
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Firm, A Time to Kill, The Pelican Brief, The Rainmaker, The Testament, The Street Lawyer, The Runaway Jury, The Client, The Partner, The Last Juror, The Chamber&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Robin Cook
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coma, Outbreak, Contagion, Seizure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nicholas Sparks
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Notebook, Message in a Bottle, A Walk to Remember, Safe Haven,The Rescue, Dear John,The Guardian, Nights in Rodanthe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clive Cussler
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inca Gold, Pacific Vortex, Treasure, Valhalla Rising, Sahara&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paulo Coelho
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Alchemist, Eleven Minutes, Brida, The Winner Stands Alone, By the River Piedra I Sat Down and Wept, The Zahir, The Witch of Portobello&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Kite Runner&lt;/strong&gt; by Khaled Hosseini&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The God of the Small Things&lt;/strong&gt; by Arundhati Roy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Atonement&lt;/strong&gt; by Ian McEwan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://robinsonraju.info/books/of-love-and-other-demons/&#34;&gt;Of Love and Other Demons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; by Gabriel García Márquez&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To Kill a Mockingbird&lt;/strong&gt; by Harper Lee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Great Gatsby&lt;/strong&gt; by F. Scott Fitzgerald&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Catcher in the Rye&lt;/strong&gt; by J. D. Salinger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Old Man and the Sea&lt;/strong&gt; by Ernest Hemingway&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gone With the Wind&lt;/strong&gt; by Margaret Mitchell&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-non-fiction&#34;&gt;Other Non-Fiction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Book of Books - The Great American Read&lt;/strong&gt; by PBS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mrs-Funnybones&lt;/strong&gt; by Twinkle-Khanna&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/reading-list/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>A Simple MapReduce Job for Iris Dataset</title>
        <link>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2015-09-30-mapreducejob-iris/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 22:50:11 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2015-09-30-mapreducejob-iris/</guid>
        <description>Rob&#39;s Notes https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2015-09-30-mapreducejob-iris/ -&lt;p&gt;This blog is an attempt to walk through the process of using hadoop to analyze a dataset that might look similar to an actual dataset that we might encounter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The objective is to read data from Iris dataset - &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.ics.uci.edu/ml/datasets/Iris&#34;&gt;https://archive.ics.uci.edu/ml/datasets/Iris&lt;/a&gt; and calculate the mean sepal length of each class of the flower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data is here -&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.ics.uci.edu/ml/machine-learning-databases/iris/iris.data&#34;&gt;https://archive.ics.uci.edu/ml/machine-learning-databases/iris/iris.data&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sample record : &lt;code&gt;5.1,3.5,1.4,0.2,Iris-setosa&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attribute Information:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sepal length in cm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sepal width in cm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;petal length in cm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;petal width in cm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;class: a) Iris Setosa, b) Iris Versicolour, c) Iris Virginica&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last blog on wordcount, I used an eclipse project that was bundled automatically with the Cloudera VM and just modified the StubMapper, StubReducer and Driver to plugin the code for wordcount. In this, I thought I&amp;rsquo;ll create one from scratch and see how it works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-1--create-a-java-project&#34;&gt;Step #1 : Create a Java project&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a Java project using Eclipse.
Add Mapper, Reducer and Driver stubs from the other project. You&amp;rsquo;ll immediately notice that there are many compilation errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-2-configure-build-path&#34;&gt;Step 2: Configure Build Path&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add the following libraries from &lt;code&gt;/usr/lib/hadoop/client&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;/cloudera/lib&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Properties &amp;gt; Java Build Path &amp;gt; Add External Jars&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also add &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;project&amp;gt;/conf&lt;/code&gt; as the class folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the compilation issues would be resolved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;step-3-add-code-for-mapper-and-reducer&#34;&gt;Step 3: Add code for Mapper and Reducer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The objective is to read the records from the data and compute the mean sepal length of each class of the Iris flower.
map() function in the Mapper gets each row and splits the columns to extract out the key (flower class) and the value (sepal length).
The reduce() function is the Reducer is simple as well. It iterates through the values for each key, computes sum, maintains count and computes mean after the loop ends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mapper&#34;&gt;Mapper&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;package com.iris.data.mapreduce;
import java.io.IOException;

import org.apache.hadoop.io.FloatWritable;
import org.apache.hadoop.io.LongWritable;
import org.apache.hadoop.io.Text;
import org.apache.hadoop.mapreduce.Mapper;

public class IrisMapper extends Mapper&amp;lt;LongWritable, Text, Text, FloatWritable&amp;gt; {

    @Override
    public void map(LongWritable key, Text value, Context context)
            throws IOException, InterruptedException {

        String[] columns = value.toString().split(&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;);
        float sepal_len = Float.valueOf(columns[0]);
        String flower_class = columns[4];

        context.write(new Text(flower_class), new FloatWritable(sepal_len));
    }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;reducer&#34;&gt;Reducer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;package com.iris.data.mapreduce;
import java.io.IOException;

import org.apache.hadoop.io.FloatWritable;
import org.apache.hadoop.io.Text;
import org.apache.hadoop.mapreduce.Reducer;

public class IrisReducer extends
        Reducer&amp;lt;Text, FloatWritable, Text, FloatWritable&amp;gt; {

    @Override
    public void reduce(Text key, Iterable&amp;lt;FloatWritable&amp;gt; values, Context context)
            throws IOException, InterruptedException {

        float sum = 0;
        float count = 0;
        float mean_sepal_len = 0;
        for (FloatWritable val : values) {
            sum += val.get();
            count++;
        }

        mean_sepal_len = sum / count;
        context.write(key, new FloatWritable(mean_sepal_len));
    }

}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;run-the-driver&#34;&gt;Run the Driver&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should see the following output&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Header Image - &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Iris&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; by Pauline Rosenberg via &lt;a href=&#34;https://flic.kr/p/6sZzjm&#34;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://robinsonraju.info/posts/2015-09-30-mapreducejob-iris/ - 2020 Robinson Raju</description>
        </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss> 